<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><records><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Shaheen, M. M. Z.</author><author>Amer, H. H.</author><author>Ali, N. A.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Robust Air-to-Air Channel Model for Swarms of Drones in Search and Rescue Missions</title><secondary-title>IEEE Access</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Access</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Access</abbr-1></periodical><pages>68890-68896</pages><volume>11</volume><keywords><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Air navigation</keyword><keyword>Controllers</keyword><keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword><keyword>Robots</keyword><keyword>Delay</keyword><keyword>Channel modelling</keyword><keyword>Radio transceivers</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Orthogonal frequency division multiplexing</keyword><keyword>Line of Sight</keyword><keyword>Lines-of-sight</keyword><keyword>Errors</keyword><keyword>Signal to noise ratio</keyword><keyword>Actuators</keyword><keyword>Air channels</keyword><keyword>Air to air channel (A2A)</keyword><keyword>air to air channels (A2A)</keyword><keyword>Bit error rate</keyword><keyword>bit error rate (BER)</keyword><keyword>Bit-error rate</keyword><keyword>IEEE 802.11n</keyword><keyword>IEEE 802.11n standard</keyword><keyword>line of sight (LOS)</keyword><keyword>orthogonal frequency division multiplexing (OFDM)</keyword><keyword>Orthogonal frequency-division multiplexing</keyword><keyword>signal to noise ratio (SNR)</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>21693536 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3292517</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Drones have greatly enhanced search and rescue missions. They help improve the response time of the rescue team. They can cover vast challenging terrains quickly. Drones used in rescue missions are expensive. Because of the challenging terrains, if any drone crashes, it cannot be retrieved. This paper presents two contributions. The first contribution is a cruising scheme for a swarm of drones heading to a dangerous area to rescue victims. The proposed scheme guarantees the safety of the drones during the mission. It guarantees that no drone is lost; whenever a drone's controller fails, another drone will guide it home. Basically, each pair of drones should monitor the control system of one another. In case no watchdog signal is sent, an error is perceived and the operational drone begins to control the malfunctioning one (the drone with a failed controller). Every drone sends all its sensor data to the other drone every 1msec. When a fault occurs, the operational drone sends back the control signals to the malfunctioning one to control its actuators. A robust air-to-air communication channel between pairs of drones, is needed in order to realize the proposed navigation scheme and to achieve a safe cruise and a successful mission to every single drone in the whole swarm. Therefore, the second contribution is a channel model for the air-to-air links between pairs of drones. It is assumed that drones' transceivers use the 802.11n protocol. Simulations are conducted to test the proposed channel model in two scenarios. The first one is fault- free and the other one is when one of the controllers in a pair of drones, fails. The separating distance between every two drones in each pair and their relative velocity with respect to one another, differ in both scenarios. The proposed channel is robust as it achieves approximately zero BER in both scenarios.  © 2013 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 1; Correspondence Address: N.A. Ali; Suez Canal University, Giza Engineering Institute, Chinese College for Applied Technology (ECCAT), Giza, 12913, Egypt; email: nora_ahmed@eng.cu.edu.eg</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85164412133&amp;doi=10.1109%2fACCESS.2023.3292517&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=4e548a77fa63ac7b4d8d131a9d6f2bdc</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Tian, B.</author><author>Kaul, H.</author><author>Janardhanan, M.</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Galizia F. G</author><author>Bortolini M</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Towards Self-organized Logistics Planning in Decentralised Production Systems via Agent-Based Modelling</title><secondary-title>Lecture Notes in Mechanical Engineering</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Lect. Notes Mech. Eng.</full-title></periodical><pages>825-832</pages><keywords><keyword>Swarm intelligence</keyword><keyword>Swarm robotics</keyword><keyword>Routings</keyword><keyword>Robot programming</keyword><keyword>Matrix algebra</keyword><keyword>Degrees of freedom (mechanics)</keyword><keyword>Simulation platform</keyword><keyword>Autonomous agents</keyword><keyword>Decentralised control</keyword><keyword>Decentralized control</keyword><keyword>Computational methods</keyword><keyword>Production control</keyword><keyword>Agent-based model</keyword><keyword>Agent-based modelling</keyword><keyword>Assembly systems</keyword><keyword>Decentralized production</keyword><keyword>Flexible products</keyword><keyword>Logistics planning</keyword><keyword>Production system</keyword><keyword>Production systems</keyword><keyword>Self-organised</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Springer Science and Business Media Deutschland GmbH</publisher><isbn>21954356 (ISSN); 978-303134820-4 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/978-3-031-34821-1_90</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The growing number of product variants reduces the utilization of traditional linear assembly systems and increases the cost of customization for manufacturing companies. Matrix-structured Manufacturing Systems (MMS) with freely linked production modules enable efficient use of assembly resources through flexible product routing. However, the high degree of freedom requires greater reliability of the production control system. Traditional centralized production control faces high uncertainty and computational complexity of flexible production. To address these challenges, this study proposes the concept of a decentralized logistics planning system based on agent-based modelling (ABM) and mobile robotic swarms. Decentralization will be achieved by treating robots and workstations as agents that can communicate and interact with each other. The rules of interactions and communications will be tested via ABM and, later, programming the rules into swarming robots to achieve fully autonomous logistics planning. This paper proposes a logistics planning framework with high adaptability and robustness for the matrix assembly system. We offer a hybrid optimisation-simulation algorithmic architecture to industrial practitioners to illustrate the steps and potential benefits of implementing self-organizing logistics planning. This self-organizing system can dynamically adjust logistics planning according to the interactive topology of ABM, which realizes flexible product routing with adaptability to changing production environments. © 2023, The Author(s), under exclusive license to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: M. Janardhanan; School of Engineering, University of Leicester, Leicester, LE1 7RH, United Kingdom; email: mukund.janardhanan@leicester.ac.uk; Conference name: Production Processes and Product Evolution in the Age of Disruption - Proceedings of the 9th Changeable, Agile, Reconfigurable and Virtual Production Conference CARV2023 and the 11th World Mass Customization&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Personalization Conference MCPC2023; Conference date: 20 June 2023 through 23 June 2023; Conference code: 299279&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Lect. Notes Mech. Eng.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Lect. Notes Mech. Eng.</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85172358468&amp;doi=10.1007%2f978-3-031-34821-1_90&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=5ef1ff868f7690e42c8181a98a3d2bc8</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>Lect. Notes Mech. Eng.</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zheng, C.</author><author>Jarecki, A.</author><author>Lee, K.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Integrated system architecture with mixed-reality user interface for virtual-physical hybrid swarm simulations</title><secondary-title>Scientific Reports</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Scientific Reports</full-title><abbr-1>Sci. Rep.</abbr-1></periodical><volume>13</volume><number>1</number><issue>1</issue><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>20452322 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1038/s41598-023-40623-6</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper introduces a hybrid robotic swarm system architecture that combines virtual and physical components and enables human–swarm interaction through mixed reality (MR) devices. The system comprises three main modules: (1) the virtual module, which simulates robotic agents, (2) the physical module, consisting of real robotic agents, and (3) the user interface (UI) module. To facilitate communication between the modules, the UI module connects with the virtual module using Photon Network and with the physical module through the Robot Operating System (ROS) bridge. Additionally, the virtual and physical modules communicate via the ROS bridge. The virtual and physical agents form a hybrid swarm by integrating these three modules. The human–swarm interface based on MR technology enables one or multiple human users to interact with the swarm in various ways. Users can create and assign tasks, monitor real-time swarm status and activities, or control and interact with specific robotic agents. To validate the system-level integration and embedded swarm functions, two experimental demonstrations were conducted: (a) two users playing planner and observer roles, assigning five tasks for the swarm to allocate the tasks autonomously and execute them, and (b) a single user interacting with the hybrid swarm consisting of two physical agents and 170 virtual agents by creating and assigning a task list and then controlling one of the physical robots to complete a target identification mission. © 2023, Springer Nature Limited.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: K. Lee; Engineering Technology &amp; Industrial Distribution, Texas A&amp;M University, College Station, 77845, United States; email: kiju.lee@tamu.edu</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85170160500&amp;doi=10.1038%2fs41598-023-40623-6&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=818a6b0aca8f4f7684fbcb16e129be3a</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hussain, K. F.</author><author>Thangavel, K.</author><author>Gardi, A.</author><author>Sabatini, R.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Autonomous Optical Sensing for Space-Based Space Surveillance</title><secondary-title>IEEE Aerospace Conference Proceedings</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.</full-title></periodical><volume>2023-March</volume><keywords><keyword>Performance</keyword><keyword>Systems architecture</keyword><keyword>Particle swarm optimization (PSO)</keyword><keyword>Object detection</keyword><keyword>Uncertainty analysis</keyword><keyword>Satellite communication systems</keyword><keyword>Satellites</keyword><keyword>Surveillance missions</keyword><keyword>Satellite links</keyword><keyword>Space debris</keyword><keyword>Space surveillance</keyword><keyword>Tracking (position)</keyword><keyword>Traffic signals</keyword><keyword>Debris populations</keyword><keyword>Detectability</keyword><keyword>Distributed satellite system</keyword><keyword>Ground-based observations</keyword><keyword>Optical sensing</keyword><keyword>Space objects</keyword><keyword>Space operations</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><isbn>1095323X (ISSN); 978-166549032-0 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/AERO55745.2023.10115786</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Space debris population has increased dramatically in the past decades posing a threat to the future of space operations. Traditionally, Resident Space Objects (RSO) are tracked and catalogued using ground-based observations. However, Space Based Space Surveillance (SBSS) is a promising technology to complement the ground-based observations as it offers greater performance in terms of detectability, accuracy and weather independency. A Distributed Satellite System (DSS) architecture is proposed for a SBSS mission equipped with dual-use star trackers and inter-satellite communication links to interact and cooperate with each other to accomplish optimized RSO tracking tasks while assumed to simultaneously perform earth observation tasks. This paper focuses on stereovision-based tracking algorithms with higher detectability and tracking accuracy in SBSS tasks in order to identify an optimal tracking solution for Space Domain Awareness (SDA), which could support future Space Traffic Management (STM) operations. Navigation and tracking uncertainties are analyzed in representative conditions to support the optimal selection and processing of individual observations and to determine the actual confidence region around the detected objects. Additionally, Particle Swarm Optimization (PSO) is implemented on-board the satellites to grant the DSS autonomous trajectory planning and Collision Avoidance (CA) manoeuvring capabilities. © 2023 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 2; Conference name: 2023 IEEE Aerospace Conference, AERO 2023; Conference date: 4 March 2023 through 11 March 2023; Conference code: 188722&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85152009437&amp;doi=10.1109%2fAERO55745.2023.10115786&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=14aa57c93bf80d66a72e1126112fc424</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Velazco, J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>INSPIRE-A Connectivity Network for the Solar System</title><secondary-title>IEEE Aerospace Conference Proceedings</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.</full-title></periodical><volume>2023-March</volume><keywords><keyword>Low latency</keyword><keyword>Orbits</keyword><keyword>Optical communication</keyword><keyword>Autonomous swarms</keyword><keyword>Moon</keyword><keyword>Interplanetary flight</keyword><keyword>Interconnected network</keyword><keyword>Network node</keyword><keyword>Internet nodes</keyword><keyword>Interplanetary space</keyword><keyword>Lagrange multipliers</keyword><keyword>Lagrange points</keyword><keyword>Planetary bodies</keyword><keyword>Small spacecrafts</keyword><keyword>Space Internet</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><isbn>1095323X (ISSN); 978-166549032-0 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/AERO55745.2023.10115844</electronic-resource-num><abstract>One of Chascii's specific goals is to provide ubiquitous superfast, low-latency connectivity along the solar system through the deployment of its INterplanetary SPace InteRnEt (INSPIRE) network. INSPIRE seeks to deploy a large number of small spacecraft (smallsats), arranged as autonomous swarms, to create optically interconnected network nodes around planetary bodies and their Lagrange points. It is envisioned that future scientific and commercial space missions along the solar system can use INSPIRE as their low-latency fast-data-rate connectivity provider. Each INSPIRE spacecraft is furnished with a set of fast communications systems. High-speed intra-swarm communications is achieved via omnidirectional optical links. The swarms act as autonomous network nodes that can form large synthetic optical apertures that enable high data rate communications among INSPIRE nodes. We see INSPIRE as the basis for the space internet and we plan to systematically implement this network to provide commercial and reliable connectivity to space users. In this paper we will present the architecture under development for implementing the cislunar INSPIRE. Chascii plans to deploy INSPIRE nodes along low-Earth-orbit and GEO as well as along Earth-Moon Lagrange points 1 and 2 to provide gigabit connectivity to future scientific, military, and commercial missions around the moon. © 2023 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: J. Velazco; Chascii Inc., Pasadena, 465 N Halstead Street, 91107, United States; email: jvelazco@chascii.com; Conference name: 2023 IEEE Aerospace Conference, AERO 2023; Conference date: 4 March 2023 through 11 March 2023; Conference code: 188722&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85160522264&amp;doi=10.1109%2fAERO55745.2023.10115844&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=417189a714c1ec6a85fc4d1b5f059b46</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mendívez Vásquez, B. L.</author><author>Barca, J. C.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Adversarial scenarios for herding UAVs and counter-swarm techniques</title><secondary-title>Robotica</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Robotica</full-title><abbr-1>Robotica</abbr-1></periodical><pages>1436-1451</pages><volume>41</volume><number>5</number><issue>5</issue><keywords><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Unmanned Aerial Vehicle</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Motion planning</keyword><keyword>Quad rotors</keyword><keyword>UAV missions</keyword><keyword>Consensus protocols</keyword><keyword>Land vehicles</keyword><keyword>adversarial control</keyword><keyword>Adversarial control</keyword><keyword>consensus protocol</keyword><keyword>shepherding</keyword><keyword>Shepherding</keyword><keyword>targeted elimination</keyword><keyword>Targeted elimination</keyword><keyword>Urban settings</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>02635747 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1017/S0263574722001801</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The present paper aims to design and simulate an adversarial strategy where a swarm of quadrotor UAVs is herding anti-aircraft land vehicles (AALV) that actively oppose the swarm's objective by potentially taking them down. The main strategy is to block the AALVs' line of sight to their goal zone (AALVs' objective), shifting its trajectory so it reaches a kill zone instead (UAVs' objective). The counter-swarm strategy performed by the AALVs consists of taking down the closest aerial units to the goal zone. As a result, a consensus algorithm is executed by the UAVs in order to assess the communication network and re-group. Consensus is based on the propagation of local observations that converge into a global agreement on a communication graph. Re-grouping is done via positioning around the kill zone vector or preferring an anti-clockwise formation to better close gaps. The adversarial strategy was tested in an empty arena and urban setting, the latter making use of a path-planning procedure that re-routes the AALV trajectory based on its current destination. Simulation results show a maximum UAV mission success rate converging to roughly 80% in the empty arena. When targeted elimination procedures are executed, UAV mission performance drops 5%, making no distinction between re-grouping strategies in the empty arena. The urban setting shows lower performance due to navigation complexity but favors the decision to re-group based on a formation that close gaps rather than positioning around the kill zone vector.  © The Author(s), 2023. Published by Cambridge University Press.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 1; Correspondence Address: B.L. Mendívez Vásquez; Monash University, Melbourne, Australia; email: bruno.mendivezvasquez@monash.edu; CODEN: ROBOD</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85153237053&amp;doi=10.1017%2fS0263574722001801&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=dba1bfe6b7d6e37a1bed119777208ac1</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Duan, T.</author><author>Wang, W.</author><author>Wang, T.</author><author>Huang, M.</author><author>Zhou, X.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Task Planning Method for UAV Swarm Dynamic Reconstruction Based on a Fourth-Order Motif</title><secondary-title>Electronics (Switzerland)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Electronics (Switzerland)</full-title><abbr-1>Electronics (Switzerland)</abbr-1></periodical><volume>12</volume><number>3</number><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>capability cluster</keyword><keyword>capability layer</keyword><keyword>dynamic schedule algorithm</keyword><keyword>flexible network</keyword><keyword>swarm reconstruction</keyword><keyword>UAV swarm architecture</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>20799292 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.3390/electronics12030692</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The primary purpose of task allocation is to build each equipment platform and quickly complete integration planning at the actual combat speed to achieve efficient management of the entire task. In this process, higher requirements are put forward for dynamic, cooperative, and highly adaptive drone colony organization. In this paper, the scheduling problem of hybrid unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) systems is studied under an uncertain environment. First, the system-capability-task organizational structure is defined and quantified, which lays a foundation for dynamic adjustment of the organizational structure in the future. Then, combined with the theory of flexible network and elastic network management, the model is calculated, and the linear transformation function and fuzzy theory are used to stratify and cluster the capability layers. On this basis, four motif structures are introduced for abnormal nodes in the process of dynamic adjustment, and a dynamic group reconstruction algorithm (DRA-M) is established. Finally, the time and communication load indexes are determined, and the alternative strategy is designed for the failure point. The performance of the classical scheduling algorithm is evaluated by benchmarking it under different conditions. The results show that the algorithm has a good dynamic adjustment ability in the event of a UAV swarm emergency, which is a bright light for the future study of highly adaptive UAV cluster organization. © 2023 by the authors.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 1; Correspondence Address: T. Duan; College of Systems Engineering, National University of Defense Technology, Changsha, 410073, China; email: duanting1994@163.com</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85147801017&amp;doi=10.3390%2felectronics12030692&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=1dc339b13705542ec3ac23900afa8aaa</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zhang, R.</author><author>Liu, Z.</author><author>Cao, Z.</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Yan L</author><author>Duan H</author><author>Deng Y</author><author>Yan L</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Multi-UAV Formation Control Under Constraints</title><secondary-title>Lecture Notes in Electrical Engineering</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Lect. Notes Electr. Eng.</full-title></periodical><pages>3480-3494</pages><volume>845 LNEE</volume><keywords><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Aircraft control</keyword><keyword>Multi UAV</keyword><keyword>Control protocols</keyword><keyword>Topology</keyword><keyword>Degrees of freedom (mechanics)</keyword><keyword>Formation control</keyword><keyword>Multiple UAVs</keyword><keyword>Communication delays</keyword><keyword>Formation flight</keyword><keyword>Consistency theory</keyword><keyword>Communication delay</keyword><keyword>Communication switching</keyword><keyword>Constraint</keyword><keyword>Constraints</keyword><keyword>Switching topology</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Springer Science and Business Media Deutschland GmbH</publisher><isbn>18761100 (ISSN); 978-981196612-5 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/978-981-19-6613-2_338</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Multi-UAV formation flight means that multiple UAVs keep flying in a certain formation. The multi-UAV formation has higher reliability and can increase the mission success rate Formation control is the prerequisite for the formation to complete the specified tasks safely and efficiently. Considering the communication interference, network congestion, the article studies the formation model in case of communication delay and switching topology, and then designs the control protocol. Considering the requirements during UAV flight and the features of the motion model, the three degrees of freedom kinematics equation of the UAV is given by using the autopilot model of longitudinal and lateral decoupling. Acceleration, velocity, and angular velocity constraints in all directions are defined according to the requirements of flight performance and maneuverability. The control protocol is adjusted according to the constraints. The results of the simulation show that the improved formation control protocol can quickly converge the UAV formation state to the specified value and maintain the specified formation in the presence of communication delay and switching topology. © 2023, The Author(s), under exclusive license to Springer Nature Singapore Pte Ltd.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: R. Zhang; School of Automation Science and Electrical Engineering, Beihang University, Beijing, 100191, China; email: zrr_leo@163.com; Conference name: International Conference on Guidance, Navigation and Control, ICGNC 2022; Conference date: 5 August 2022 through 7 August 2022; Conference code: 292199&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Lect. Notes Electr. Eng.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Lect. Notes Electr. Eng.</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85151166257&amp;doi=10.1007%2f978-981-19-6613-2_338&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=0cdb1d249b36160c7e4cb834a25a732f</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>Lect. Notes Electr. Eng.</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Huang, W.-C.</author><author>Lin, C.-L.</author><author>Chen, Y.-Y.</author><author>Lai, C.-H.</author><author>Lu, C.-Y.</author><author>Ciou, S.-Y.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>MQLINK: A Scalable and Robust Communication Network for Autonomous Drone Swarms</title><secondary-title>IEEE International Symposium on Industrial Electronics</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Int Symp Ind Electron</full-title></periodical><volume>2023-June</volume><keywords><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>Network architecture</keyword><keyword>Ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>ad-hoc network</keyword><keyword>Ad-hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Aircraft control</keyword><keyword>communication</keyword><keyword>Communication problems</keyword><keyword>Communications networks</keyword><keyword>Coordination problems</keyword><keyword>Disaster prevention</keyword><keyword>Distributed control</keyword><keyword>Distributed parameter control systems</keyword><keyword>Distributed-control</keyword><keyword>Edge AI</keyword><keyword>Robot sensing system</keyword><keyword>Robot sensing systems</keyword><keyword>Robust communication</keyword><keyword>Scalable communication</keyword><keyword>Swarm intelligence</keyword><keyword>UAV swarm</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>979-835039971-4 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ISIE51358.2023.10228080</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper presents a novel drone network architecture, MQLINK, for autonomous drone swarms, addressing communication, coordination, and scalability problems. The proposed system utilizes a lightweight, efficient MQTT protocol and incorporates a self-developed UAVLINK module to ensure robust communication in various scenarios, including emergencies and infrastructure failures. The effectiveness of MQLINK in leader-follower formation and proximity detection is demonstrated through real-world experiments on the prototypes. This work advances drone swarm technology, offering a practical solution for enhancing mission efficiency, completion rate, group complementarity, and system flexibility in various applications such as performance, surveying, logistics, inspection, and disaster relief.  © 2023 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: W.-C. Huang; National Chung Hsing University, Department of Electrical Engineering, Taichung, Taiwan; email: g110064030@smail.nchu.edu.tw; C.-L. Lin; National Chung Hsing University, Department of Electrical Engineering, Taichung, Taiwan; email: chunlin@dragon.nchu.edu.tw; Conference name: 32nd IEEE International Symposium on Industrial Electronics, ISIE 2023; Conference date: 19 June 2023 through 21 June 2023; Conference code: 192344; CODEN: 85PTA&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Int Symp Ind Electron&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Int Symp Ind Electron</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85172129216&amp;doi=10.1109%2fISIE51358.2023.10228080&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=16027804a4ca4999e404be0046513962</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>IEEE Int Symp Ind Electron</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Islam, S.</author><author>Badsha, S.</author><author>Khalil, I.</author><author>Atiquzzaman, M.</author><author>Konstantinou, C.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Triggerless Backdoor Attack and Defense Mechanism for Intelligent Task Offloading in Multi-UAV Systems</title><secondary-title>IEEE Internet of Things Journal</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Internet of Things Journal</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Internet Things J.</abbr-1></periodical><pages>5719-5732</pages><volume>10</volume><number>7</number><issue>7</issue><keywords><keyword>Computer architecture</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Deep learning</keyword><keyword>Backdoor attack</keyword><keyword>Backdoors</keyword><keyword>Cloud-computing</keyword><keyword>computation offloading</keyword><keyword>Computation offloading</keyword><keyword>Computational modelling</keyword><keyword>Data privacy</keyword><keyword>Deforestation</keyword><keyword>edge computing</keyword><keyword>Edge computing</keyword><keyword>Intelligent systems</keyword><keyword>Multi UAV</keyword><keyword>Multi-UAV system</keyword><keyword>multiunmanned aerial vehicle (MUAV) system</keyword><keyword>Network security</keyword><keyword>Reinforcement learning</keyword><keyword>Resource drain</keyword><keyword>resource drain-out</keyword><keyword>Resource drain-out.</keyword><keyword>Task analysis</keyword><keyword>UAV systems</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>23274662 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/JIOT.2022.3172936</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In recent years, multiunmanned aerial vehicular systems (MUAVs) have become prevalent in divergent applications: agriculture, spectrum utilization, transportation, forest fire monitoring, and among others, due to their flexible, robust, and autonomous operational maneuver. Battery-powered multiunmanned aerial vehicles (MUAVs) systems possess limited computation and communication resources, significantly reducing their functional dimension by limiting mission time and range. To address this issue, we propose a federated deep reinforcement learning (FDRL)-based intelligent and decentralized task offloading scheme for resource-constrained UAVs that can enhance the operational capability of the MUAV systems. Moreover, the proposed FDRL scheme can improve offloading policy quality while preserving data privacy in MUAV. However, such intelligent systems may fall prey to backdoor attacks that can intervene in the system's regular operation causing rapid degradation of its performance. We introduce a novel triggerless backdoor attack scheme on intelligent task offloading UAVs and analyze its impact to gauge the resiliency of the offloading policy in the presence of an adversary. Then, we propose lightweight agnostic defense mechanisms to combat such backdoors in multi-UAV settings. The extensive simulation results show that the proposed attack and defense strategies are practical and efficient.  © 2014 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 6; Correspondence Address: S. Badsha; Bosch Engineering-North America, Department of IoT Systems Engineering, Farmington Hills, 48331, United States; email: shahriar.badsha@us.bosch.com</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85132533980&amp;doi=10.1109%2fJIOT.2022.3172936&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=18471c4bee2199e01d85affad60a6821</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Lv, C.</author><author>Yu, R.</author><author>Cao, J.</author><author>Gong, C.</author><author>Wu, W.</author><author>Wang, X.</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Yan L</author><author>Duan H</author><author>Deng Y</author><author>Yan L</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>A Survey on Unmanned Aerial Vehicle Swarm Communication and Navigation</title><secondary-title>Lecture Notes in Electrical Engineering</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Lect. Notes Electr. Eng.</full-title></periodical><pages>2386-2393</pages><volume>845 LNEE</volume><keywords><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Military vehicles</keyword><keyword>Low-costs</keyword><keyword>Network architecture</keyword><keyword>Ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Ad-hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Air navigation</keyword><keyword>Vehicle to vehicle communications</keyword><keyword>Wireless communications</keyword><keyword>Ad-hoc network</keyword><keyword>Autonomous navigation</keyword><keyword>Broad application</keyword><keyword>Communicationtechnology</keyword><keyword>Navigation technology</keyword><keyword>Quick response</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle swarm</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle swarms</keyword><keyword>Wireless communication</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Springer Science and Business Media Deutschland GmbH</publisher><isbn>18761100 (ISSN); 978-981196612-5 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/978-981-19-6613-2_232</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Due to the advantages of quick response, low cost, and flexible deployment, unmanned aerial vehicle swarms have broad application prospects in the military and civilian fields. Compared with single aircraft, the swarms have the advantages of robustness, scalability and information interaction. The safety of unmanned aerial vehicle swarms is crucial to perform the flight mission successfully for the system. When performing tasks, communication and navigation technologies provide basic guarantees for cluster collaboration. This paper introduces the research status and development trend of unmanned aerial vehicle swarm communication and navigation technology. Two typical unmanned aerial vehicle swarm wireless communication architectures are introduced. Most systems still utilizes ground stations to control unmanned aerial vehicle swarms directly, called infrastructure-based swarm architecture. On the contrary, this paper mainly introduces swarm architecture based on Ad-hoc network, and points out its development direction. As satellite navigation signal easily suffer from interference, several new autonomous navigation technologies which do not rely on satellite navigation are introduced, including bionic navigation, visual-inertial integrated navigation, and cooperative navigation. © 2023, The Author(s), under exclusive license to Springer Nature Singapore Pte Ltd.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: R. Yu; College of Intelligence Science and Technology, National University of Defense Technology, Changsha, 410073, China; email: yuruihang@nudt.edu.cn; Conference name: International Conference on Guidance, Navigation and Control, ICGNC 2022; Conference date: 5 August 2022 through 7 August 2022; Conference code: 292199&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Lect. Notes Electr. Eng.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Lect. Notes Electr. Eng.</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85151128158&amp;doi=10.1007%2f978-981-19-6613-2_232&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=4da6896dec001741f3544b6ce4add567</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>Lect. Notes Electr. Eng.</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wang, F.</author><author>Huang, J.</author><author>Low, K. H.</author><author>Hu, T.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Collective Navigation of Aerial Vehicle Swarms: A Flocking Inspired Approach</title><secondary-title>IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Vehicles</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Vehicles</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Trans. Intell. Veh.</abbr-1></periodical><pages>1-14</pages><keywords><keyword>Visualization</keyword><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Navigation</keyword><keyword>Intelligent systems</keyword><keyword>Intelligent vehicle highway systems</keyword><keyword>Behavioral research</keyword><keyword>Air navigation</keyword><keyword>Economic and social effects</keyword><keyword>Intelligent robots</keyword><keyword>Behavioral science</keyword><keyword>Robustness (control systems)</keyword><keyword>Intelligent vehicles</keyword><keyword>Birds</keyword><keyword>Aerial vehicle swarm</keyword><keyword>Behavioral sciences</keyword><keyword>Biological system modeling</keyword><keyword>Biological systems</keyword><keyword>Bionic visual projection field</keyword><keyword>bionic visual projection field (VPF)</keyword><keyword>collective behaviors</keyword><keyword>Collective behaviour</keyword><keyword>collective navigation</keyword><keyword>Collective navigation</keyword><keyword>flocking inspired approach</keyword><keyword>Flocking inspired approach</keyword><keyword>Projection fields</keyword><keyword>Robustness</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>23798858 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/TIV.2023.3271667</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Collective navigation is inspired by natural migratory species traveling long distances and conserving their group behavior in the whole journey. With the technological development of autonomous intelligent systems, collective navigation has been an important application in the field of intelligent vehicles. However, many of the existing collective behavior approaches rely on communication exchanges between individuals and focus on the emergence of collective motion, which limits the application in specific mission scenarios and lacks robustness against interference. To address these challenges, this paper proposes a novel flocking-inspired approach of collective navigation for aerial vehicle swarms flying synchronously to the desired region. Firstly, flocking without communication is achieved based on bionic visual projection field (VPF), ensuring the normal operation of the swarm in communication-denied unknown environments. Secondly, each aerial entity is assigned a hidden identity as informed or uninformed, but only the informed agents are allocated information about the migration destination. Under such an architecture, the trade-off between informed and uninformed individuals in the group enables few-to-many control and fast navigation. Finally, simulation and experiments are both conducted within multiple scenarios, in terms of adaptability to different environments, swarm scalability, and robustness to vehicle failures. Results validate the effectiveness of the developed bio-inspired collective navigation algorithm. IEEE</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85159824274&amp;doi=10.1109%2fTIV.2023.3271667&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=bbada384bcaf508d651b3ff4d39ce661</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Gul, F.</author><author>Mir, I.</author><author>Mir, S.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Aquila Optimizer with parallel computing strategy for efficient environment exploration</title><secondary-title>Journal of Ambient Intelligence and Humanized Computing</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Ambient Intelligence and Humanized Computing</full-title><abbr-1>J. Ambient Intell. Humanized Comput.</abbr-1></periodical><pages>4175-4190</pages><volume>14</volume><number>4</number><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>Optimization</keyword><keyword>Motion planning</keyword><keyword>Path planning</keyword><keyword>Robot programming</keyword><keyword>Optimizers</keyword><keyword>Industrial robots</keyword><keyword>Multipurpose robots</keyword><keyword>Multirobots</keyword><keyword>Optimization algorithms</keyword><keyword>Space explorations</keyword><keyword>Space research</keyword><keyword>Heuristic</keyword><keyword>Aquila optimizer</keyword><keyword>Aquila Optimizer</keyword><keyword>CME</keyword><keyword>Coordinated multi-robot exploration</keyword><keyword>Deterministics</keyword><keyword>Multi-robot exploration</keyword><keyword>Parallel com- puting</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>18685137 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/s12652-023-04515-x</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper introduces Aquila Optimization Algorithm specifically configured for Multi-Robot space exploration that can be utilized for a wide range of operations. The proposed strategy incorporates a novel parallel communication protocol, to improve multi-robot space exploration process while minimizing the computation complexity. This ensures acquisition of a collision-free optimal motion in a barrier-filled environment via generating a finite explored map. The framework is a unique combination of both deterministic Coordinated Multi-robot Exploration (CME) and a swarm based methodology, known as Aquila Optimizer (AO). Combinely known as Coordinated Multi-robot Exploration Aquila Optimizer (CME-AO). The architecture starts by determining the cost and utility values of neighbouring cells around the robot using deterministic CME. Aquila Optimization technique is then incorporated to increase the overall solution accuracy. Numerous simulations under different environmental conditions were then performed to validate the effectiveness of the proposed CME-AO algorithm. A perspective analysis was then performed by comparing the performance of the CME-AO algorithm with latest contemporary algorithms namely conventional CME, CME Arithmetic Optimization Algorithm (CME-AOA) and Frequency Modified Hybrid-whale Optimization Algorithm (FMH-WOA). The comparison duly accommodates all pertinent aspects such as % area explored, number of failed runs, and time taken for map exploration for different environments. A statistical comparison with both CME and CME-AOA is then carried out by performing multiple simulations under different environmental configurations. The mean and standard deviation of the (%) area explored and total time taken are then calculated. Results indicate that the proposed algorithm presents distinct advantages of enhanced map exploration in a considerably lesser execution time with almost no fail runs. © 2023, The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 3; Correspondence Address: I. Mir; Department of Avionics Engineering, Air University, Aerospace and Aviation, Islamabad, Campus Kamra, Pakistan; email: imir@cae.nust.edu.pk</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85148097745&amp;doi=10.1007%2fs12652-023-04515-x&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=0df6e199be79aade1a899cde6ac395b6</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Miya, T.</author><author>Ohshima, K.</author><author>Kitaguchi, Y.</author><author>Yamaoka, K.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Adaptive GW Relocation and Strategic Flow Rerouting for Heterogeneous Drone Swarms</title><secondary-title>IEICE Transactions on Communications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEICE Transactions on Communications</full-title><abbr-1>IEICE Trans Commun</abbr-1></periodical><pages>331-351</pages><volume>E106B</volume><number>4</number><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>Optimisations</keyword><keyword>Ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Ad-hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Swarm intelligence</keyword><keyword>ad hoc network</keyword><keyword>Communication-aware</keyword><keyword>communication-aware optimization</keyword><keyword>Communication-aware optimization</keyword><keyword>drone swarm</keyword><keyword>Drone swarm</keyword><keyword>dynamic relocation</keyword><keyword>Dynamic relocation</keyword><keyword>Gateways (computer networks)</keyword><keyword>Multiple swarms</keyword><keyword>Optimizers</keyword><keyword>Protocol translator</keyword><keyword>Robotics architecture</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>09168516 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1587/transcom.2022EBP3091</electronic-resource-num><abstract>A drone swarm is a robotic architecture having multiple drones cooperate to accomplish a mission. Nowadays, heterogeneous drone swarms, in which a small number of gateway drones (GWs) act as protocol translators to enable the mixing of multiple swarms that use independent wireless protocols, have attracted much attention from many researchers. Our previous work proposed Path Optimizer — a method to minimize the number of end-to-end path-hops in a remote video monitoring system using heterogeneous drone swarms by autonomously relocating GWs to create a shortcut in the network for each communication request. However, Path Optimizer has limitations in improving communication quality when more video sessions than the number of GWs are requested simultaneously. Path Coordinator, which we propose in this paper, achieves a uniform reduction in end-to-end hops and maximizes the allowable hop satisfaction rate regardless of the number of sessions by introducing the cooperative and synchronous relocation of all GWs. Path Coordinator consists of two phases: first, physical optimization is performed by geographically relocating all GWs (relocation phase), and then logical optimization is achieved by modifying the relaying GWs of each video flow (rerouting phase). Computer simulations reveal that Path Coordinator adapts to various environments and performs as well as we expected. Furthermore, its performance is comparable to the upper limits possible with brute-force search. Copyright © 2023 The Institute of Electronics, Information and Communication Engineers.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; CODEN: ITRCE</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85153886892&amp;doi=10.1587%2ftranscom.2022EBP3091&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=aa6121f8c49b731a9beff94b8c5c8733</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hatata, A. Y.</author><author>Hasan, E. O.</author><author>Alghassab, M. A.</author><author>Sedhom, B. E.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Centralized Control Method for Voltage Coordination Challenges With OLTC and D-STATCOM in Smart Distribution Networks Based IoT Communication Protocol</title><secondary-title>IEEE Access</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Access</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Access</abbr-1></periodical><pages>11903-11922</pages><volume>11</volume><keywords><keyword>Controllers</keyword><keyword>Internet of things</keyword><keyword>Transformer</keyword><keyword>Particle swarm optimization (PSO)</keyword><keyword>Internet of Things</keyword><keyword>Stochastic systems</keyword><keyword>Uncertainty</keyword><keyword>Communications protocols</keyword><keyword>Multiobjective optimization</keyword><keyword>Renewable energy resources</keyword><keyword>System stability</keyword><keyword>Wind turbines</keyword><keyword>Automatic voltage control</keyword><keyword>D-STATCOM</keyword><keyword>distribution network</keyword><keyword>Distribution static compensator</keyword><keyword>Electric current regulators</keyword><keyword>Electric loads</keyword><keyword>Electric power distribution</keyword><keyword>Electric power system control</keyword><keyword>Load tap changer</keyword><keyword>on-load tap changer</keyword><keyword>Onload tap changer</keyword><keyword>Power systems stability</keyword><keyword>Smart distribution networks</keyword><keyword>Static synchronous compensators</keyword><keyword>Voltage control</keyword><keyword>voltage coordination</keyword><keyword>Voltage coordination</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>21693536 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3242236</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper proposes a coordination method for the voltage control devices based on optimal settings of the D-STATCOMs, on the load tap changer (OLTC) transformer and the distributed generations (DGs)-based renewable energy resources (RERs). The central controller is introduced to handle the active smart distribution network (SDN) problems to maintain the voltage profile within its permissible limits, minimize power losses in different operating conditions, and minimize the energy wastage from the distributed renewable energy resources. These problems are formulated as a multi-objective optimization problem. With increasing load demand and RERs in the distribution system, voltage coordination threatens real-time efficiency. In this research work, central controller-based Gorilla Troops optimization (GTO) algorithm is proposed to detect the optimum solutions for the voltage coordination problem. The load demand uncertainty and the stochastic nature of power generated from RERs (PV panels and wind turbines) are considered in the voltage coordination problem due to their significant effects on the operation and planning of the SDN. The proposed SDN has been represented based on the Internet of Things (IoT) communication protocol. It enhances the data and information transfer between the system-connected agents. A practical test system, NDEDC-24 bus radial distribution network from the North Delta Electrical Distribution Company and IEEE-33 node system are used to test and evaluate the proposed method. The results are compared with other well-known evolutionary methods. The proposed method obtains more accurate results than the other methods.  © 2013 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 2; Correspondence Address: B.E. Sedhom; Mansoura University, El-Mansoura, Faculty of Engineering, Electrical Engineering Department, Mansoura, 35516, Egypt; email: eng_bishoy90@mans.edu.eg</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85148457256&amp;doi=10.1109%2fACCESS.2023.3242236&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=d6fb3c39d323487c3e64d901bc4fba8f</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bartolini, N.</author><author>Coletta, A.</author><author>Giorgi, F.</author><author>Maselli, G.</author><author>Prata, M.</author><author>Silvestri, D.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Stop &amp; Offload: Periodic data offloading in UAV networks</title><secondary-title>Computer Communications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Computer Communications</full-title><abbr-1>Comput Commun</abbr-1></periodical><pages>239-250</pages><volume>212</volume><keywords><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Harsh environment</keyword><keyword>Ad-hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Vehicle to vehicle communications</keyword><keyword>5G mobile communication systems</keyword><keyword>UAVs</keyword><keyword>Mobile communications</keyword><keyword>Vehicle network</keyword><keyword>Vehicular ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Key technologies</keyword><keyword>Internet protocols</keyword><keyword>Routing protocols</keyword><keyword>Ad-hoc Networks</keyword><keyword>Control channels</keyword><keyword>Dynamic network topology</keyword><keyword>Fast mobility</keyword><keyword>Mobile Communication</keyword><keyword>Mobile networks</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>01403664 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.comcom.2023.10.003</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Swarms of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) are a key technology to support communication in many harsh environments where fixed infrastructures (e.g., 5G) are disrupted or not available. However, the fast mobility and highly dynamic network topology pose unique challenges and require the development of novel multi-hop routing protocols. Previous work in this direction extends geographical protocols or adapts approaches designed for Mobile Ad-hoc NETworks (MANETs), rarely taking full advantage of UAV capabilities. In this paper, we introduce a novel data offloading approach, namely Stop &amp; Offload, that exploits the device controllable mobility to facilitate network routing. The swarm of UAVs performs data offloading synchronously and recurrently. At fixed intervals of time, the swarm interrupts the sensing mission (Stop) and moves, as little as possible, to build a connected formation to the base station and offload the data (Offload). We provide both centralized solutions — assuming a long-range control channel — and a distributed solution — working in the absence of a control channel. By means of extensive simulations we show that our proposals outperform state-of-the-art solutions, decreasing the time taken to build a connected formation of about 45% and increasing the time spent on sensing of 10%. Additionally, we compared our protocol with various routing strategies and observe remarkable improvements, including a 50% reduction in average packet delay. © 2023 The Author(s)</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: N. Bartolini; Computer Science Department, Sapienza University of Rome, Rome, Italy; email: bartolini@di.uniroma1.it; CODEN: COCOD</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85174346707&amp;doi=10.1016%2fj.comcom.2023.10.003&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=a7464f6029fb9c077cded26eaf6e8231</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Varun Kumar, K. A.</author><author>Priyadarshini, R.</author><author>Kathik, P. C.</author><author>Madhan, E. S.</author><author>Sonya, A.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Self-co-ordination algorithm (SCA) for multi-UAV systems using fair scheduling queue</title><secondary-title>Sensor Review</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Sensor Review</full-title><abbr-1>Sens. Rev.</abbr-1></periodical><pages>233-242</pages><volume>43</volume><number>4</number><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Real time systems</keyword><keyword>Internet of things</keyword><keyword>Access control</keyword><keyword>Data transfer</keyword><keyword>Digital storage</keyword><keyword>Drone</keyword><keyword>Drone network</keyword><keyword>Energy utilization</keyword><keyword>Fair queue</keyword><keyword>Fair queue scheduling</keyword><keyword>Fair scheduling algorithm</keyword><keyword>Queue scheduling</keyword><keyword>Queueing theory</keyword><keyword>Scheduling</keyword><keyword>Scheduling algorithms</keyword><keyword>Self-organising</keyword><keyword>Self-organizing network</keyword><keyword>Sensor networks</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle systems</keyword><keyword>Virtual reality</keyword><keyword>Weighted fair queuing</keyword><keyword>Weighted fair queuing scheduling</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>SEP 1 2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>0260-2288, 1758-6828</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1108/SR-01-2022-0003</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Purpose: Data traffic through wireless communication is significantly increasing, resulting in the frequency of streaming applications as various formats and the evolution of the Internet of Things (IoT), such as virtual reality, edge device based transportation and surveillance systems. Growth in kind of applications resulted in increasing the scope of wireless communication and allocating a spectrum, as well as methods to decrease the intervention between nearby-located wireless links functioning on the same spectrum bands and hence to proliferation for the spectral efficiency. Recent advancement in drone technology has evolved quickly leading on board sensors with increased energy, storage, communication and processing capabilities. In future, the drone sensor networks will be more common and energy utilization will play a crucial role to maintain a fully functional network for the longest period of time. Envisioning the aerial drone network, this study proposes a robust high level design of algorithms for the drones (group coordination). The proposed design is validated with two algorithms using multiple drones consisting of various on-board sensors. In addition, this paper also discusses the challenges involved in designing solutions. The result obtained through proposed method outperforms the traditional techniques with the transfer rate of more than 3 MB for data transfer in the drone with coordination Design/methodology/approach: Fair Scheduling Algorithm (FSA) using a queue is a distributed slot assignment algorithm. The FSA executes in rounds. The duration of each round is dynamic based upon the delay in the network. FSA prevents the collision by ensuring that none of the neighboring node gets the same slot. Nodes (Arivudainambi et al., 2019) which are separated by two or more hopes can get assigned in the same slot, thereby preventing the collision. To achieve fairness at the scheduling level, the FSA maintains four different states for each node as IDLE, REQUEST, GRANT and RELEASE. Findings: A multi-unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) system can operate in both centralized and decentralized manner. In a centralized system, the ground control system will take care of drone data collection, decisions on navigation, task updation, etc. In a decentralized system, the UAVs are unambiguously collaborating on various levels as mentioned in the centralized system to achieve the goal which is represented in Figure 2. Research limitations/implications: However, the multi-UAVs are context aware in situations such as environmental observation, UAV–UAV communication and decision-making. Independent of whether operation is centralized or decentralized, this study relates the goals of the multi-UAVs are sensing, communication and coordination among other UAVs, etc. Figure 3 shows overall system architecture. Practical implications: The individual events attempts in the UAV’s execution are required to complete the mission in superlative manner which affects in every multi UAV system. This multi UAV systems need to take a steady resolute on what way UAV has to travel and what they need to complete to face the critical situations in changing of environments with the uncertain information. This coordination algorithm has certain dimensions including events that they needs to resolute on, the information that they used to make a resolution, the resolute making algorithm, the degree of decentralization. In multi UAV systems, the coordinated events ranges from lower motion level. Originality/value: This study has proposed a novel self-organizing coordination algorithm for multi-UAV systems. Further, the experimental results also confirm that is robust to form network at ease. The testbed for this simulation to sensing, communication, evaluation and networking. The algorithm coordination has to testbed with multi UAVs systems. The two scheduling techniques has been used to transfer the packets using done network. The self-organizing algorithm (SOA) with fair scheduling queue outperforms the weighted queue scheduling in the transfer rate with less loss and time lag. The results obtained through from Figure 10 clearly indicates that the fair queue scheduling with SOA have several advantages over weighted fair queue in different parameters. © 2022, Emerald Publishing Limited.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 1; Correspondence Address: K.A. Varun Kumar; Department of Networking and Communications, School of Computing, SRM Institute of Science and Technology, Kattankulathur, India; email: varun.kumar300@gmail.com; CODEN: SNRVD</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85137723302&amp;doi=10.1108%2fSR-01-2022-0003&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=4b081b99f9ec52764d6acbbe556014b4</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Yang, X.</author><author>Wang, L.</author><author>Xu, L.</author><author>Zhang, Y.</author><author>Fei, A.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Boids Swarm-based UAV Networking and Adaptive Routing Schemes for Emergency Communication</title><secondary-title>IEEE INFOCOM 2023 - Conference on Computer Communications Workshops, INFOCOM WKSHPS 2023</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE INFOCOM - Conf. Comput. Commun. Workshops, INFOCOM WKSHPS</full-title></periodical><keywords><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Aircraft control</keyword><keyword>UAV swarm</keyword><keyword>Biomimetics</keyword><keyword>Vehicle to vehicle communications</keyword><keyword>Emergency communication</keyword><keyword>Emergency services</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle swarm</keyword><keyword>Vehicle network</keyword><keyword>Power management (telecommunication)</keyword><keyword>Routing protocols</keyword><keyword>Location awareness</keyword><keyword>Routing-protocol</keyword><keyword>Adaptive routing</keyword><keyword>emergency communication</keyword><keyword>location awareness</keyword><keyword>mobility control</keyword><keyword>Mobility control</keyword><keyword>routing protocol</keyword><keyword>Routing scheme</keyword><keyword>Swarm mobilities</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-166549427-4 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/INFOCOMWKSHPS57453.2023.10225900</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Communications in disaster scenarios face critical challenges because of damage to ground communication facilities. A promising solution for emergency response is establishing self-organizing networks with flexible unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) swarms to provide a communication guarantee for rescue mission execution. However, the server environment of the disaster area and the highly dynamic characteristic of UAV networks place strict requirements on swarm mobility control and data transmission. To this end, this work proposes a Boids mobility model-based adaptive routing scheme to achieve efficient UAV swarm networking. Specifically, we develop a biological-inspired Boids-based Social Force Model (BSFM) to implement swarm mobility control with location information and link states to improve the communication performance of UAV networks. Then, we design an adaptive routing scheme to adjust the Hello message sending interval based on the relative velocity and distance between the UAV s for neighbor discovery and topology maintenance. We conduct experiments with Network Simulator 3 (NS-3) for performance evaluation, and simulation results show that our method outperforms conventional approaches regarding the average delay, packet loss ratio, and network throughput.  © 2023 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: L. Wang; School of Computer Science, Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications, Beijing, China; email: liwang@bupt.edu.cn; Conference name: 2023 IEEE INFOCOM Conference on Computer Communications Workshops, INFOCOM WKSHPS 2023; Conference code: 192133&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE INFOCOM - Conf. Comput. Commun. Workshops, INFOCOM WKSHPS&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE INFOCOM - Conf. Comput. Commun. Workshops, INFOCOM WKSHPS</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85171619528&amp;doi=10.1109%2fINFOCOMWKSHPS57453.2023.10225900&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=aeee6c58880ec0f115c7bc9b9b00e3d5</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>IEEE INFOCOM - Conf. Comput. Commun. Workshops, INFOCOM WKSHPS</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mansoor, N.</author><author>Hossain, M. I.</author><author>Rozario, A.</author><author>Zareei, M.</author><author>Arreola, A. R.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Fresh Look at Routing Protocols in Unmanned Aerial Vehicular Networks: A Survey</title><secondary-title>IEEE Access</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Access</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Access</abbr-1></periodical><pages>66289-66308</pages><volume>11</volume><keywords><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Military operations</keyword><keyword>Military vehicles</keyword><keyword>ad-hoc network</keyword><keyword>Ad-hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Cost effectiveness</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle systems</keyword><keyword>Energy efficiency</keyword><keyword>Topology</keyword><keyword>Vehicle communications</keyword><keyword>Vehicle network</keyword><keyword>Vehicular ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Internet protocols</keyword><keyword>Routing protocols</keyword><keyword>FANET</keyword><keyword>Routing-protocol</keyword><keyword>routing protocol</keyword><keyword>multi-path communication</keyword><keyword>Multi-path communication</keyword><keyword>Multipath</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>21693536 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3290871</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The use of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) or drones has grown rapidly in both civilian and military operations over the last few decades. Multi-UAV systems are preferred to single-UAV systems, as they are more efficient and cost-effective when completing missions collaboratively. However, like other ad-hoc networks, UAV networks face the challenge of effective communication. Existing research in mobile ad-hoc networks (MANETs) and vehicular ad-hoc networks (VANETs) does not fully address the unique characteristics of UAV networks, which can exhibit varying levels of dynamism, intermittent links, and fluid topology. Moreover, drones need to communicate with each other and ground stations in Flying Ad-hoc Networks. Therefore, routing protocols in such networks must select the most effective paths for communication while ensuring reliable and stable data transmission. This article examines several recently developed routing protocols in UAV communication, detailing their construction methods. As routing is quite challenging in UAVs, where communication performance depends on various factors, this research introduces performance metrics to analyze the efficiency of these protocols. Routing protocols in UAV networks must adapt to high mobility, dynamic topology, intermittent links, power constraints, and changing link quality. Since the lifespan of UAV nodes is limited, seamless handovers are crucial, and the energy efficiency of protocols at different layers should also be considered. Although the reviewed protocols address several aspects of designing routing protocols for UAV communication, some challenges remain. Thus, this article provides a comprehensive exploration of routing protocols in UAV communication, along with a discussion of some open research areas. © 2013 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: M. Zareei; Tecnologico de Monterrey, School of Engineering and Sciences, Zapopan, 45201, Mexico; email: m.zareei@ieee.org; A.R. Arreola; Tecnologico de Monterrey, School of Engineering and Sciences, Zapopan, 45201, Mexico; email: alberto.r.arreola@tec.mx</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85163500367&amp;doi=10.1109%2fACCESS.2023.3290871&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=11784a7e200aa47c35025f54af3a521a</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cardona, G. A.</author><author>Leahy, K.</author><author>Vasile, C.-I.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Temporal Logic Swarm Control with Splitting and Merging</title><secondary-title>Proceedings - IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proc IEEE Int Conf Rob Autom</full-title></periodical><pages>12423-12429</pages><volume>2023-May</volume><keywords><keyword>Computer circuits</keyword><keyword>Integer programming</keyword><keyword>Safe operation</keyword><keyword>Linearization</keyword><keyword>Temporal logic</keyword><keyword>Inter-agent communications</keyword><keyword>Merging</keyword><keyword>Metric temporal logic</keyword><keyword>Splitting and merging</keyword><keyword>Splittings</keyword><keyword>Sub-swarms</keyword><keyword>Swarm of robots</keyword><keyword>Temporal logic formula</keyword><keyword>Time horizons</keyword><keyword>Upper Bound</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>10504729 (ISSN); 979-835032365-8 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICRA48891.2023.10160335</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper presents an agent-agnostic framework to control swarms of robots tasked with temporal and logical missions expressed as Metric Temporal Logic (MTL) formulas. We consider agents that can receive global commands from a high-level planner, but no inter-agent communication. Moreover, agents are grouped into sub-swarms whose number can vary over the mission time horizon due to splitting and merging. However, a strict upper bound on the maximum number of sub-swarms is imposed to ensure their safe operation in the environment. We propose a two-phase approach. In the first phase, we compute the trajectories of the sub-swarms, splitting, and merging actions using a Mixed Integer Linear Programming approach that ensures the satisfaction of the MTL specification with minimal swarm division over the mission time horizon. Moreover, it enforces the upper bound on the number of sub-swarms. In the second phase, splitting fractions for sub-swarms resulting from splitting actions are computed. A distributed randomized protocol with no interagent communication ensures agent assignments matching the splitting fractions. Finally, we show the operation and performance of the approach in simulations with multiple tasks that require swarm splitting or merging. © 2023 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Conference name: 2023 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation, ICRA 2023; Conference date: 29 May 2023 through 2 June 2023; Conference code: 190430; CODEN: PIIAE&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proc IEEE Int Conf Rob Autom&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proc IEEE Int Conf Rob Autom</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85168686125&amp;doi=10.1109%2fICRA48891.2023.10160335&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=c7c85ba1b3fa3d4a97388d561e373caf</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>Proc IEEE Int Conf Rob Autom</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hussein, S.</author><author>Thasin, A.</author><author>Sami, A.</author><author>Sabitha Banu, A.</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Gupta D</author><author>Khanna A</author><author>Bhattacharyya S</author><author>Hassanien A. E</author><author>Anand S</author><author>Jaiswal A</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Secure AI-Based Flying Ad Hoc Networks: Trusted Communication</title><secondary-title>Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Lect. Notes Networks Syst.</full-title></periodical><pages>521-528</pages><volume>473</volume><keywords><keyword>UAV</keyword><keyword>FANETS</keyword><keyword>DSR &amp; ML</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Springer Science and Business Media Deutschland GmbH</publisher><isbn>23673370 (ISSN); 978-981192820-8 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/978-981-19-2821-5_43</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Unmanned aerial vehicles are real-time applications for flying networks which encourage multi-UAV structures. A multi-UAV system has a corporate behavior and can finish a mission efficiently. Coverage issues between ground stations and aerial vehicles are easily solved using FANETs. Because of the dynamic nature of flying vehicles, there are several security concerns. Routing protocols can upgrade and secure communication channels in flying networks. In order to increase the lifeline of aerial networks, a qualified routing research study is also carried out. According to simulation findings, zone routing protocol has maintained to secure communication channels and promises higher security without incurring computational expense. © 2023, The Author(s), under exclusive license to Springer Nature Singapore Pte Ltd.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: A. Sabitha Banu; Avinashilingam Institute for Home Science and Higher Education for Women, Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu, India; email: 16phcsf003@avinuty.ac.in; Conference name: 5th International Conference on Innovative Computing and Communication, ICICC 2022; Conference date: 19 February 2022 through 20 February 2022; Conference code: 283899&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Lect. Notes Networks Syst.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Lect. Notes Networks Syst.</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85140479362&amp;doi=10.1007%2f978-981-19-2821-5_43&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=e1b055c7ec7229763f13baa8a3c26f8b</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>Lect. Notes Networks Syst.</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Haddox, P.</author><author>Allison, J. T.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>New Mission and Spacecraft Design Enabled Using MSAC</title><secondary-title>IEEE Aerospace Conference Proceedings</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.</full-title></periodical><volume>2023-March</volume><keywords><keyword>Performance</keyword><keyword>Attitude control</keyword><keyword>Control design</keyword><keyword>Optical communication</keyword><keyword>Mission design</keyword><keyword>Spacecraft</keyword><keyword>Solar radiation</keyword><keyword>Solar sails</keyword><keyword>Active noise cancellation</keyword><keyword>Attitude control system</keyword><keyword>Multifunctional structures</keyword><keyword>Physical design</keyword><keyword>Pointing accuracy</keyword><keyword>Pointing stability</keyword><keyword>Spacecraft design</keyword><keyword>Spurious signal noise</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><isbn>1095323X (ISSN); 978-166549032-0 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/AERO55745.2023.10115834</electronic-resource-num><abstract>A new attitude control system (ACS) called Multifunctional Structures for Attitude Control (MSAC) utilizes structures onboard a spacecraft to provide active noise cancellation and large-angle slewing capabilities. Previous studies have detailed the system trades and physical and control designs that maximize the pointing performance of an MSAC system. As a result, the MSAC system can provide sub-milli-arc-second(mas)/nano-radian level pointing stability and accuracy. Traditional spacecraft design is formulated based on conventional spacecraft bus systems, of which conventional ACSs are a significant driver for the mass and volume of the spacecraft. MSAC relaxes these requirements and enables a new class of spacecraft missions. This paper details the new spacecraft architectures with large area-to-mass ratios that can be enabled using the MSAC system, such as solar sails, Disksats, ChipSats, etc. In addition to standalone spacecraft, MSAC can also be used to provide independent actuation capabilities to different subsystems onboard a spacecraft, such as self-steering antennas, solar panels, and thermal radiators. These new spacecraft busses and subsystems are made possible using MSAC, which can profoundly impact constellation mission development and deployment. Currently, MSAC exists as three main variants for use with different mission types and varying design complexity levels. This paper compares the different variants, and the control authority obtained using the different implementations. In addition to rotational control, MSAC also offers translational position control. These translational positioning capabilities are best at small scales (micrometer-level positioning). The position control can be utilized for internal translational active noise cancellation and formation flying missions that are sensitive to a spacecraft's position. Using the fine pointing and positioning accuracy and stability offered by MSAC can increase communication data rates for deep space optical communication, as well as enable missions such as distributed swarms and LISA. © 2023 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Conference name: 2023 IEEE Aerospace Conference, AERO 2023; Conference date: 4 March 2023 through 11 March 2023; Conference code: 188722&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85160519267&amp;doi=10.1109%2fAERO55745.2023.10115834&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=a8af09cbcb4f18e6c42684ee6c26df10</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Song, Y.</author><author>Lim, S.</author><author>Myung, H.</author><author>Lee, H.</author><author>Jeong, J.</author><author>Lim, H.</author><author>Oh, H.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Distributed swarm system with hybrid-flocking control for small fixed-wing UAVs: Algorithms and flight experiments</title><secondary-title>Expert Systems with Applications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Expert Systems with Applications</full-title><abbr-1>Expert Sys Appl</abbr-1></periodical><volume>229</volume><keywords><keyword>Computer architecture</keyword><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Fixed wings</keyword><keyword>Flight simulators</keyword><keyword>Aircraft control</keyword><keyword>Control protocols</keyword><keyword>Distributed swarm system architecture</keyword><keyword>Flight control systems</keyword><keyword>Flight experiment</keyword><keyword>Flight experiments</keyword><keyword>Flocking control</keyword><keyword>Hybrid-flocking control</keyword><keyword>Smale model</keyword><keyword>Swarm systems</keyword><keyword>Systems architecture</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>09574174 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.eswa.2023.120457</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper presents a distributed swarm system for small fixed-wing unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs). In particular, to perform various missions with multiple UAVs that are densely gathered and collision free, a hybrid-flocking control algorithm is synthesized by using three types of control protocols: vector field guidance (for path following/loitering), augmented Cucker–Smale (ACS) model (for collective flocking behavior), and potential field (for collision avoidance). In particular, to address the issue of conflicts between different control protocols, the adaptive ACS model is proposed and the optimization problem is formulated to determine the suitable mixing weights of control protocols. We also design the transition of multiple operation modes and communication architecture for the swarm system. The system is evaluated using the proposed hybrid-flocking control algorithm by proof-of-concept real flight experiments using 18 small fixed-wing UAVs as well as extensive numerical simulations. Flight experiments are successfully performed for multiple consecutive tasks including the individual task, circular path loitering and elliptical path loitering while avoiding collisions among UAVs. © 2023 Elsevier Ltd</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 1; Correspondence Address: H. Oh; Ulsan National Institute of Science and Technology (UNIST), Ulsan, 44919, South Korea; email: h.oh@unist.ac.kr; CODEN: ESAPE</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85159782210&amp;doi=10.1016%2fj.eswa.2023.120457&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=742263ceb6079e5c9489cacfb1117a3d</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Liu, Y.</author><author>Huo, L.</author><author>Wu, J.</author><author>Bashir, A. K.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Swarm Learning-Based Dynamic Optimal Management for Traffic Congestion in 6G-Driven Intelligent Transportation System</title><secondary-title>IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst.</abbr-1></periodical><pages>7831-7846</pages><volume>24</volume><number>7</number><issue>7</issue><keywords><keyword>Optimisations</keyword><keyword>Swarm intelligence</keyword><keyword>Motion planning</keyword><keyword>Computational modelling</keyword><keyword>Intelligent systems</keyword><keyword>Learning systems</keyword><keyword>Vehicle's dynamics</keyword><keyword>Neural networks</keyword><keyword>Neural-networks</keyword><keyword>Mobile communications</keyword><keyword>Urban transportation</keyword><keyword>Vehicles</keyword><keyword>neural networks</keyword><keyword>Roads and streets</keyword><keyword>Traffic congestion</keyword><keyword>Intelligent transportation systems</keyword><keyword>Road</keyword><keyword>6g mobile communication</keyword><keyword>6g-driven intelligent transportation system</keyword><keyword>6G-driven ITS</keyword><keyword>Hidden Markov models</keyword><keyword>Hidden-Markov models</keyword><keyword>intelligent decision</keyword><keyword>Intelligent decisions</keyword><keyword>swarm learning</keyword><keyword>Swarm learning</keyword><keyword>traffic congestion optimization</keyword><keyword>Traffic congestion optimization</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>15249050 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/TITS.2023.3234444</electronic-resource-num><abstract>As city boundaries expand and the vehicles continues to proliferate, the transportation system is increasingly overloaded, greatly increasing people's commuting burden and extending the resulting negative effects to all areas of work and life. It is a big issue that needs to be solved urgently. However, due to the development of infrastructure and technologies in 6G-driven Intelligent Transportation Systems (ITS), it becomes possible to alleviate urban congestion. Existing solutions either optimize the path planning of each vehicle, or only focus on solving the problem of resource allocation of a single road, neither can take advantage of self-organizing networks and easily fall into local optimum. Combining the above reasons, we propose the Direction Decide as a Service (DDaaS) scheme. First, it contains a novel three-layer service architecture based on Swarm Learning (SL), which enables orderly transmission of traffic data and control instructions and protects user privacy. Second, an improved local model and aggregation method is incorporated into DDaaS, which enables to make accurate predictions when the road resources at a single intersection are insufficient. Third, we propose a dynamic traffic control algorithm to provide signal light switching decisions for rapidly changing ITS. Finally, constructing an urban road simulation experiment combined with SUMO, we prove that DDaaS can reduce traffic congestion effectively and has significant advantages compared to other schemes.  © 2000-2011 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 7; Correspondence Address: J. Wu; Waseda University, Graduate School of Information, Production and Systems, Fukuoka, 808-0135, Japan; email: jun.wu@ieee.org</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85147266919&amp;doi=10.1109%2fTITS.2023.3234444&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=a1c38dd60dc5d40338adb52dddd9c0bb</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Millar, R. C.</author><author>Hashemi, L.</author><author>Mahmoodi, A.</author><author>Meyer, R. W.</author><author>Laliberte, J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Integrating unmanned and manned UAVs data network based on combined Bayesian belief network and multi-objective reinforcement learning algorithm</title><secondary-title>Drone Systems and Applications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Drone Systems and Applications</full-title><abbr-1>Drone. Syst. Appl.</abbr-1></periodical><pages>1-17</pages><volume>11</volume><keywords><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Bayesian networks</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Network architecture</keyword><keyword>Data handling</keyword><keyword>Reinforcement learning</keyword><keyword>unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Learning algorithms</keyword><keyword>Optical radar</keyword><keyword>Risk assessment</keyword><keyword>Convex optimization</keyword><keyword>Multiobjective optimization</keyword><keyword>Bayesian belief network</keyword><keyword>Data network</keyword><keyword>LIDAR sensor</keyword><keyword>LIDAR sensors</keyword><keyword>Multi objective</keyword><keyword>multi-objective reinforcement algorithm</keyword><keyword>Multi-objective reinforcement algorithm</keyword><keyword>Multiple-objectives</keyword><keyword>Reinforcement algorithms</keyword><keyword>Reinforcement learning algorithms</keyword><keyword>trajectory optimization</keyword><keyword>Trajectory optimization</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>25644939 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1139/dsa-2022-0043</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper presents and assesses the feasibility and potential of a novel concept: the operation of multiple Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) commanded and supported by a manned “Tender” air vehicle carrying a pilot and flight manager(s). The “Ten-der” is equipped to flexibly and economically monitor and manage multiple diverse UAVs over otherwise inaccessible terrain through wireless communication. The proposed architecture enables operations and analysis supported by the means to de-tect, assess, and accommodate change and hazards on the spot with effective human observation and coordination. Further, this paper seeks to find the optimal trajectories for UAVs to collect data from sensors in a predefined continuous space. We formulate the path-planning problem for a cooperative, and a diverse swarm of UAVs tasked with optimizing multiple objectives simultaneously with the goal of maximizing accumulated data within a given flight time within cloud data processing constraints as well as minimizing the probable imposed risk during UAVs mission. The risk assessment model determines risk indicators using an integrated Specific Operation Risk Assessment —Bayesian belief network approach, while its resultant analysis is weighted through the analytic hierarchy process ranking model. To this end, as the problem is formulated as a convex optimization model, and we propose a low complexity multi-objective reinforcement learning (MORL) algorithm with a provable performance guarantee to solve the problem efficiently. We show that the MORL architecture can be successfully trained and allows each UAV to map each observation of the network state to an action to make optimal movement decisions. This proposed network architecture enables the UAVs to balance multiple objectives. Estimated MSE measures show that the algorithm produced decreasing errors in the learning process with increasing epoch number. © 2023 The Author(s).</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: A. Mahmoodi; Carleton University, Mechanical &amp; Aerospace Engineering, Ottawa, Canada; email: arminmahmoodi@cmail.carleton.ca</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85149659347&amp;doi=10.1139%2fdsa-2022-0043&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=af2ffd62e0a7460c2ea962eb774d8246</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Pichierri, L.</author><author>Testa, A.</author><author>Notarstefano, G.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>CrazyChoir: Flying Swarms of Crazyflie Quadrotors in ROS 2</title><secondary-title>IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Robot. Autom.</abbr-1></periodical><pages>4713-4720</pages><volume>8</volume><number>8</number><issue>8</issue><keywords><keyword>Decision making</keyword><keyword>Modulars</keyword><keyword>Optimisations</keyword><keyword>Task analysis</keyword><keyword>Robot programming</keyword><keyword>Robot Operating System</keyword><keyword>Quad rotors</keyword><keyword>Decisions makings</keyword><keyword>Control schemes</keyword><keyword>Firmware</keyword><keyword>Distributed robot systems</keyword><keyword>Co-operating robots</keyword><keyword>cooperating robots</keyword><keyword>optimization and optimal control</keyword><keyword>Optimization and optimal control</keyword><keyword>Software architecture for robotic and automation</keyword><keyword>software architecture for robotics and automation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>23773766 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/LRA.2023.3286814</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This letter introduces CrazyChoir, a modular Python framework based on the Robot Operating System (ROS) 2. The toolbox provides a comprehensive set of functionalities to simulate and run experiments on teams of cooperating Crazyflie nano-quadrotors. Specifically, it allows users to perform realistic simulations over robotic simulators as, e.g., Webots and includes bindings of the firmware control and planning functions. The toolbox also provides libraries to perform radio communication with Crazyflie directly inside ROS 2 scripts. The package can be thus used to design, implement and test planning strategies and control schemes for a Crazyflie nano-quadrotor. Moreover, the modular structure of CrazyChoir allows users to easily implement online distributed optimization and control schemes over multiple quadrotors. The CrazyChoir package is validated via simulations and experiments on a swarm of Crazyflies for formation control, pickup-and-delivery vehicle routing and trajectory tracking tasks.  © 2016 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 1; Correspondence Address: L. Pichierri; University of Bologna, Department of Electrical, Electronic and Information Engineering, Bologna, 40136, Italy; email: lorenzo.pichierri@unibo.it</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85162653103&amp;doi=10.1109%2fLRA.2023.3286814&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=21c00226342864bfb82cabfd84234a6b</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bartolini, N.</author><author>Coletta, A.</author><author>Giorgi, F.</author><author>Maselli, G.</author><author>Prata, M.</author><author>Silvestri, D.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Stop &amp; Route: Periodic Data Offloading in UAV Networks</title><secondary-title>2023 18th Wireless On-Demand Network Systems and Services Conference, WONS 2023</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Wirel. On-Demand Netw. Syst. Serv. Conf., WONS</full-title></periodical><pages>92-99</pages><keywords><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Harsh environment</keyword><keyword>Routings</keyword><keyword>Vehicle to vehicle communications</keyword><keyword>5G mobile communication systems</keyword><keyword>UAVs</keyword><keyword>Vehicle network</keyword><keyword>routing</keyword><keyword>Key technologies</keyword><keyword>Internet protocols</keyword><keyword>Routing protocols</keyword><keyword>FANET</keyword><keyword>FANETs</keyword><keyword>Mobile ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Control channels</keyword><keyword>Fast mobility</keyword><keyword>data offloading</keyword><keyword>Data offloading</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-390317656-0 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.23919/WONS57325.2023.10062043</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Swarms of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) are a key technology to support communication in many harsh environments where fixed infrastructures (e.g., 5G) are disrupted or not available. However, the fast mobility and highly dynamic network topology pose unique challenges and require the development of novel multi-hop routing protocols. Previous work in this direction extends geographical protocols, or adapts approaches designed for Mobile Ad-hoc NETworks (MANETs), rarely taking full advantage of UAV capabilities. In this paper we introduce a novel data offloading approach, namely Stop &amp; Route, that exploits the device controllable mobility to facilitate network routing. The swarm of UAVs performs data offloading synchronously and recurrently. At fixed intervals of time, the swarm interrupts the sensing mission (stop) and moves, as less as possible, to build a connected formation to the base station and offload the data (route). We provide both centralized solutions - assuming a long-range control channel - and a distributed solution - working in the absence of a control channel. By means of extensive simulations we show that our proposals outperform state-of-the-art solutions, decreasing the time taken to build a connected formation of about 25% and increasing the time spent on sensing of 14%.  © 2023 IFIP.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: N. Bartolini; Sapienza University of Rome, Computer Science Department, Rome, Italy; email: bartolini@di.uniroma1.it; Conference name: 18th Wireless On-Demand Network Systems and Services Conference, WONS 2023; Conference date: 30 January 2023 through 1 February 2023; Conference code: 187212&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Wirel. On-Demand Netw. Syst. Serv. Conf., WONS&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Wirel. On-Demand Netw. Syst. Serv. Conf., WONS</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85150684979&amp;doi=10.23919%2fWONS57325.2023.10062043&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=6d9eda32bba5904191b6cabde2c3d09a</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>Wirel. On-Demand Netw. Syst. Serv. Conf., WONS</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Xiong, H.</author><author>Yu, B.</author><author>Yi, Q.</author><author>He, C.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>End-Cloud Collaboration Navigation Planning Method for Unmanned Aerial Vehicles Used in Small Areas</title><secondary-title>Sensors</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Sensors</full-title><abbr-1>Sensors</abbr-1></periodical><volume>23</volume><number>16</number><issue>16</issue><keywords><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Flight simulators</keyword><keyword>Rock mechanics</keyword><keyword>Aircraft control</keyword><keyword>Swarm optimization</keyword><keyword>Air navigation</keyword><keyword>unmanned aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>end-cloud collaboration</keyword><keyword>End-cloud collaboration</keyword><keyword>improved particle swarm optimization</keyword><keyword>Improved particle swarm optimization</keyword><keyword>Indoor positioning systems</keyword><keyword>Navigation controls</keyword><keyword>navigation planning</keyword><keyword>Navigation planning</keyword><keyword>Navigation planning methods</keyword><keyword>Particle swarm</keyword><keyword>Particle swarm optimization (PSO)</keyword><keyword>Planning algorithms</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>14248220 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.3390/s23167129</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) collaboration has become the main means of indoor and outdoor regional search, railway patrol, and other tasks, and navigation planning is one of the key, albeit difficult, technologies. The purpose of UAV navigation planning is to plan reasonable trajectories for UAVs to avoid obstacles and reach the task area. Essentially, it is a complex optimization problem that requires the use of navigation planning algorithms to search for path-point solutions that meet the requirements under the guide of objective functions and constraints. At present, there are autonomous navigation modes of UAVs relying on airborne sensors and navigation control modes of UAVs relying on ground control stations (GCSs). However, due to the limitation of airborne processor computing power, and background command and control communication delay, a navigation planning method that takes into account accuracy and timeliness is needed. First, the navigation planning architecture of UAVs of end-cloud collaboration was designed. Then, the background cloud navigation planning algorithm of UAVs was designed based on the improved particle swarm optimization (PSO). Next, the navigation control algorithm of the UAV terminals was designed based on the multi-objective hybrid swarm intelligent optimization algorithm. Finally, the computer simulation and actual indoor-environment flight test based on small rotor UAVs were designed and conducted. The results showed that the proposed method is correct and feasible, and can improve the effectiveness and efficiency of navigation planning of UAVs. © 2023 by the authors.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: B. Yu; State Key Laboratory of Satellite Navigation System and Equipment Technology, Shijiazhuang, 050081, China; email: yubg@sina.cn</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85168715911&amp;doi=10.3390%2fs23167129&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=4adf929ef8ff25f47a497782d836286d</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bakirci, M.</author><author>Ozer, M. M.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Gaining Swarm Behavior through Establishing a Control System and Communication Network on Unmanned Aerial Vehicles</title><secondary-title>Proceedings of 10th International Conference on Recent Advances in Air and Space Technologies, RAST 2023</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proc. Int. Conf. Recent Adv. Air Space Technol., RAST</full-title></periodical><keywords><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Network architecture</keyword><keyword>Ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Communications networks</keyword><keyword>UAV</keyword><keyword>Control architecture</keyword><keyword>Robot Operating System</keyword><keyword>Swarm systems</keyword><keyword>Vehicle to vehicle communications</keyword><keyword>Aviation industry</keyword><keyword>communication network</keyword><keyword>control architecture</keyword><keyword>Diverse fields</keyword><keyword>Environmental technology</keyword><keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword><keyword>Swarm behavior</keyword><keyword>swarm systems</keyword><keyword>Systems networks</keyword><keyword>Wide-field</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>979-835032302-3 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/RAST57548.2023.10197953</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The aviation industry has been disrupted to a great extent, with unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) attracting great interest in both industry and academia in recent years. As technology continues to evolve, disruption has only continued to increase in size as it finds its place in a wide and diverse field covering both military and domestic fields. With indigenous practices such as search and rescue missions during disasters, environmental monitoring and surveillance, agriculture and farming, this disruption has shifted to a specialized technology, swarm UAVs. Communication is a critical component in swarm systems with the potential to distribute missions and coordinate the operation of many UAVs without operator intervention. In this study, a swarm architecture is proposed that will allow higher swarm autonomy and reliability by providing both reliable communication between swarm systems and the ground station, and communication between individual UAVs. The development of swarm UAVs with autonomous coordination capability with wireless ad hoc networks, an attractive solution for inter-UAV communication, is at the heart of improving the utility of UAV swarms. During the realization of this, the integrated communication architecture of the swarm UAVs, which combines both the long-range architectures offered by 900 MHz-based radios and the short-range architectures offered by 802.11-based ad-hoc networks, coexists. All these systems are implemented using the robot operating system (ROS), which allows it to be easily integrated into the capabilities of any distributed application.  © 2023 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Conference name: 10th International Conference on Recent Advances in Air and Space Technologies, RAST 2023; Conference date: 7 June 2023 through 9 June 2023; Conference code: 191477&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proc. Int. Conf. Recent Adv. Air Space Technol., RAST&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proc. Int. Conf. Recent Adv. Air Space Technol., RAST</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85168421655&amp;doi=10.1109%2fRAST57548.2023.10197953&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=c2a2c2028926473e69dccb075a5917d6</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>Proc. Int. Conf. Recent Adv. Air Space Technol., RAST</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kourtis, M. A.</author><author>Xilouris, G.</author><author>Batistatos, M.</author><author>Kourtis, A.</author><author>Markakis, A.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Emergency communications leveraging decentralized swarm computing</title><secondary-title>ACM International Conference Proceeding Series</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Int. Conf. Proc. Ser.</full-title></periodical><pages>302-306</pages><keywords><keyword>Computer architecture</keyword><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>drones</keyword><keyword>Swarm intelligence</keyword><keyword>Emergency communications</keyword><keyword>blockchain</keyword><keyword>Block-chain</keyword><keyword>Blockchain</keyword><keyword>DAO</keyword><keyword>Decentralised</keyword><keyword>decentralized computing</keyword><keyword>Decentralized computing</keyword><keyword>Emergency communication</keyword><keyword>High data rate</keyword><keyword>High data-rates</keyword><keyword>Low latency</keyword><keyword>Reliable communication</keyword><keyword>swarm intelligence</keyword><keyword>Ubiquitous communication</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>979-840070049-1 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3576914.3588019</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Reliable and ubiquitous communications, offering high data rates, low latency and supporting large numbers of connected devices, are critical requirements for modern emergency rescue missions. Multiple teams of First Responders, operating at remote areas, on rough terrain or under harsh conditions (e.g. wildfires, earthquakes, flooding etc.) need seamless connectivity to send/receive mission data and organize their operations. Decentralized swarm computing architectures offer a wide range of capabilities to enhance and accelerate edge processing for critical use case scenarios. This paper presents a converged approach on swarm computing and intelligence using Decentralized Autonomous Organizations for emergency communications, and how a swarm of drones can leverage different edge accelerators for different applications.  © 2023 ACM.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Conference name: 2023 Cyber-Physical Systems and Internet-of-Things Week, CPS-IoT Week 2023; Conference date: 9 May 2023 through 12 May 2023; Conference code: 188505&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: ACM Int. Conf. Proc. Ser.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: ACM Int. Conf. Proc. Ser.</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85159782999&amp;doi=10.1145%2f3576914.3588019&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=fb36f4cbb96f81ec3a9d80eb3a649ddb</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>ACM Int. Conf. Proc. Ser.</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bakirci, M.</author><author>Ozer, M. M.</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Varol A</author><author>Karabatak M</author><author>Varol C</author><author>Nasab A</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>A Low-Cost UAV Design for Surveillance Purposes in Swarm Systems</title><secondary-title>ISDFS 2023 - 11th International Symposium on Digital Forensics and Security</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ISDFS - Int. Symp. Digit. Forensics Secur.</full-title></periodical><keywords><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Aircraft detection</keyword><keyword>Low-costs</keyword><keyword>Network architecture</keyword><keyword>Rock mechanics</keyword><keyword>UAV systems</keyword><keyword>Cost effectiveness</keyword><keyword>Data transfer</keyword><keyword>Swarm systems</keyword><keyword>swarm systems</keyword><keyword>communication architecture</keyword><keyword>Communication architectures</keyword><keyword>Flight mission</keyword><keyword>low-cost UAV</keyword><keyword>Low-cost UAV</keyword><keyword>object detection</keyword><keyword>Object detection</keyword><keyword>Object recognition</keyword><keyword>Objects detection</keyword><keyword>surveillance</keyword><keyword>Surveillance</keyword><keyword>Surveillance applications</keyword><keyword>UAV designs</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>979-835033698-6 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ISDFS58141.2023.10131774</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This study focuses on a low-cost UAV design for a swarm UAV system to be used in reconnaissance and surveillance applications. The individual UAV, which will form the swarm and serve in this context, is designed in accordance with the swarm behaviors and requirements such as autonomous behavior, formation and coordination. Within the scope of the planned flight missions, the necessary communication architectures were emphasized by considering the communication between the ground control station and other swarm members. The most cost-effective equipment for fundamental tasks such as flight control, swarm intercommunication, object detection has been studied, and individual swarm members are equipped in line with these requirements and limitations. The problem of consistent sharing of data obtained during the flight mission has been examined in detail and appropriate solutions have been produced with proper communication and data transfer protocols. A low-cost solution has been obtained for aerial surveillance applications of the swarm UAV system, which can provide direct point-to-point communication through selected equipment and network message transmission during flight. © 2023 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: M. Bakirci; Faculty of Aeronautics and Astronautics Tarsus University, Unmanned/Intelligent Systems Lab, Mersin, Turkey; email: muratbakirci@tarsus.edu.tr; Conference name: 11th International Symposium on Digital Forensics and Security, ISDFS 2023; Conference date: 11 May 2023 through 12 May 2023; Conference code: 189042&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: ISDFS - Int. Symp. Digit. Forensics Secur.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: ISDFS - Int. Symp. Digit. Forensics Secur.</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85163053799&amp;doi=10.1109%2fISDFS58141.2023.10131774&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=cabfb576f8c503f362483a1643c2e00b</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>ISDFS - Int. Symp. Digit. Forensics Secur.</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Collier, P.</author><author>Adalier, M.</author><author>Guarneros, A. L.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Modular Low SWaP-C SmallSats with Advanced Communications for Space Exploration</title><secondary-title>IEEE Aerospace Conference Proceedings</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.</full-title></periodical><volume>2023-March</volume><keywords><keyword>Software testing</keyword><keyword>Modulars</keyword><keyword>Delay tolerant networks</keyword><keyword>Orbits</keyword><keyword>Space platforms</keyword><keyword>NASA</keyword><keyword>Earth orbits</keyword><keyword>Key technologies</keyword><keyword>Space flight</keyword><keyword>Development and testing</keyword><keyword>Space explorations</keyword><keyword>Rapid testing</keyword><keyword>Small spacecrafts</keyword><keyword>Disruption tolerant networking</keyword><keyword>Orbit mission</keyword><keyword>Rapid identification</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><isbn>1095323X (ISSN); 978-166549032-0 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/AERO55745.2023.10115701</electronic-resource-num><abstract>NASA is pursuing rapid identification, development and testing of key technologies that further advance the capabilities of small spacecraft platforms to accelerate the pace of space exploration, scientific discovery and the expansion of space commerce in a sustainable manner. Under a NASA funded Lunar Sequential project titled 'Efficient and Secure Communications for Spacecraft Beyond LEO,' Antara has been developing modular SpaceVNX+ based small spacecraft and a software package for secure, efficient, and scalable Delay and Disruption Tolerant Networking (DTN) communications for distributed platforms. The paper describes the SpaceVNX+ standard and the CubeSat platform that will host the soft-ware; the LunaNet compatible DTN software, taraION; and the planned Low Earth Orbit (LEO) mission to flight qualify the hardware and software. The LEO mission will be comprised of a small swarm of six SpaceVNX+ CubeSats that will demonstrate secure DTN and autonomous communications between ground stations and CubeSats as well as among the CubeSats. As a case study, the paper also covers the details and analysis of benchtop testing of the mission software and hardware. These emerging capabilities have the potential to make possible new mission architectures, enhance conventional missions and reduce development and deployment timelines, which will enable NASA and other space mission operators to achieve their objectives at significantly lower programmatic risk and cost than traditional approaches. © 2023 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Conference name: 2023 IEEE Aerospace Conference, AERO 2023; Conference date: 4 March 2023 through 11 March 2023; Conference code: 188722&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85160569799&amp;doi=10.1109%2fAERO55745.2023.10115701&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=62867d6b37d2e967022811c862508e0e</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>IEEE Aerosp. Conf. Proc.</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kuhn, R.</author><author>Darmasaputra, A.</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Just R</author><author>Fraser F</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Behaviorally Typed State Machines in TypeScript for Heterogeneous Swarms</title><secondary-title>ISSTA 2023 - Proceedings of the 32nd ACM SIGSOFT International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ISSTA - Proc. ACM SIGSOFT Int. Symp. Softw. Test. Anal.</full-title></periodical><pages>1475-1478</pages><keywords><keyword>Computation theory</keyword><keyword>Middleware</keyword><keyword>Swarm systems</keyword><keyword>State-machine</keyword><keyword>Communication topologies</keyword><keyword>Individual agent</keyword><keyword>Mission-critical operations</keyword><keyword>Distributed systems</keyword><keyword>Distributed coordination</keyword><keyword>Behavioral types</keyword><keyword>behavioural types</keyword><keyword>Data replication</keyword><keyword>local-first software</keyword><keyword>Local-first software</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery, Inc</publisher><isbn>979-840070221-1 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3597926.3604917</electronic-resource-num><abstract>A heterogeneous swarm system is a distributed system where participants come and go, communication topology may change at any time, data replication is asynchronous and partial, and local agents behave differently between nodes. These systems are hard to design and reason about, mainly because we desire a particular class of behaviors to emerge from the interplay of heterogeneous individual agents. Nevertheless, mission-critical operations like manufacturing process orchestration in factories use such systems due to their uncompromising availability and resilience of computing services. This paper presents a set of TypeScript libraries to model peer-to-peer workflows as state machines, execute them using the Actyx middleware, and check the shape of these machines for conformance to a swarm protocol. The swarm protocol describes an idealized global view of the cooperation of machines of different roles. It directly corresponds to a diagram a product manager would sketch on a whiteboard; this allows for verifying that the coded state machines correctly implement the product specification. A well-formed swarm protocol also guarantees that conforming machines will achieve eventual consensus on the overall state progression even in the absence of further coordination. This tool is for developers of business logic for heterogeneous swarm systems, helping them verify that their protocols and implementations are correct. Tool repo: https://github.com/Actyx/machines  © 2023 ACM.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Conference name: 32nd ACM SIGSOFT International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis, ISSTA 2023; Conference date: 17 July 2023 through 21 July 2023; Conference code: 190710&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: ISSTA - Proc. ACM SIGSOFT Int. Symp. Softw. Test. Anal.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: ISSTA - Proc. ACM SIGSOFT Int. Symp. Softw. Test. Anal.</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85167689254&amp;doi=10.1145%2f3597926.3604917&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=bf5c10162de7a74ac75add71ff43e5f7</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>ISSTA - Proc. ACM SIGSOFT Int. Symp. Softw. Test. Anal.</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Montecchiari, L.</author><author>Trotta, A.</author><author>Gigli, L.</author><author>Bellone, L.</author><author>Di Felice, M.</author><author>Natalizio, E.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Distributed Service Discovery over Heterogeneous Robotic Systems-of-Systems</title><secondary-title>Proceedings - 19th International Conference on Distributed Computing in Smart Systems and the Internet of Things, DCOSS-IoT 2023</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proc. - Int. Conf. Distrib. Comput. Smart Syst. Internet Things, DCOSS-IoT</full-title></periodical><pages>227-231</pages><keywords><keyword>Software design</keyword><keyword>Swarm intelligence</keyword><keyword>Learning systems</keyword><keyword>Dynamics</keyword><keyword>System of systems</keyword><keyword>System-of-systems</keyword><keyword>Topology</keyword><keyword>Robots</keyword><keyword>Robotic systems</keyword><keyword>Federated learning</keyword><keyword>Runtimes</keyword><keyword>Robotic swarms</keyword><keyword>Distributed service discovery</keyword><keyword>Federated Learning</keyword><keyword>Multi-radio</keyword><keyword>Multi-Radio</keyword><keyword>Robotic Swarm</keyword><keyword>Robotic system-of-system</keyword><keyword>Robotic Systems-of-Systems</keyword><keyword>Service directories</keyword><keyword>Service Directory</keyword><keyword>Service discovery mechanism</keyword><keyword>Software Development</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>979-835034649-7 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/DCOSS-IoT58021.2023.00047</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In robotic swarms, nodes must cooperate in order to accomplish complex tasks. Robot interactions may occur at run-time based on the dynamic network topology and on mission-specific goals. For this reason, service discovery mechanisms are fundamental in order to inform each robot about the functionalities offered by the other peers. Although several network discovery protocols have been proposed so far, none of them fits the unique characteristics of robotic swarms in terms of dynamic topology, communication heterogeneity, and latency requirements. In this paper, we fill such gap by designing, implementing and evaluating a novel service discovery mechanisms for generic Robotic Systems-of-Systems (RSoS). The study proposes algorithmic and practical contributions. Regarding the first, we describe a novel distributed service discovery algorithm for RSoS which adapts to highly mobile robotic environments while limiting the network overhead and latency. Regarding the latter, we implemented the proposed algorithm within the Uhura swarm robotics framework; as a result, our solution is able to support multi-radio scenarios where robots are provided with heterogeneous Machine-to-Machine (M2M) communication technologies. In addition, we validate our solution through large-scale simulations and a test-bed in which ground robots are able to discover a Federated Learning (FL) task and join it at run-time to improve the accuracy.  © 2023 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: L. Montecchiari; University of Bologna, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Italy; email: leonardo.montecchiari@unibo.it; A. Trotta; University of Bologna, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Italy; email: angelo.trotta5@unibo.it; L. Gigli; University of Bologna, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Italy; email: lorenzo.gigli@unibo.it; M. Di Felice; University of Bologna, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Italy; email: marco.difelice3@unibo.it; Conference name: 19th Annual International Conference on Distributed Computing in Smart Systems and the Internet of Things, DCOSS-IoT 2023; Conference date: 19 June 2023 through 21 June 2023; Conference code: 192963&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proc. - Int. Conf. Distrib. Comput. Smart Syst. Internet Things, DCOSS-IoT&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proc. - Int. Conf. Distrib. Comput. Smart Syst. Internet Things, DCOSS-IoT</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85174390507&amp;doi=10.1109%2fDCOSS-IoT58021.2023.00047&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=5eddf0190597fdf7c4091279dee76d35</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>Proc. - Int. Conf. Distrib. Comput. Smart Syst. Internet Things, DCOSS-IoT</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wang, G.</author><author>Lv, X.</author><author>Yan, X.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Two-Stage Distributed Task Assignment Algorithm Based on Contract Net Protocol for Multi-UAV Cooperative Reconnaissance Task Reassignment in Dynamic Environments</title><secondary-title>Sensors</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Sensors</full-title><abbr-1>Sensors</abbr-1></periodical><volume>23</volume><number>18</number><issue>18</issue><keywords><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Performance</keyword><keyword>Dynamic environments</keyword><keyword>Tasks assignments</keyword><keyword>Disaster prevention</keyword><keyword>Multi UAV</keyword><keyword>UAV systems</keyword><keyword>multi-UAVs</keyword><keyword>Assignment algorithms</keyword><keyword>Distributed tasks</keyword><keyword>Two stage</keyword><keyword>Contract net protocols</keyword><keyword>contract net protocol</keyword><keyword>distributed algorithm</keyword><keyword>task reassignment</keyword><keyword>Task reassignment</keyword><keyword>two stage</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>14248220 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.3390/s23187980</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Multi-UAV systems have been widely used in reconnaissance, disaster relief, communication, and other fields. However, many dynamic events can cause a partial failure of the original mission during the mission execution process, in which case task reassignment should be carried out. How to reassign resources and tasks in multi-dynamic, multi-target, and multi-constraint events becomes a core issue in the enhancement of combat efficiency. This paper establishes a model of multi-UAV cooperative reconnaissance task reassignment that comprehensively considers various dynamic factors such as UAV performance differences, size of target areas, and time window constraints. Then, a two-stage distributed task assignment algorithm (TS-DTA) is presented to achieve multi-task reassignment in dynamic environments. Finally, this paper verifies the effectiveness of the TS-DTA algorithm through simulation experiments and analyzes its performance through comparative experiments. The experimental results show that the TS-DTA algorithm can efficiently solve the task reassignment problem in dynamic environments while effectively reducing the communication burden of UAV formations. © 2023 by the authors.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: X. Lv; College of Computer Engineering, Naval University of Engineering, Wuhan, 430033, China; email: xiaolv_nue@163.com</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85172721986&amp;doi=10.3390%2fs23187980&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=6b429fab3c00177abcdc8e07671c0ca0</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zhang, J.</author><author>Xiang, X.</author><author>Zhang, Q.</author><author>Tao, B.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Particle swarm optimization-based subsea cable electromagnetic detection by autonomous underwater vehicle</title><secondary-title>Neural Computing and Applications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Neural Computing and Applications</full-title><abbr-1>Neural Comput. Appl.</abbr-1></periodical><keywords><keyword>Motion planning</keyword><keyword>Swarm optimization</keyword><keyword>Cables</keyword><keyword>Particle swarm</keyword><keyword>Particle swarm optimization (PSO)</keyword><keyword>Autonomous vehicles</keyword><keyword>Localisation</keyword><keyword>Electric power transmission</keyword><keyword>Image segmentation</keyword><keyword>Particle swarm optimization algorithm</keyword><keyword>Location</keyword><keyword>Remotely operated vehicles</keyword><keyword>Autonomous underwater vehicles</keyword><keyword>Particle swarm optimization</keyword><keyword>Autonomous underwater vehicle</keyword><keyword>Autonomous underwater vehicles]</keyword><keyword>Electromagnetic detection</keyword><keyword>Electromagnetic localization</keyword><keyword>Offshore oil well production</keyword><keyword>Offshore wind farms</keyword><keyword>Power-transmission</keyword><keyword>Subsea cables</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>09410643 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/s00521-023-09060-4</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Subsea cables are widely used for power and information transmission in offshore infrastructure such as global communication networks and offshore wind farms. The precise positioning of subsea cables is an important prerequisite for maintenance and repair. However, the small diameter and burial depth of 3–5 m below the seabed make locating and detecting the subsea cable technically challenging. This paper investigates the localization and intelligent tracking detection of subsea cables based on autonomous underwater vehicle (AUV) and particle swarm optimization (PSO) algorithm. First, an autonomous electromagnetic localization and tracking topology of subsea cable is designed based on AUV architecture and PSO algorithm. The basic principle of locating the horizontal position and depth of a subsea cable based on horizontal survey line measurement is illustrated. Second, the PSO algorithm is retrofitted with electromagnetic localization. Specifically, the subsea cable localization flow diagram, region of interest (ROI) and fitness function are constructed, respectively. Third, an online swath path planning method for subsea cable detection is designed based on the PSO localization results. Finally, the effectiveness of the PSO submarine cable location algorithm and the online planning method for detection paths is verified through multiple controlled simulation tests. © 2023, The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag London Ltd., part of Springer Nature.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: X. Xiang; School of Naval Architecture and Ocean Engineering, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430074, China; email: xbxiang@hust.edu.cn</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85174599629&amp;doi=10.1007%2fs00521-023-09060-4&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=fe3e0a622ae75363ac461146aeab0fc3</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Karam, S. N.</author><author>Bilal, K.</author><author>Shuja, J.</author><author>Rehman, F.</author><author>Yasmin, T.</author><author>Jamil, A.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Inspection of unmanned aerial vehicles in oil and gas industry: critical analysis of platforms, sensors, networking architecture, and path planning</title><secondary-title>Journal of Electronic Imaging</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Electronic Imaging</full-title><abbr-1>J. Electron. Imaging</abbr-1></periodical><volume>32</volume><number>1</number><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>architecture</keyword><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Aircraft detection</keyword><keyword>Network architecture</keyword><keyword>Ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Ad-hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Motion planning</keyword><keyword>Routings</keyword><keyword>Cost effectiveness</keyword><keyword>path planning</keyword><keyword>Inspection</keyword><keyword>Flying ad-hoc network</keyword><keyword>flying ad-hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Gas industry</keyword><keyword>Inspection unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>inspection unmanned aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>Leak detection</keyword><keyword>Networking architecture</keyword><keyword>Oil and Gas Industry</keyword><keyword>pipeline monitoring</keyword><keyword>Pipeline monitoring</keyword><keyword>Pipelines</keyword><keyword>Platform sensors</keyword><keyword>routing</keyword><keyword>Scaffolds</keyword><keyword>Sensor networking</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>10179909 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1117/1.JEI.32.1.011006</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The rapid growth of unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) has huge potential in the oil and gas industry (OGI). These are especially helpful in situations in which human lives are at risk. OGI pipelines are threatened by natural and man-made disasters, which are harmful to both people and assets. Usually, oil and gas pipelines pass through extreme environments for which standard inspection, maintenance, and repairing approaches such as rope access, scaffolds, telescopic elevation platforms supported by cranes, and manned helicopters are not secure and difficult and expensive to implement. However, technological advancements like device miniaturization have boosted the performance of UAVs, offering cost-effective, efficient, and high mission flexibility. UAVs are capable of carrying sensors and cameras to perform monitoring. As pipelines span thousands of kilometers, multi-UAV systems, commonly referred to as flying ad-hoc networks (FANETs), can collaboratively complete monitoring missions more effectively and economically as compared with single UAV systems. Moreover, many issues must be resolved before the effective use of UAVs can provide stable and reliable context-specific networks. Several OGI-specific issues of UAVs such as architecture design, platform, sensors, networking architectures, and path planning models for different OGI pipeline surveillance scenarios must be resolved to use FANETs effectively for robust and sustainable networks. The prime objective of this research is a state-of-the-art review of UAVs in OGI. We first present OGI midstream challenges and parameters to give a brief overview of the challenges faced by the OGI for pipeline surveillance. Then we discuss OGI-specific scenarios for sensor readings, visual leak detection, and detection of any unusual activity that happens in the pipeline while monitoring through UAVs. We also present different OGI-specific UAV platforms, UAV networking architectures, and path planning models of FANET for efficient communication and collaboration. Finally, the challenges of UAVs and future research prospects in OGI-specific UAVs are highlighted.  © 2022 SPIE and IS&amp;T.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 1; Correspondence Address: K. Bilal; Department of Computer Science, Comsats, Islamabad, Pakistan; email: kashifbilal@cuiatd.edu.pk; CODEN: JEIME</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85149441297&amp;doi=10.1117%2f1.JEI.32.1.011006&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=9219f04ee3074030f03fc7a592b42697</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Nakib, S. E.</author><author>Jawhar, I.</author><author>Sindian, S.</author><author>Wu, J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Networking of multi-robot systems: issues and requirements</title><secondary-title>International Journal of Sensor Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Journal of Sensor Networks</full-title><abbr-1>Int. J. Sens. Netw.</abbr-1></periodical><pages>88-98</pages><volume>43</volume><number>2</number><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Data handling</keyword><keyword>Swarm intelligence</keyword><keyword>Agriculture</keyword><keyword>Motion planning</keyword><keyword>Swarm robotics</keyword><keyword>Robot programming</keyword><keyword>wireless sensor networks</keyword><keyword>Industrial robots</keyword><keyword>Multipurpose robots</keyword><keyword>unmanned aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>Wireless sensor networks</keyword><keyword>UAVs</keyword><keyword>path planning</keyword><keyword>WSNs</keyword><keyword>Multi-robot systems</keyword><keyword>Trajectory optimization</keyword><keyword>Agricultural robots</keyword><keyword>swarm robotics</keyword><keyword>Networking protocols</keyword><keyword>Robot learning</keyword><keyword>multi-robot system</keyword><keyword>MRS</keyword><keyword>Systems issues</keyword><keyword>trajectory optimisation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>17481279 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1504/IJSNET.2023.134307</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The advancement of multi-robot systems (MRS), wireless sensor networks (WSNs) and unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) have led to their increasing use for large-scale monitoring. The research in this area has focused on developing advanced sensing and networking protocols, as well as specialised system topologies and embedded computer and communication platforms. This has resulted in a need for multidisciplinary projects to develop appropriate algorithms for data processing, communication, and control across diverse fields. The primary focus of this article is the collaborative features of MRS. It briefly overviews recent advancements in this vital domain, with a comparative focus on numerous recent theoretical and practical contributions. The article also identifies and discusses focus areas, such as a classification of MRS systems and the issues and requirements of MRS networking protocols. Additionally, references to applications in various domains, including the environment, agriculture, emergency scenarios, and border patrol, are highlighted. Finally, an integrated system model based on WSNs and UAVs is presented, along with an optimality study. © 2023 Inderscience Enterprises Ltd.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: S.E. Nakib; Computer and Communication Department, Islamic University of Lebanon, Beirut, Lebanon; email: snakib88@hotmail.com</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85175054854&amp;doi=10.1504%2fIJSNET.2023.134307&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=0336b2b920fbe5de87b425e287028e07</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>An, X.</author><author>Yu, X.</author><author>Song, W.</author><author>Han, L.</author><author>Yang, T.</author><author>Li, Z.</author><author>Su, Z.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Software-Defined Distributed Architecture for Controlling Unmanned Swarm Systems</title><secondary-title>Electronics (Switzerland)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Electronics (Switzerland)</full-title><abbr-1>Electronics (Switzerland)</abbr-1></periodical><volume>12</volume><number>18</number><issue>18</issue><keywords><keyword>distributed</keyword><keyword>network architecture</keyword><keyword>plug-and-play</keyword><keyword>software-defined</keyword><keyword>unmanned swarm</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>20799292 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.3390/electronics12183739</electronic-resource-num><abstract>An unmanned swarm is usually composed of a group of homogeneous or heterogeneous hardware platforms, software control systems, and interfaces for human–computer interaction that operate collectively to achieve a specific goal by information interaction. They exhibit robustness and fault tolerance when facing complex missions, making it crucial in military, transportation, intelligent traffic, and other fields. However, the coupling between the hardware and software of a heterogeneous unmanned swarm can indeed have significant implications for system flexibility, software development and deployment, and hardware maintenance. Over the years, there has been a significant shift from traditional hardware-focused control systems to a greater emphasis on the core software layer. In this paper, a distributed network architecture is proposed to solve this problem, in which hardware resources are abstracted and represented to accomplish standardization and unification by defining a consistent and uniform set of data formats, and a resource pool of hardware data is constructed to realize the function that the number and scale of platforms is irrelevant, the task module can be plug-and-play at any time, and the software can be configured on demand. The resource scheduling of a single platform is achieved through process and thread communication using shared memory, while the resource scheduling of a cross platform is achieved through a network using request and response and subscription and notification. As a result, it can satisfy the development of functional modules in a software-defined mode and gradually improve the intelligence capability of an unmanned swarm. Based on the above architecture, the overall framework of the autonomous navigation system and the collaborative control system has been successfully established. Finally, a hardware-in-the-loop simulation environment is constructed, and the integration and verification of the proposed distributed architecture is carried out by the cooperative formation experiment, which proves the feasibility of this proposal. © 2023 by the authors.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: Z. Su; China North Artificial Intelligence &amp; Innovation Research Institute, Beijing, 100072, China; email: bitszb@163.com</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85172880525&amp;doi=10.3390%2felectronics12183739&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=822efff450ec3b4399284091a3efc7e8</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sadik, A. R.</author><author>Bolder, B.</author><author>Subasic, P.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A self-adaptive system of systems architecture to enable its ad-hoc scalability</title><secondary-title>ACM International Conference Proceeding Series</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Int. Conf. Proc. Ser.</full-title></periodical><pages>111-118</pages><keywords><keyword>Computer architecture</keyword><keyword>Swarm intelligence</keyword><keyword>Swarm robotics</keyword><keyword>Swarm Robotics</keyword><keyword>Multi agent systems</keyword><keyword>System of systems</keyword><keyword>System-of-systems</keyword><keyword>Secondary batteries</keyword><keyword>Uncertainty</keyword><keyword>Fleet operations</keyword><keyword>Systems-of-systems architecture</keyword><keyword>Vehicle fleets</keyword><keyword>Multi-agents simulations</keyword><keyword>Scalability</keyword><keyword>Automatic mode</keyword><keyword>Holonic architecture</keyword><keyword>Holonic Architecture</keyword><keyword>Manual modes</keyword><keyword>Multi-agent Simulation</keyword><keyword>Self-adaptive system</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-145039992-0 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3596947.3596949</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The concept of System of Systems (SoS) refers to a collection of Constituent Systems (CSs) that interact to deliver an emergent behavior that cannot be achieved by any individual CS on its own. The focus of this research is on the ad-hoc scalability of SoS, meaning that the size of the system can change during operation by adding or removing a CS or changing the size of existing CSs. The Unmanned Vehicle Fleet (UVF) is selected as a practical example to showcase the challenge and solution of ad-hoc scalability. UVF has various applications in fields such as search and rescue, intelligent transportation and mobility, but it operates in a dynamic environment that is prone to uncertainties like changing missions, increasing range and capacity, UV failures, and battery requirements. The proposed solution to overcome these uncertainties is a self-adaptive system that can dynamically change the UVF architecture in real-time, allowing for upscaling or downscaling the size of the UVF. The Mission Control Center (MCC) can control this change either through fully-automatic mode based on performance criteria like battery utilization and communication traffic, or through manual mode where the operator makes the decision. A multi-agent environment and rule management engine are implemented to simulate the UVF behavior and validate the proposed solution in both automatic and manual modes. © 2023 Copyright held by the owner/author(s). Publication rights licensed to ACM.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: A.R. Sadik; Honda Research Institute Europe, Germany; email: ahmed.sadik@honda-ri.de; Conference name: 7th International Conference on Intelligent Systems, Metaheuristics and Swarm Intelligence, ISMSI 2023; Conference date: 23 April 2023 through 24 April 2023; Conference code: 191251&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: ACM Int. Conf. Proc. Ser.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: ACM Int. Conf. Proc. Ser.</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85168903239&amp;doi=10.1145%2f3596947.3596949&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=7bf09b2baf76d301d06ec10633495895</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>ACM Int. Conf. Proc. Ser.</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Shahin, K.</author><author>Rotta, R.</author><author>Archila, O.</author><author>Mykytyn, P.</author><author>Nattke, M.</author><author>Reichenbach, M.</author><author>Nolte, J.</author><author>Natarov, R.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Modular Communication Architecture for Adaptive UAV Swarms</title><secondary-title>2023 IEEE International Conference on Omni-Layer Intelligent Systems, COINS 2023</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Int. Conf. Omni-Layer Intell. Syst., COINS</full-title></periodical><keywords><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Modulars</keyword><keyword>Network architecture</keyword><keyword>Autonomous vehicles</keyword><keyword>Communication architectures</keyword><keyword>autonomous aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>Disaster monitoring</keyword><keyword>Farms</keyword><keyword>Industrial disasters</keyword><keyword>Industrial logistics</keyword><keyword>Normalized difference vegetation index</keyword><keyword>Small unmanned aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>swarm flight</keyword><keyword>Swarm flight</keyword><keyword>vehicular networks</keyword><keyword>Vehicular networks</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>979-835034647-3 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/COINS57856.2023.10189245</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Small Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) have vast application potential from industrial logistics and disaster monitoring to smart farming, for example, to create maps with Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI) cameras and AI-based image classification or the precision spot application of fertilizers. Operating multiple UAVs in parallel, including those with different specializations, enables efficient coverage of large areas. While existing research focused mainly on predefined flight formations for swarms or autonomous missions for single UAVs, the focus of this work is on multiple UAVs with individually adaptable missions. We derive communication system requirements from swarm coordination algorithms and present a respective design. The resulting modular architecture enables future research on autonomous adaptive UAV swarms and their use as flying sensor platforms.  © 2023 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Conference name: 2023 IEEE International Conference on Omni-Layer Intelligent Systems, COINS 2023; Conference date: 23 July 2023 through 25 July 2023; Conference code: 191147&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Int. Conf. Omni-Layer Intell. Syst., COINS&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Int. Conf. Omni-Layer Intell. Syst., COINS</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85167874548&amp;doi=10.1109%2fCOINS57856.2023.10189245&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=2d6ddd417090b9dbdefc96e91c3f224c</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>IEEE Int. Conf. Omni-Layer Intell. Syst., COINS</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Si, J.</author><author>Hao, M.</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Wang Y</author><author>Sun X</author><author>Li H</author><author>Xie F</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Online Weapon-target Assignment based on Distributed Auction Mechanism</title><secondary-title>Journal of Physics: Conference Series</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>J. Phys. Conf. Ser.</full-title></periodical><volume>2456</volume><keywords><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Motion planning</keyword><keyword>Combinatorial optimization</keyword><keyword>Particle swarm optimization (PSO)</keyword><keyword>Vehicle to vehicle communications</keyword><keyword>Unknown environments</keyword><keyword>Clustering algorithms</keyword><keyword>Large-scales</keyword><keyword>Assignment algorithms</keyword><keyword>Auctions mechanisms</keyword><keyword>Combinatorial optimization algorithm</keyword><keyword>Distributed Auctions</keyword><keyword>Particle swarm optimization algorithm</keyword><keyword>Task flows</keyword><keyword>Weapon-target assignment</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Physics</publisher><isbn>17426588 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1088/1742-6596/2456/1/012044</electronic-resource-num><abstract>To solve the problem of online weapon-target assignment (OWTA) in the integration of large-scale search and attack in unknown environment, an OWTA algorithm based on distributed auction mechanism is presented. Aiming at the problem that the traditional combinatorial optimization algorithm needs to set up the global battlefield situation in advance, considering the consumability of resources in the attack process, the integrated search and attack task flow is established. Considering the communication restricted environment, the unmanned aerial vehicles (uavs) are grouped, with centralized architecture within the group and distributed structure between the groups, and the corresponding distributed auction mechanism is constructed to achieve OWTA within the communication range limited. In order to solve the problem that it is difficult to ensure the time consistency of the coordinated attack target, a dubins cooperative path planning based on cooperative particle swarm optimization (CPSO) algorithm is proposed. Particle swarm optimization algorithm is used to adjust the radius of the dubins path of each bomb, so that the uav in the same group can hit the target simultaneously without collision and have the shortest flight range. The simulation results show that the designed distributed auction algorithm takes into account the consumption of attack resources, and quickly redistributes the firepower to the new targets in the dynamic uncertain environment, which ensures the maximization of the execution efficiency of the multi-machine cluster fire allocation task.  © Published under licence by IOP Publishing Ltd.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: M. Hao; Sci. and Technology on Complex System Control and Intelligent Agent Cooperation Laboratory, Beijing, Beijing, China; email: hmrhit@163.com; Conference name: 2nd International Conference on Robotics, Automation and Intelligent Control, ICRAIC 2022; Conference date: 9 December 2022 through 11 December 2022; Conference code: 187603&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: J. Phys. Conf. Ser.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: J. Phys. Conf. Ser.</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85152631744&amp;doi=10.1088%2f1742-6596%2f2456%2f1%2f012044&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=68c6a57315f24feb69a21fa8e1e42115</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>J. Phys. Conf. Ser.</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mahmoud, H. H.</author><author>Al-Shammari, M. K. M.</author><author>Amran, G. A.</author><author>Eldin, E. T.</author><author>Alareqi, A. R.</author><author>Ghamry, N. A.</author><author>ALnajjar, E.</author><author>Almosharea, E.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Submarine Hunter: Efficient and Secure Multi-Type Unmanned Vehicles</title><secondary-title>Computers, Materials and Continua</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Computers, Materials and Continua</full-title><abbr-1>Comput. Mater. Continua</abbr-1></periodical><pages>573-589</pages><volume>76</volume><number>1</number><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Swarm intelligence</keyword><keyword>Network layers</keyword><keyword>unmanned aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>Unmanned vehicles</keyword><keyword>unmanned underwater vehicles</keyword><keyword>Peer to peer networks</keyword><keyword>Cyber security</keyword><keyword>anti-submarine warfare</keyword><keyword>Antisubmarine warfare</keyword><keyword>Artificial intelligence technologies</keyword><keyword>Coastal cities</keyword><keyword>dragonfly algorithm</keyword><keyword>Dragonfly algorithm</keyword><keyword>High altitude unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>high altitude unmanned aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>re-fragmentation</keyword><keyword>Re-fragmentation</keyword><keyword>Submarines</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>15462218 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.32604/cmc.2023.039363</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Utilizing artificial intelligence (AI) to protect smart coastal cities has become a novel vision for scientific and industrial institutions. One of these AI technologies is using efficient and secure multi-environment Unmanned Vehicles (UVs) for anti-submarine attacks. This study’s contribution is the early detection of a submarine assault employing hybrid environment UVs that are controlled using swarm optimization and secure the information in between UVs using a decentralized cybersecurity strategy. The Dragonfly Algorithm is used for the orientation and clustering of the UVs in the optimization approach, and the Re-fragmentation strategy is used in the Network layer of the TCP/IP protocol as a cybersecurity solution. The research’s noteworthy findings demonstrate UVs’ logistical capability to promptly detect the target and address the problem while securely keeping the drone’s geographical information. The results suggest that detecting the submarine early increases the likelihood of averting a collision. The dragonfly strategy of sensing the position of the submersible and aggregating around it demonstrates the reliability of swarm intelligence in increasing access efficiency. Securing communication between Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) improves the level of secrecy necessary for the task. The swarm navigation is based on a peer-to-peer system, which allows each UAV to access information from its peers. This, in turn, helps the UAVs to determine the best route to take and to avoid collisions with other UAVs. The dragonfly strategy also increases the speed of the mission by minimizing the time spent finding the target. © 2023 Tech Science Press. All rights reserved.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: G.A. Amran; Department of Management Science and Engineering, Dalian University of Technology, Dalian, Liaoning, 116024, China; email: jehad.westran@gmail.com; E.T. Eldin; Faculty of Engineering and Technology, Future University in Egypt, New Cairo, 11835, Egypt; email: elsayed.tageldin@fue.edu.eg</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85164283161&amp;doi=10.32604%2fcmc.2023.039363&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=bf50446db5b56ba4b51011c0e34059fb</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Pereira, P. H. M.</author><author>Pasandideh, F.</author><author>Basso, M.</author><author>Da Costa, J. P. J.</author><author>Pignaton De Freitas, E.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Design and Deployment of an Efficient Communication Service for Multi-UAV Systems</title><secondary-title>2023 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2023</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Int. Conf. Unmanned Aircr. Syst., ICUAS</full-title></periodical><pages>753-760</pages><keywords><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Cooperative communication</keyword><keyword>Energy utilization</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle systems</keyword><keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword><keyword>Communications protocols</keyword><keyword>Communication service</keyword><keyword>Efficient communications</keyword><keyword>Electric power transmission</keyword><keyword>Electronic data interchange</keyword><keyword>High rate</keyword><keyword>Information technology and communications</keyword><keyword>Low energy consumption</keyword><keyword>Microelectronics</keyword><keyword>Processing capacities</keyword><keyword>Small devices</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>979-835031037-5 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICUAS57906.2023.10156133</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Recent advances in the areas of microelectronics, information technology, and communication protocols have made possible the development of smaller devices, with increasing processing capacity and low energy consumption. This context contributed to the growth of applications based on the use of one or multiple Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs). Networks composed of multiple UAVs are being used as a matter of improving the effectiveness, accuracy, and minoring the time of missions. However, these applications demand a high rate of data exchange, such as the localization information of each UAV, which can be a challenge, due to the limited transmission power of certain drone platforms. This article proposes a communication service for multi-UAV systems based on dividing the UAV-fleet into groups using the communication protocol IEEE 802.11 ac. Each group has its local network, whose participants can be chosen based on the UAV's localization or task assignment. UAVs/Drones within the same group constantly communicate, exchanging pose information and specific mission-related data. On the other hand, communication between different groups is only established by messenger drones in pre-set times. The communication service from its detailed implementation to its simulated and field validation experiments is presented in this paper. The results of three different network topologies provide evidence that the proposed communication service for multi-UAV is efficient and can be used for drone cooperative missions. © 2023 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: E. Pignaton De Freitas; Federal University of Rio Grande Do sul (UFRGS), Graduate Program in Electrical Engineering, Porto Alegre, 91.501-970, Brazil; email: epfreitas@inf.ufrgs.br; Conference name: 2023 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2023; Conference date: 6 June 2023 through 9 June 2023; Conference code: 190024&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Int. Conf. Unmanned Aircr. Syst., ICUAS&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Int. Conf. Unmanned Aircr. Syst., ICUAS</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85165641006&amp;doi=10.1109%2fICUAS57906.2023.10156133&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=326a34f1f424b7f0f5bb66407529180f</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>Int. Conf. Unmanned Aircr. Syst., ICUAS</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Aadil, Farhan</author><author>Song, Oh-young</author><author>Mushtaq, Mahreen</author><author>Maqsood, Muazzam</author><author>Sheikh, Sadia Ejaz</author><author>Baber, Junaid</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An efficient cluster optimization framework for internet of things (IoT) based Wireless Body Area Networks</title><secondary-title>JOURNAL OF ENTERPRISE INFORMATION MANAGEMENT</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>JOURNAL OF ENTERPRISE INFORMATION MANAGEMENT</full-title><abbr-1>J. Enterp. Inf. Manag.</abbr-1></periodical><pages>839-860</pages><volume>36</volume><number>3</number><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Evolutionary algorithms</keyword><keyword>Clustering</keyword><keyword>ALGORITHM</keyword><keyword>SENSOR NETWORKS</keyword><keyword>ROUTING PROTOCOL</keyword><keyword>Grasshoppers optimization</keyword><keyword>MULTIOBJECTIVE OPTIMIZATION</keyword><keyword>Wireless body area networks</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>APR 24 2023</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1741-0398, 1758-7409</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1108/JEIM-02-2020-0075</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Purpose Wireless Body Area Network (WBAN) technology envisions a network in which sensors continuously operate on and obtained critical physical and physiological readings. Sensors deployed in WBANs have restricted resources such as battery energy, computing power and bandwidth. We can utilize these resources efficiently. By devising a mechanism that is energy efficient with following characteristics, i.e. computational complexity is less, routing overhead is minimized, and throughput will be maximum. A lot of work has been done in this area but still WBAN faces some challenges like mobility, network lifetime, transmission range, heterogeneous environment, and limited resources. In the present years well, contemplative studies have been made through a large body to reach some holistic points pertaining to the energy consumption in WBAN. Thus we/put forward appropriate algorithm for energy efficiency which can vividly corroborate the advances in this specific domain. We have also focused on various aspects and phases of the studies like study computational complexity, routing overhead and throughput type of characteristics. There is still a room for improvement to get the desired energy optimization in WBAN. The network performance mainly relies upon the algorithm used for optimization process. In this work, we intended to develop an energy optimization algorithm for energy consumption in WBAN which is based on evolutionary algorithms for inter-BAN communications using cluster-based routing protocol. Design/methodology/approach In this paper we propose a meta heuristics algorithm Goa to solve the optimization problem in WBAN. Grasshopper is an insect. Generally, this insect is viewed individually and creating large swarm in nature. Figure 5 shows the individual grasshoppers' primitive patterns in swarm. Figure 7 depicts the pseudo code of Goa. In Goa, experiments are done to view the behavior of grasshoppers in swarm. How they gradually move towards the stationary and mobile target. Through experimentation it is conceived that swarm gradually converge towards their target. Another interesting pattern related to convergence of grasshopper is that it slowly towards its target. This shows that grasshopper does not trapped in local optima. In starting iterations of exploration process Goa, search globally and in last iterations it searches local optima. Goa makes the exploration and exploitation process balanced while solving challenging optimization problems. Findings Energy efficiency is achieved in the optimization process of cluster formation process. As the use of proposed algorithm Goa creates the optimal number of clusters. Shorter cluster lifetime means more times clustering procedure is called. It increases the network computational cost and the communication overhead. Experimentation results show that proposed Goa algorithm performs well. We compare the results of Goa with existing optimization Algorithms ACO and MFO. Results are generated using MATLAB. Originality/value A lot of work has done for the sake of energy optimization in WBAN. Many algorithms are proposed in past for energy optimization of WBAN. All of them have some strengths and weaknesses. In this paper we propose a nature inspired algorithm Goa. We use the Goa algorithm for the sake of energy optimization in WBAN.</abstract><language>English</language></record></records></xml>