<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><records><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>M. -T. Lee</author><author>S. -T. Kuo</author><author>Y. -R. Chen</author><author>M. -L. Chuang</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>UAV Swarm Real-Time Rerouting by Edge Computing under a Changing Environment</title><secondary-title>Proceedings of the 3rd IEEE Eurasia Conference on IOT, Communication and Engineering 2021, ECICE 2021</secondary-title><tertiary-title>Proceedings of the 3rd IEEE Eurasia Conference on IOT, Communication and Engineering 2021, ECICE 2021</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>3rd IEEE Eurasia Conference on IOT, Communication and Engineering, ECICE 2021, October 29, 2021 - October 31, 2021</full-title></periodical><pages>6-9</pages><keywords><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>Rock mechanics</keyword><keyword>Aircraft control</keyword><keyword>UAV swarm</keyword><keyword>edge computing</keyword><keyword>Edge computing</keyword><keyword>Real- time</keyword><keyword>Autonomous control</keyword><keyword>Dynamic programming</keyword><keyword>Cost functions</keyword><keyword>Formation flight</keyword><keyword>Changing environment</keyword><keyword>Computing system</keyword><keyword>D</keyword><keyword>formation flight</keyword><keyword>Lite</keyword><keyword>Research use</keyword><keyword>Tabu search</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>29-31 Oct. 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-166544516-0 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ECICE52819.2021.9645660</electronic-resource-num><abstract>To allow UAVs to equip a higher level of autonomous control, this research uses edge computing systems to replace the ground control station commonly used to control UAVs. Since the GCS belongs to the central control architecture, the edge computing system of the distributed architecture gives the drones more flexibility in dealing with changing environmental conditions, allowing them to autonomously and instantly plan their flight path, fly in formation, or even avoid obstacles. Broadcast communications are used to realize UAV-to-UAV communications for allocating tasks among a swarm of UAVs and ensuring each individual collaborates as an integrated member of the group. The dynamic path programming problem for the UAV swarm mission uses a 2-phase Tabu search with the 2-Opt exchange method and A∗ search as the path programming algorithm. Distance is taken as a cost function for path programming. We then increase and expand the turning-points of no-fly zones based on drone fleet coverage, thus preventing drones from entering prohibited areas. Whereas previous work mostly only considers single no-fly zones, this approach accounts for multiple restricted areas, ensuring that a UAV swarm can complete its assigned task without violating no-fly zones. A drone encountering an obstacle while traveling along the route set by the algorithm will update the map information in real-time, allowing for an instant recharting of the optimal path to the goal as a reverse search using the D∗ Lite algorithm. © 2021 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Conference name: 3rd IEEE Eurasia Conference on IOT, Communication and Engineering, ECICE 2021; Conference date: 29 October 2021 through 31 October 2021; Conference code: 175835&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 3rd IEEE Eurasia Conference on IOT, Communication and Engineering, ECICE 2021, October 29, 2021 - October 31, 2021&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 IEEE 3rd Eurasia Conference on IOT, Communication and Engineering (ECICE)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proc. IEEE Eurasia Conf. IOT, Commun. Eng., ECICE&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 3rd IEEE Eurasia Conference on IOT, Communication and Engineering, ECICE 2021, October 29, 2021 - October 31, 2021</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85124249276&amp;doi=10.1109%2fECICE52819.2021.9645660&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=dc891032b6f8fd6b7d7da0490cc522f6</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ECICE52819.2021.9645660</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Yunlin, Taiwan</custom1><custom3>3rd IEEE Eurasia Conference on IOT, Communication and Engineering, ECICE 2021, October 29, 2021 - October 31, 2021</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>J. Wubben</author><author>I. Catalán</author><author>M. Lurbe</author><author>F. Fabra</author><author>F. J. Martinez</author><author>C. T. Calafate</author><author>J. -C. Cano</author><author>P. Manzoni</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Providing resilience to UAV swarms following planned missions</title><secondary-title>2020 29th International Conference on Computer Communications and Networks (ICCCN)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2020 29th International Conference on Computer Communications and Networks (ICCCN)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-6</pages><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>3-6 Aug. 2020</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2637-9430</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICCCN49398.2020.9209634</electronic-resource-num><abstract>As we experience an unprecedented growth in the field of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs), more and more applications keep arising due to the combination of low cost and flexibility provided by these flying devices, especially those of the multirrotor type. Within this field, solutions where several UAVs team-up to create a swarm are gaining momentum as they enable to perform more sophisticated tasks, or accelerate task execution compared to the single-UAV alternative. However, advanced solutions based on UAV swarms still lack significant advancements and validation in real environments to facilitate their adoption and deployment. In this paper we take a step ahead in this direction by proposing a solution that improves the resilience of swarm flights, focusing on handling the loss of the swarm leader, which is typically the most critical condition to be faced. Experiments using our UAV emulation tool (ArduSim) evidence the correctness of the protocol under adverse circumstances, and highlight that swarm members are able to seamlessly switch to an alternative leader when necessary, introducing a negligible delay in the process in most cases, while keeping this delay within a few seconds even in worst-case conditions.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 29th International Conference on Computer Communications and Networks (ICCCN)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 29th International Conference on Computer Communications and Networks (ICCCN)</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49791/J. Wubben et al. - 2020 - Providing resilience to UAV swarms following plann.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><custom3>2020 29th International Conference on Computer Communications and Networks (ICCCN)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>P. -B. Bok</author><author>K. S. Kohls</author><author>D. Behnke</author><author>C. Wietfeld</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Distributed Flow Permission Inspection for Mission-Critical Communication of Untrusted Autonomous Vehicles</title><secondary-title>2014 IEEE 80th Vehicular Technology Conference (VTC2014-Fall)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2014 IEEE 80th Vehicular Technology Conference (VTC2014-Fall)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-6</pages><dates><year>2014</year><pub-dates><date>14-17 Sept. 2014</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1090-3038</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/VTCFall.2014.6965939</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Swarms of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) and Unmanned Ground Vehicles (UGVs) are used for cooperative sensing, clarification and communication relaying in disaster situations and, thereby, allow to reduce jeopardizing the health of rescue personnel. Having meshed interconnection, a swarm maintains a communication network dedicated for applications with context-dependent performance requirements that require reliable traffic classification and conditioning. Nevertheless, these systems are vulnerable because UAVs/UGVs may act incorrectly resulting in an erroneous network behavior which may affect the performance of mission-critical flows. This is a major problem if a couple of untrusted UAVs and UGVs from different rescue organizations are connected. In this paper, the reliability of traffic conditioning within untrusted swarms is enhanced by the Distributed Flow Permission Inspection (DiFPIN) scheme. DiFPIN is used to verify the flow classification to circumvent the usage of erroneous entities on the transmission path. Thereby, the negative impairment of mission-critical flows can be reduced.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2014 IEEE 80th Vehicular Technology Conference (VTC2014-Fall)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2014 IEEE 80th Vehicular Technology Conference (VTC2014-Fall)</research-notes><custom3>2014 IEEE 80th Vehicular Technology Conference (VTC2014-Fall)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>A. Lakas</author><author>A. N. Belkacem</author><author>S. Al Hassani</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An Adaptive Multi-clustered Scheme for Autonomous UAV Swarms</title><secondary-title>16th IEEE International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing Conference (IEEE IWCMC)</secondary-title><tertiary-title>2020 International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing, IWCMC 2020</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>16th IEEE International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing Conference, IWCMC 2020, June 15, 2020 - June 19, 2020</full-title></periodical><pages>1567-1572</pages><keywords><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Military applications</keyword><keyword>Military vehicles</keyword><keyword>UAV swarm</keyword><keyword>Autonomous unmanned aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>Motion planning</keyword><keyword>Air navigation</keyword><keyword>Mobile computing</keyword><keyword>Broadcast protocols</keyword><keyword>Human intervention</keyword><keyword>Swarm technology</keyword><keyword>Intelligent swarm</keyword><keyword>leader-follower</keyword><keyword>Leader-follower approach</keyword><keyword>multi-cluster</keyword><keyword>Navigation and path planning</keyword><keyword>Surrounding obstacles</keyword><keyword>swarm stability</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>15-19 June 2020</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-172813129-0 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/IWCMC48107.2020.9148449</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Swarm technology for autonomous unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) has gained popularity in the last few years due to their potential for civilian and military applications. Intelligent swarm systems are very efficient at solving group-level problems and their capability to accomplish complex missions with no or little human intervention. One of the most challenging problems is operating in environments with surrounding obstacles such as buildings, thus, often obstructing inter-UAV communication. A UAV swarm is required to maintain continuous communication between its members and preserve the stability of its formation while flying towards an ultimate goal. In this paper we propose MSCS, a new cooperative and adaptive scheme for multi-clustered autonomous UAV swarms. This schemes allows several UAVs operating in a swarm formation to coordinate their navigation and path planning operations by using an adaptive multi-clustered leader-follower approach. The swarm members follow a dynamically elected leader based on the UAV with best fit to lead the swarm towards the destination. The coordination of the UAVs is achieved through SBP (Swarm Broadcast Protocol), a single-hop broadcast UAV-to-UAV (U2U) communication protocol, which allows swarm members to exchange information about their current location and their local cluster leader. We present a set of performance results, which show that this scheme contributes efficiently at maintaining the swarm formation's stability at acceptable density and disconnection ratio. © 2020 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 9; Conference name: 16th IEEE&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing Conference, IWCMC 2020; Conference date: 15 June 2020 through 19 June 2020; Conference code: 162085&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 16th IEEE International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing Conference, IWCMC 2020, June 15, 2020 - June 19, 2020&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 16TH INTERNATIONAL WIRELESS COMMUNICATIONS &amp; MOBILE COMPUTING CONFERENCE, IWCMC&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing (IWCMC)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Int. Wirel. Commun. Mob. Comput., IWCMC&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 16th IEEE International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing Conference, IWCMC 2020, June 15, 2020 - June 19, 2020</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85089706012&amp;doi=10.1109%2fIWCMC48107.2020.9148449&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=982eda5c280567c74dba5360c073b41a</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/IWCMC48107.2020.9148449</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Limassol, Cyprus</custom1><custom3>16th IEEE International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing Conference, IWCMC 2020, June 15, 2020 - June 19, 2020</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>F. G. Tinetti</author><author>O. C. V. Riveros</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Combining Technologies for Aiding Search Missions with Drones</title><secondary-title>2021 International Conference on Computational Science and Computational Intelligence (CSCI)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2021 International Conference on Computational Science and Computational Intelligence (CSCI)</full-title></periodical><pages>1617-1622</pages><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>15-17 Dec. 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/CSCI54926.2021.00013</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper presents the combination of technologies in an application for aiding search missions. Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV), wireless communications, and image processing and classification technologies are combined for generating warnings to an operator in a search mission. Thus, the UAV would be used to cover a specific ground area communicating images the system should be able to classify. In case a positive image is classified (i.e., one with the object/s being searched for), an operator is warned so that the final decision is made by an expert. In this way, the mostly bored task of looking at images without object being looked for is avoided, and the expert attention could be focused on images with a high probability of having the object/s being looked for. A cloud service is used for image classification (IBM Watson) along with a previously proposed UAV system architecture and a low-cost drone SDK. A proof of concept is described, giving implementation details, and preliminary results. Obtained results show that the general system is a viable solution and set a starting point for enhancing several subsystems for better performance.</abstract><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;Not really architecture&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 International Conference on Computational Science and Computational Intelligence (CSCI)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 International Conference on Computational Science and Computational Intelligence (CSCI)</research-notes><custom3>2021 International Conference on Computational Science and Computational Intelligence (CSCI)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Z. Yuan</author><author>Y. Yang</author><author>P. Ying</author><author>J. Jiao</author><author>X. Ma</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Modular Swarm UAV-aided Data Collection for WSNs relying on Cooperative Communication and Path Planning</title><secondary-title>2021 IEEE International Conference on Computing (ICOCO)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2021 IEEE International Conference on Computing (ICOCO)</full-title></periodical><pages>282-286</pages><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>17-19 Nov. 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICOCO53166.2021.9673496</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Using Swarm UAVs to collect feedback information from sensor nodes can greatly improve the coverage rate and energy efficiency of Wireless Sensor Networks (WSNs), especially for environmental monitoring in inaccessible areas. Based on a modular swarm UAV platform and randomly distributed sensor network, this paper devotes to design a clustering algorithm which considers the distance constraints of sensor communication. Then, relying on the cluster results, we propose an Ant Colony Optimization (ACO)-based cooperative path planning for modular UAVs, with multiple constraints brought by characters of separate/recombine modes. Simulation results indicate that the proposed clustering algorithm and cooperative path planning is capable of effectively realizing the adaptive clustering and improving the total information collected by the UAV-aided WSNs.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 IEEE International Conference on Computing (ICOCO)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 IEEE International Conference on Computing (ICOCO)</research-notes><custom3>2021 IEEE International Conference on Computing (ICOCO)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>H. Lumbantoruan</author><author>K. Adachi</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Trajectory and Communication Protocol for Efficient Data Collecting in UAV-Enabled WSN</title><secondary-title>2020 International Conference on Information Networking (ICOIN)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2020 International Conference on Information Networking (ICOIN)</full-title></periodical><pages>348-353</pages><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>7-10 Jan. 2020</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1976-7684</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICOIN48656.2020.9016615</electronic-resource-num><abstract>A low power consumption and efficient communication scheme is crucial to boost the data collecting effectivity in a WSN (Wireless Sensor Network) with a large number of SNs (Sensor Nodes). To enhance the received signal power and avoid frequent signal collision, RADMA (Rotational Angle Division Multiple Access) has been proposed. In RADMA, a UAV-BS (Unmanned Aerial Vehicle-Base Station) equipped with ULA (Uniformly Linear Array antenna) is deployed as the mobile data collector, To improve the performance of RADMA when serving a larger area, it is required to design an effective trajectory to dynamically deploy the UAV-BS within the area. In this paper, a simple UAV-BS trajectory decision method based on sectorized K-means clustering is proposed to provide uniform QoS (Quality-of-Service) among all SNs. First, the area is sectorized with equal sector size. Then, the initial centroid coordinate of each cluster is randomly generated within each sector area to avoid biased centroids. Finally, the trajectory is formed by connecting the centroids of the SNs clusters. The numerical results have validated that combining RADMA with sectorized k-means clustering-based trajectory enables all SNs to transmit all the data within a predetermined mission time and with low transmission energy.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 International Conference on Information Networking (ICOIN)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 International Conference on Information Networking (ICOIN)</research-notes><custom3>2020 International Conference on Information Networking (ICOIN)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>F. Fabra</author><author>W. Zamora</author><author>P. Reyes</author><author>C. T. Calafate</author><author>J. -C. Cano</author><author>P. Manzoni</author><author>E. Hernandez-Orallo</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An UAV Swarm Coordination Protocol Supporting Planned Missions</title><secondary-title>2019 28th International Conference on Computer Communication and Networks (ICCCN)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2019 28th International Conference on Computer Communication and Networks (ICCCN)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-9</pages><keywords><keyword>UAV</keyword><keyword>swarm</keyword><keyword>UNMANNED AERIAL VEHICLES</keyword><keyword>ArduSim</keyword><keyword>flight coordination</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2019</year><pub-dates><date>29 July-1 Aug. 2019</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>IEEE</publisher><isbn>978-1-72811-856-7</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICCCN.2019.8847043</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) are being widely used as a valuable tool in critical situations, especially when the access to the target area is difficult or hazardous. In these situations, a swarm of UAVs can provide additional benefits by covering larger areas, thereby speeding up the fulfillment of a mission, or by carrying heavier loads that a single UAV would not support. In this paper we present MUSCOP, a protocol that allows a set of UAVs to properly synchronize their flight in the fulfillment of planned missions. The results obtained show that MUSCOP achieves a high degree of swarm cohesion even in the presence of channel losses, introducing minimum synchronization delays and low position offset errors compared to an ideal scenario.</abstract><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;Duplicate of DOI: 10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2987983&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 28th International Conference on Computer Communication and Networks (ICCCN)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 28th International Conference on Computer Communication and Networks (ICCCN)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 28TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMPUTER COMMUNICATION AND NETWORKS (ICCCN)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 28TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMPUTER COMMUNICATION AND NETWORKS (ICCCN)</research-notes><language>English</language><custom1>New York</custom1><custom3>2019 28th International Conference on Computer Communication and Networks (ICCCN)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>V. Autefage</author><author>S. Chaumette</author><author>D. Magoni</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Mission-Oriented Service Discovery Mechanism for Highly Dynamic Autonomous Swarms of Unmanned Systems</title><secondary-title>2015 IEEE International Conference on Autonomic Computing</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2015 IEEE International Conference on Autonomic Computing</full-title></periodical><pages>31-40</pages><dates><year>2015</year><pub-dates><date>7-10 July 2015</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICAC.2015.28</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Over the past few years, many research projects have begun to focus on swarms of mobile unmanned systems (e.g., Drones, ground robots) globally referred as UMS. These systems, because of the many sensors and actuators they can embed, are suitable for autonomous missions in 3D (Dull, Dirty and Dangerous) environments for instance. However, embedding a large number of capabilities in all of members of a swarm is expensive in terms of cost, weight and energy consumption. Thus, it is usually more efficient to embed only a single or a few capabilities within each UMS. It then becomes necessary to provide a discovery mechanism built into the swarm in order to allow its members to share their capabilities and to collaborate for achieving a global mission. These shared capabilities are called services. In this paper, we propose a new service discovery system called AMiRALE for Asynchronous Missions Relay for Autonomous and Lively Entities dedicated to highly volatile, autonomous and mobile swarms of UMS. Our solution is independent of both nodes' mobility and connectivity patterns. Moreover, it supports heterogeneous swarms and degraded conditions of operation (i.e., Message loss, UMS loss and disconnected network). It is also totally decentralized and enables both discovery and service usage. We provide a description of the theoretical model of our AMiRALE system as well as several simulation results obtained from a park cleaning scenario.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2015 IEEE International Conference on Autonomic Computing&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2015 IEEE International Conference on Autonomic Computing</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49796/V. Autefage et al. - 2015 - A Mission-Oriented Service Discovery Mechanism for.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><custom3>2015 IEEE International Conference on Autonomic Computing</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>J. Goričanec</author><author>A. Ivanović</author><author>L. Marković</author><author>I. Pavlak</author><author>S. Bogdan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Civil infrastructure data acquisition in urban environments based on multi-UAV mission</title><secondary-title>2021 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2021</secondary-title><tertiary-title>2021 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2021</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2021 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2021, June 15, 2021 - June 18, 2021</full-title></periodical><pages>542-551</pages><keywords><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Data acquisition</keyword><keyword>Multi agent systems</keyword><keyword>Urban environments</keyword><keyword>Proposed architectures</keyword><keyword>Autonomous agents</keyword><keyword>Situation awareness</keyword><keyword>Civil infrastructures</keyword><keyword>Data representations</keyword><keyword>Human Machine Interface</keyword><keyword>Mission execution</keyword><keyword>Performance degradation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>15-18 June 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-073813115-3 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICUAS51884.2021.9476735</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Increased capabilities of modern unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) in terms of autonomy and payload operations lead towards development of multi-agent UAV systems. While the multi-UAV systems have a great potential in many different scenarios, increasing complexity of missions gave raise to a new set of problems. Some of them include high workload periods of a single operator supervising multiple agents, loss of the situation awareness, increased amount of the data generated by the system and problems in communication channels between the operator and UAVs. All of them could lead to performance degradation in the mission execution or even critical failures of system elements. In general, there are two aspects that help to avoid or at least to decrease mentioned problems - mission planning and human-machine interface (HMI) design. In this paper, we mainly address the mission planning aspect and only briefly present an HMI design that allows simultaneous handling of three UAVs in civil infrastructure data acquisition missions. The proposed interface, among the standard telemetry data, includes data download/upload from/to external services, a trajectory planner and the acquired data representation. The proposed architecture has been tested in a simulation and in a real environment.  © 2021 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 1; Conference name: 2021 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2021; Conference date: 15 June 2021 through 18 June 2021; Conference code: 170495&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2021, June 15, 2021 - June 18, 2021&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Int. Conf. Unmanned Aircr. Syst., ICUAS&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2021, June 15, 2021 - June 18, 2021</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85111440512&amp;doi=10.1109%2fICUAS51884.2021.9476735&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=69f5d2cda3fec3172858c058ee8795a3</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICUAS51884.2021.9476735</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Athens, Greece</custom1><custom3>2021 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2021, June 15, 2021 - June 18, 2021</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>U. C. Cabuk</author><author>M. Tosun</author><author>O. Dagdeviren</author><author>Y. Ozturk</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An Architectural Design for Autonomous and Networked Drones</title><secondary-title>MILCOM 2022 - 2022 IEEE Military Communications Conference (MILCOM)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>MILCOM 2022 - 2022 IEEE Military Communications Conference (MILCOM)</full-title></periodical><pages>962-967</pages><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>28 Nov.-2 Dec. 2022</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2155-7586</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/MILCOM55135.2022.10017877</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Drone technology is evolving rapidly, offering support for many new applications every day. Off-the-shelf drone products accessible at reasonable costs are enabling new applications and research directions from crowd management, product delivery, and smart cities to security and military applications. The potential of autonomous swarm missions opens up new research avenues; however, off-the-shelf drone products, as well as most commercial projects, lack features that are required by autonomous collective multi drone missions. One potential reason is that there is no consensus on how to develop drones with cooperative operation capacity systemically. This study suggests a generalized device architecture concerning both hardware and software organization to aid developers of cooperative drones designed for multi-drone missions. The proposed architecture grants autonomy and cooperation within a swarm. An additional solution is also provided to enable ad-hoc networking for drones when the drone platform does not natively support it. The architecture is developed and deployed on ModalAI VOXL m500 developer drone to achieve cooperative swarm sensing and is validated through use cases.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: MILCOM 2022 - 2022 IEEE Military Communications Conference (MILCOM)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: MILCOM 2022 - 2022 IEEE Military Communications Conference (MILCOM)</research-notes><custom3>MILCOM 2022 - 2022 IEEE Military Communications Conference (MILCOM)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Á. Calvo</author><author>G. Silano</author><author>J. Capitán</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Mission Planning and Execution in Heterogeneous Teams of Aerial Robots supporting Power Line Inspection Operations</title><secondary-title>2022 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2022</secondary-title><tertiary-title>2022 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2022</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2022 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2022, June 21, 2022 - June 24, 2022</full-title></periodical><pages>1644-1649</pages><keywords><keyword>Planning and execution</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Forestry</keyword><keyword>Motion planning</keyword><keyword>Multi UAV</keyword><keyword>Multi-UAV system</keyword><keyword>UAV systems</keyword><keyword>Robot programming</keyword><keyword>Vehicle to vehicle communications</keyword><keyword>Task planning</keyword><keyword>Intelligent robots</keyword><keyword>Inspection</keyword><keyword>Behaviour Trees</keyword><keyword>Behavior Trees</keyword><keyword>Inspection and maintenance</keyword><keyword>Line maintenance</keyword><keyword>Multi-UAV systems</keyword><keyword>Power line inspection and maintenance</keyword><keyword>Power line inspections</keyword><keyword>Task executions</keyword><keyword>Task planning and execution</keyword><keyword>SYSTEMS</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>21-24 June 2022</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-166540593-5 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICUAS54217.2022.9836234</electronic-resource-num><abstract>A software architecture aimed at coordinating a team of heterogeneous aerial vehicles for inspection and maintenance operations in high-voltage power line scenarios is presented in this paper. A hierarchical approach deals with high-level tasks by planning and executing complex missions requiring vehicles to support human operators. A resource-constrained problem allows distributing tasks among the team taking into account vehicles' capabilities and battery constraints. Besides, Behavior Trees (BTs) are in charge of mission execution, triggering replanning operations in case of unforeseen events, such as vehicle faults or communication drop-outs. The feasibility and validity of the approach are showcased through realistic simulations achieved in Gazebo.  © 2022 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 8; Conference name: 2022 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2022; Conference date: 21 June 2022 through 24 June 2022; Conference code: 181377&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2022, June 21, 2022 - June 24, 2022&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON UNMANNED AIRCRAFT SYSTEMS (ICUAS)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Int. Conf. Unmanned Aircr. Syst., ICUAS&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2022, June 21, 2022 - June 24, 2022</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85136155242&amp;doi=10.1109%2fICUAS54217.2022.9836234&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=01957e6256e4b2c69e0f0274edd90d8a</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49799/Á. Calvo et al. - 2022 - Mission Planning and Execution in Heterogeneous Te.pdf</url></pdf-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICUAS54217.2022.9836234</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Dubrovnik, Croatia</custom1><custom3>2022 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems, ICUAS 2022, June 21, 2022 - June 24, 2022</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>S. Misra</author><author>P. K. Deb</author><author>K. Saini</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Dynamic Leader Selection in a Master-Slave Architecture-Based Micro UAV Swarm</title><secondary-title>2021 IEEE Global Communications Conference, GLOBECOM 2021 - Proceedings</secondary-title><tertiary-title>2021 IEEE Global Communications Conference, GLOBECOM 2021 - Proceedings</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2021 IEEE Global Communications Conference, GLOBECOM 2021, December 7, 2021 - December 11, 2021</full-title></periodical><pages>et al.; Huawei; Intel; Qualcomm; Vodafone; ZTE</pages><keywords><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Rock mechanics</keyword><keyword>Internet of things</keyword><keyword>Energy utilization</keyword><keyword>Internet of Things</keyword><keyword>Heuristic methods</keyword><keyword>Architecture-based</keyword><keyword>Unmanned Aerial Vehicles</keyword><keyword>Complex mission</keyword><keyword>Communications modeling</keyword><keyword>Dynamic leader selection</keyword><keyword>Greedy heuristic solution</keyword><keyword>Greedy heuristics</keyword><keyword>Ground base stations</keyword><keyword>Heuristic solutions</keyword><keyword>Information theory</keyword><keyword>Master slave communication</keyword><keyword>Master-slave architecture</keyword><keyword>Scalability</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>7-11 Dec. 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-172818104-2 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/GLOBECOM46510.2021.9685538</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In this paper, we present a method for dynamically selecting leaders in a master-slave communication model in a swarm of micro-Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs). With the growing size of the UAV swarm in complex missions, it becomes a challenge to control them for efficient execution of missions. In a traditional centralized communication model where all UAVs in the swarm are controlled directly through ground control, channel capacity limits the number of UAVs in the swarm which restricts the scalability. In the context of low-power miniature drones, we limit the communication of the ground Base Station (gBS) with only one UAV (leader) which controls the rest of the UAVs (followers). Towards this, we propose a greedy heuristic method for selecting the UAV leader that requires minimal time to communicate with the gBS in real-time. The proposed master-slave model enhances the scalability of the swarm by improving the utilization of channel resources. Simulation results demonstrate that the proposed dynamic leader selection enhances the lifetime of the entire network with a multifold decrease in energy consumption, compared to the state-of-the-art. Additionally, the lifetime of the network also decreases on operating with a single UAV leader. We also observe reductions in delays by almost 60% and an increase in data rate by 50%. © 2021 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 4; Conference name: 2021 IEEE Global Communications Conference, GLOBECOM 2021; Conference date: 7 December 2021 through 11 December 2021; Conference code: 176805&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 IEEE Global Communications Conference (GLOBECOM)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 IEEE GLOBAL COMMUNICATIONS CONFERENCE (GLOBECOM)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 IEEE Global Communications Conference, GLOBECOM 2021, December 7, 2021 - December 11, 2021&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Glob. Commun. Conf., GLOBECOM - Proc.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 IEEE Global Communications Conference, GLOBECOM 2021, December 7, 2021 - December 11, 2021</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85127248715&amp;doi=10.1109%2fGLOBECOM46510.2021.9685538&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=18c3125c0b92241268d75d98c2ada520</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/GLOBECOM46510.2021.9685538</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Madrid, Spain</custom1><custom3>2021 IEEE Global Communications Conference, GLOBECOM 2021, December 7, 2021 - December 11, 2021</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>M. R. Silva</author><author>E. S. Souza</author><author>P. J. Alsina</author><author>H. C. Francisco</author><author>A. A. D. Medeiros</author><author>M. B. Nogueira</author><author>G. G. L. A. de Alburquerque</author><author>J. B. D. Dantas</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Communication network architecture specification for multi-UAV system applied to scanning rocket impact area first results</title><secondary-title>2017 Latin American Robotics Symposium (LARS) and 2017 Brazilian Symposium on Robotics (SBR)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2017 Latin American Robotics Symposium (LARS) and 2017 Brazilian Symposium on Robotics (SBR)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-6</pages><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>8-11 Nov. 2017</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/SBR-LARS-R.2017.8215296</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper presents the specifications for a network architecture of a squadron of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles to be used to scan rocket impact areas. It presents the main features of communication networks for multi UAV systems and the details of its application. In this context, we propose a network architecture based on XBee Pro 900HP S3B modules integrated to a hardware platform controlled by embedded computer Model Raspberry Pi 2B, equipped with GPS and Ardupilot controller board. A test plan was established to evaluate the performance of the proposed network architecture in terms of robustness, reliability and energy efficiency. For benchmarking the possible formation of UAVs squadron scenarios, we used network management software in order to measure throughput, packet loss and other performance indicators in the communication links between the different network nodes.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 Latin American Robotics Symposium (LARS) and 2017 Brazilian Symposium on Robotics (SBR)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 Latin American Robotics Symposium (LARS) and 2017 Brazilian Symposium on Robotics (SBR)</research-notes><custom3>2017 Latin American Robotics Symposium (LARS) and 2017 Brazilian Symposium on Robotics (SBR)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>M. V. K. Myjak</author><author>P. Ranganathan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Unmanned Aerial System (UAS) Swarm Design, Flight Patterns, Communication Type, Applications, and Recommendations</title><secondary-title>2022 IEEE International Conference on Electro Information Technology (eIT)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2022 IEEE International Conference on Electro Information Technology (eIT)</full-title></periodical><pages>586-594</pages><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>19-21 May 2022</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2154-0373</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/eIT53891.2022.9813866</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Autonomy in vehicular systems is becoming increasingly prevalent worldwide because of their ability to perform dangerous tasks without any risk to human controllers. Swarms of unmanned aerial systems can aid in multiple applications such as protecting humans in war or natural disasters, conditioning infrastructure or asset monitoring, acting on a target, or package/medical drug delivery applications. If a single swarm member becomes immobilized, the swarm can still complete its task – assuming it is correctly programmed. The design framework for swarms is a complex problem in today’s aviation industry. Factors such as the selection of drones, a means of communication type, architecture, and autonomous flight pattern are all difficult decisions. Early adaption of artificial intelligence (AI) technology seems promising to realize autonomous swarm navigation and control. This paper reviews the current state-of-the-art swarm-based UAS and recommends specific types, modes of communication, architectures, and swarm patterns for particular applications.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 IEEE International Conference on Electro Information Technology (eIT)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 IEEE International Conference on Electro Information Technology (eIT)</research-notes><custom3>2022 IEEE International Conference on Electro Information Technology (eIT)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>J. Peng</author><author>H. Gao</author><author>L. Liu</author><author>Y. Wu</author><author>X. Xu</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>FNTAR: A Future Network Topology-aware Routing protocol in UAV networks</title><secondary-title>2020 IEEE Wireless Communications and Networking Conference (WCNC)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2020 IEEE Wireless Communications and Networking Conference (WCNC)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-6</pages><volume>2020-May</volume><keywords><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Global positioning system</keyword><keyword>Topology</keyword><keyword>UAV networks</keyword><keyword>Ground stations</keyword><keyword>Internet protocols</keyword><keyword>Network topology</keyword><keyword>Routing protocols</keyword><keyword>Future position</keyword><keyword>Network routing</keyword><keyword>Mobile ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>routing protocols</keyword><keyword>Inertial sensor</keyword><keyword>Dynamic topologies</keyword><keyword>delay-tolerant network</keyword><keyword>geographic routing</keyword><keyword>Location information</keyword><keyword>Motion information</keyword><keyword>Routing decisions</keyword><keyword>topology-aware</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>25-28 May 2020</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>15253511 (ISSN); 978-172813106-1 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/WCNC45663.2020.9120842</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) can gather data in the air and transmit the data to the ground station. Multi-UAV systems have been used in an increasing number of mission scenarios and routing protocols play a critical role in UAV network communications. It is now well established that unstable link quality and frequently changing network topology pose significant challenges for messages forwarding in UAV networks. Hence, traditional mobile ad-hoc network routing protocols do not fit well in UAV networks. In many UAV applications, the flight paths of UAVs are planned in advance before performing missions. The positions and motion information of UAVs are available through Global Positioning System (GPS) and inertial sensors, which can be utilized to calculate the future positions of UAVs. Therefore, the future topology of the UAV network is also available. However, existing work does not take advantage of this information. Based on the trajectory, location and motion information of the UAVs, this paper proposes a future network topology-aware routing (FNTAR) protocol, which uses future location information to make superior routing decisions. Moreover, to mitigate data loss problems caused by unstable links and highly dynamic topology, FNTAR can forward messages to multiple excellent next-hop UAVs based on future network topology, and these UAVs can deliver messages to destinations faster. We implement FNTAR in the simulation experiment, the simulation results demonstrate that FNTAR can achieve lower latency and higher delivery ratio than DTNgeo protocol. © 2020 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 12; Conference name: 2020 IEEE Wireless Communications and Networking Conference, WCNC 2020; Conference date: 25 May 2020 through 28 May 2020; Conference code: 161344&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 IEEE Wireless Communications and Networking Conference (WCNC)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Wireless Commun. Networking Conf. WCNC&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 IEEE Wireless Communications and Networking Conference (WCNC)</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85087280490&amp;doi=10.1109%2fWCNC45663.2020.9120842&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=bac9006ab7e7eeaeb50064a3005b14b0</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>2020 IEEE Wireless Communications and Networking Conference (WCNC)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>A. R. Ragab</author><author>M. S. Ale Isaac</author><author>M. A. Luna</author><author>P. F. Peña</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Unmanned Aerial Vehicle Swarming</title><secondary-title>2021 International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies (ICEET)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2021 International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies (ICEET)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-6</pages><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>27-28 Oct. 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2409-2983</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICEET53442.2021.9659698</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) is a special case of the ad-hoc network, as it is categorized from the Flying ad-hoc network (FANET), which is a subcategory from the ad-hoc network. The massive widely used applications for UAVs through the variety of missions leads the researchers to deep through enhancing such systems by equipping different technologies and techniques for UAVs. Adding swarming facilities for UAVs was our case research interest in Drone Hopper research center, to gain the accurate and powerful usage through a swarm of drones to be used in different applications such as firefighting and agriculture. In this paper, a perspective study for UAVs swarming is highlighted through the FASTER project, under H2020 Grant Agreement 833507, showing the problems that face such techniques and technologies, and giving a clear accurate solution.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies (ICEET)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies (ICEET)</research-notes><custom3>2021 International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies (ICEET)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>E. G. Cabral-Pacheco</author><author>S. Villarreal-Reyes</author><author>A. Galaviz-Mosqueda</author><author>S. Villarreal-Reyes</author><author>R. Rivera-Rodriguez</author><author>A. E. Perez-Ramos</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Performance Analysis of Multi-Hop Broadcast Protocols for Distributed UAV Formation Control Applications</title><secondary-title>IEEE Access</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Access</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Access</abbr-1></periodical><pages>113548-113577</pages><volume>7</volume><keywords><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Aircraft control</keyword><keyword>Remote sensing</keyword><keyword>Controllers</keyword><keyword>Control</keyword><keyword>Control strategies</keyword><keyword>Vehicular ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Agricultural robots</keyword><keyword>FANET</keyword><keyword>Message dissemination</keyword><keyword>Multi hop communication</keyword><keyword>Performance analysis</keyword><keyword>Exchange of information</keyword><keyword>Broadcast</keyword><keyword>Dissemination</keyword><keyword>Evaluation framework</keyword><keyword>Multi-hop</keyword><keyword>Multi-hop broadcast</keyword><keyword>Pollution monitoring</keyword><keyword>UAV formation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2019</year><pub-dates><date>2019</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>21693536 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2935307</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Multi-unmanned aerial vehicle (multi-UAV) systems have become popular in applications such as precision agriculture, remote sensing, and pollution monitoring. Commonly, multi-UAV systems require to reach and maintain a specific flight formation during mission execution. This can be achieved by using a distributed UAV formation control strategy in which each UAV has a flight controller whose function is to calculate the control actions for the UAV actuators such that the UAV formation is maintained. To perform this task, the control strategy requires the reliable and timely exchange of information within the UAV formation. The information that is needed by the controller is commonly referred to as state information (SI). It has been assumed that SI can be properly disseminated by means of multi-hop communications, i.e., by deploying a flying ad-hoc network (FANET). In this sense, multi-hop broadcast protocols (MBPs) that were previously proposed for mobile and vehicular ad-hoc networks seem to be suited for this task. However, previous work dealing with distributed UAV formation control has made communication and networking assumptions that would be hard to fulfill in actual FANET deployments. Moreover, the efficiency of the MBPs to disseminate SI within a FANET remains unexplored. The goal of this paper is to analyze how the network performance offered by different MBPs impacts the effectiveness of distributed UAV formation control to maintain UAV formation. An evaluation framework to perform this task is proposed in this paper. The simulation results demonstrate the relevance of MBP performance in SI message dissemination and thus in the ability of the controller to maintain a formation. © 2019 Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.. All rights reserved.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 5; Correspondence Address: S. VILLARREAL-REYES; Center for Scientific Research and Higher Education at Ensenada (CICESE), Ensenada, 22860, Mexico; email: svillar@cicese.mx</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85077755703&amp;doi=10.1109%2fACCESS.2019.2935307&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=0be30b8b10a483b00257e5235f9c1609</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49788/E. G. Cabral-Pacheco et al. - 2019 - Performance Analysis of Multi-Hop Broadcast Protoc.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>H. Zhao</author><author>X. Zhang</author><author>R. Yu</author><author>R. Li</author><author>M. Zhu</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Research on UAV Formation Network Technology in High Dynamic Environment</title><secondary-title>2019 International Conference on Virtual Reality and Intelligent Systems (ICVRIS)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2019 International Conference on Virtual Reality and Intelligent Systems (ICVRIS)</full-title></periodical><pages>469-472</pages><dates><year>2019</year><pub-dates><date>14-15 Sept. 2019</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICVRIS.2019.00119</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Formations are the main form of UAV cooperative operation, and UAV ad hoc network is an effective technique to achieve the formation control. Additionally, clustering techniques are important to manage and control UAV ad hoc networks. Therefore, the paper aiming at the special environment of UAV networking in mountainous and jungle area and the requirement of flexible and dynamic networking, a high dynamic self-organizing UAV network architecture design based on cluster is proposed. we will fully consider the situation of the mobile network, and propose the concrete plan for the management of non-human computer network, namely the switching of the nodes in the two modes of the node, and the design of the switching mode of the network mode. which can meet the requirements of various UAV autonomous cooperative formation networking under high dynamic environment, and improve the communication performance and intelligent decision-making ability of UAV formation networking.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 International Conference on Virtual Reality and Intelligent Systems (ICVRIS)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 International Conference on Virtual Reality and Intelligent Systems (ICVRIS)</research-notes><custom3>2019 International Conference on Virtual Reality and Intelligent Systems (ICVRIS)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>J. Modares</author><author>N. Mastronarde</author><author>K. Dantu</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>UB-ANC emulator: An emulation framework for multi-agent drone networks</title><secondary-title>2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots, SIMPAR 2016</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)</full-title></periodical><pages>252-258</pages><keywords><keyword>Software testing</keyword><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Rock mechanics</keyword><keyword>Multi agent systems</keyword><keyword>Controllers</keyword><keyword>Robot programming</keyword><keyword>Application programs</keyword><keyword>Vehicle to vehicle communications</keyword><keyword>Robots</keyword><keyword>Flight controllers</keyword><keyword>Micro air vehicle (MAV)</keyword><keyword>Vehicles</keyword><keyword>Fighter aircraft</keyword><keyword>Ground control stations</keyword><keyword>Leader-follower</keyword><keyword>Open software</keyword><keyword>Airborne networking</keyword><keyword>Emulation framework</keyword><keyword>Seamless transition</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year><pub-dates><date>13-16 Dec. 2016</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-150904616-4 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/SIMPAR.2016.7862404</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Recent interest in hobby aerial vehicles and their applications has seen the emergence of quadrotor designs with various form factors, and development of waypoint-based flight controllers such as APM and Pixhawk. Common to these flight controllers is the use of the Micro Air Vehicle Communications Protocol (MAVLink) that allows the flight controller to communicate with a ground control station. However, it is still challenging to experiment with multiple such aerial vehicles concurrently. To this end, we have developed an open software/hardware platform-the University at Buffalo's Airborne Networking and Communications testbed (UB-ANC)-that facilitates rapid development and deployment of multi-drone applications. In this paper, we present the UB-ANC Emulator, an emulation environment to design, implement, and test various applications (missions) involving one or more drones in software, and provides seamless transition to experimentation. We validate the UB-ANC Emulator's output against experimental data collected in a mission with three networked drones to demonstrate its feasibility and accuracy, and we demonstrate its scalability up to 100 drones using a simulated 'leader-follower' mission. © 2016 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 12; Conference name: 2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots, SIMPAR 2016; Conference date: 13 December 2016 through 16 December 2016; Conference code: 126624&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Int. Conf. Simul., Model., Program. Auton. Robot., SIMPAR&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85015911261&amp;doi=10.1109%2fSIMPAR.2016.7862404&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=d38e9848f21a0435b897a73c2d71c336</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>2016 IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>F. Zhang</author><author>H. Lu</author><author>J. Wu</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A reconfigurable mission management system based on modular framework for micro UAVs</title><secondary-title>Proceedings of 2014 IEEE Chinese Guidance, Navigation and Control Conference</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of 2014 IEEE Chinese Guidance, Navigation and Control Conference</full-title></periodical><pages>2510-2514</pages><dates><year>2014</year><pub-dates><date>8-10 Aug. 2014</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/CGNCC.2014.7007562</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In this paper, we present the architecture of the reconfigurable mission management system for micro UAVs. The system consists of two subsystems: the onboard system and the ground control station. They all base on the modular framework. All modules are independent to each other. The entire system can reconfigure depending on the requirements of different missions. The method of multi-thread is introduced to realize them. Each thread performs one specific task, such as communication, path planning, control, mission management, health monitor and data logging. Meanwhile, the ground control station provides a friendly interface displaying the real-time status of UAVs. Especially for the onboard system, we mainly detail the mission management computer, which includes a mission management module. Petri net is used to model the vehicle behaviors during the mission.</abstract><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;Not accessible&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of 2014 IEEE Chinese Guidance, Navigation and Control Conference&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of 2014 IEEE Chinese Guidance, Navigation and Control Conference</research-notes><custom3>Proceedings of 2014 IEEE Chinese Guidance, Navigation and Control Conference</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>L. C. Batista da Silva</author><author>R. M. Bernardo</author><author>H. A. de Oliveira</author><author>P. F. F. Rosa</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Multi-UAV agent-based coordination for persistent surveillance with dynamic priorities</title><secondary-title>ICMT 2017 - 6th International Conference on Military Technologies</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2017 International Conference on Military Technologies (ICMT)</full-title></periodical><pages>765-771</pages><keywords><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Flight simulators</keyword><keyword>Rock mechanics</keyword><keyword>Ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Embedded systems</keyword><keyword>Monitoring</keyword><keyword>Multipurpose robots</keyword><keyword>Flight control systems</keyword><keyword>surveillance</keyword><keyword>Robots</keyword><keyword>Multi-robot systems</keyword><keyword>System architectures</keyword><keyword>Command and control systems</keyword><keyword>Ground control stations</keyword><keyword>Persistent surveillance</keyword><keyword>Space surveillance</keyword><keyword>Continuous monitoring</keyword><keyword>ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Agent-based coordination</keyword><keyword>command and control systems</keyword><keyword>Methodology approaches</keyword><keyword>multi-robot systems</keyword><keyword>Spatial coordination</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>31 May-2 June 2017</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-153861988-9 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/MILTECHS.2017.7988859</electronic-resource-num><abstract>A system to coordinate a team of unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV) applied for surveillance tasks is presented in this paper. Such scenario demands continuous monitoring of the region and take account of its priority areas which will require control interactions, both in mission planning and execution. The methodology approach is based on priority gradients combined with region partitioning, where the points of greatest interest are updated more frequently. The proposed system is based on the coordination of embedded agents using spatial coordination on strategical positioning and role exchange. The system architecture is composed by three modules, namely, the ground control station, for mission planning and control through user interaction; a quadrotors team, capable of navigation by inertial and satellite systems; and the control agents embedded in aircrafts, responsible for communications, task allocation and payload mission control. The preliminary results are validated using both computer simulation and a real flight with quadrotors. Telemetry data from the results were compared and it demonstrate that the proposed methodology converges to an effective solution. © 2017 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 21; Conference name: 6th International Conference on Military Technologies, ICMT 2017; Conference date: 31 May 2017 through 2 June 2017; Conference code: 129537&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 International Conference on Military Technologies (ICMT)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: ICMT - Int. Conf. Mil. Technol.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 International Conference on Military Technologies (ICMT)</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85029376263&amp;doi=10.1109%2fMILTECHS.2017.7988859&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=1ca7a223269aea6d6648dfdc03af11cc</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>2017 International Conference on Military Technologies (ICMT)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>N. Figueira</author><author>P. Pochmann</author><author>A. Oliveira</author><author>E. P. de Freitas</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A C4ISR Application on the Swarm Drones Context in a Low Infrastructure Scenario</title><secondary-title>2022 International Conference on Electrical, Computer and Energy Technologies (ICECET)</secondary-title><tertiary-title>International Conference on Electrical, Computer, and Energy Technologies, ICECET 2022</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2022 IEEE International Conference on Electrical, Computer, and Energy Technologies, ICECET 2022, July 20, 2022 - July 22, 2022</full-title></periodical><pages>1-7</pages><keywords><keyword>Decision making</keyword><keyword>Information management</keyword><keyword>Interoperability</keyword><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>Military applications</keyword><keyword>Military operations</keyword><keyword>Data acquisition</keyword><keyword>Air navigation</keyword><keyword>Middleware</keyword><keyword>Command and control systems</keyword><keyword>Software radio</keyword><keyword>Amazon scenario</keyword><keyword>Amazon Scenario</keyword><keyword>C4ISR</keyword><keyword>Data fusion</keyword><keyword>IFA2S</keyword><keyword>INTERC2</keyword><keyword>Internet-to-the-battlefield</keyword><keyword>IoBT</keyword><keyword>Low infrastructure scenario</keyword><keyword>Low Infrastructure Scenario</keyword><keyword>Mission-oriented</keyword><keyword>Mission-oriented sensor array</keyword><keyword>MOSA</keyword><keyword>SDR</keyword><keyword>Sensors array</keyword><keyword>Software-defined radios</keyword><keyword>Swarm drone</keyword><keyword>Swarm Drones</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>20-22 July 2022</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-166547087-2 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICECET55527.2022.9872941</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The military operations in low communications infrastructure scenarios employ flexible solutions to optimize the data processing cycle using situational awareness systems, guaranteeing interoperability and assisting in all processes of decision-making. This paper presents an architecture for the integration of Command, Control, Computing, Communication, Intelligence, Surveillance and Reconnaissance Systems (C4ISR), developed within the scope of the Brazilian Ministry of Defense, in the context of operations with Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAV) - swarm drones - and the Internet-to-the-battlefield (IoBT) concept. This solution comprises the following intelligent subsystems embedded in UAV: STFANET, an SDN-Based Topology Management for Flying Ad Hoc Network focusing drone swarms operations, developed by University of Rio Grande do Sul; Interoperability of Command and Control (INTERC2), an intelligent communication middleware developed by Brazilian Navy; A Mission-Oriented Sensors Array (MOSA), which provides the automatization of data acquisition, data fusion, and data sharing, developed by Brazilian Army; The In-Flight Awareness Augmentation System (IFA2S), which was developed to increase the safety navigation of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAV), developed by Brazilian Air Force; Data Mining Techniques to optimize the MOSA with data patterns; and an adaptive-collaborative system, composed of a Software Defined Radio (SDR), to solve the identification of electromagnetic signals and a Geographical Information System (GIS) to organize the information processed. This research proposes, as a main contribution in this conceptual phase, an application that describes the premises for increasing the capacity of sensing threats in the low structured zones, such as the Amazon rainforest, using existing communications solutions of Brazilian defense monitoring systems.  © 2022 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Conference name: 2022 IEEE International Conference on Electrical, Computer, and Energy Technologies, ICECET 2022; Conference date: 20 July 2022 through 22 July 2022; Conference code: 182630&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 IEEE International Conference on Electrical, Computer, and Energy Technologies, ICECET 2022, July 20, 2022 - July 22, 2022&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 International Conference on Electrical, Computer and Energy Technologies (ICECET)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Int. Conf. Electr., Comput., Energy Technol., ICECET&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 IEEE International Conference on Electrical, Computer, and Energy Technologies, ICECET 2022, July 20, 2022 - July 22, 2022</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85138989508&amp;doi=10.1109%2fICECET55527.2022.9872941&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=475f8eccf5f27cdeb22dc976fd28018a</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICECET55527.2022.9872941</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Prague, Czech republic</custom1><custom3>2022 IEEE International Conference on Electrical, Computer, and Energy Technologies, ICECET 2022, July 20, 2022 - July 22, 2022</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Z. Guo</author><author>Y. Wang</author><author>Y. Sun</author><author>J. Zhong</author><author>J. Li</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Modeling on RMS of UAV swarm based on multi agent simulation</title><secondary-title>12th International Conference on Quality, Reliability, Risk, Maintenance, and Safety Engineering (QR2MSE 2022)</secondary-title><tertiary-title>IET Conference Proceedings</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>12th International Conference on Quality, Reliability, Risk, Maintenance, and Safety Engineering, QR2MSE 2022, July 27, 2022 - July 30, 2022</full-title></periodical><pages>1937-1942</pages><volume>2022</volume><keywords><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>UAV swarm</keyword><keyword>Multi agent systems</keyword><keyword>Adaptive characteristic</keyword><keyword>Evolution rules</keyword><keyword>multi-agent simulation</keyword><keyword>Multi-agents simulations</keyword><keyword>NetLogo</keyword><keyword>Petri net</keyword><keyword>Petri nets</keyword><keyword>RMS evaluation</keyword><keyword>Self organizations</keyword><keyword>Simulation framework</keyword><keyword>Time factors</keyword><keyword>Time-varying functions</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>27-30 July 2022</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institution of Engineering and Technology</publisher><isbn>27324494 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1049/icp.2022.3152</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In view of the characteristics of the UAV swarm, such as changeable tasks and time-varying functions, this paper first gave the DoDAF description of architecture tasks. Then the Petri net of time factor is introduced to formalize the agent, and the multi-agent simulation framework is constructed based on the task evolution rules of the system. According to the self-organization and self-adaptive characteristics of the swarm, the random walk rules of communication information are proposed to evaluate the RMS of the dynamic system quantitatively. Through the simulation, the model can illustrate the critical impact of the RMS of the UAV swarm on the operational mission to provide technical solutions and theoretical guidance for the system construction and operational application evaluation. © 2022 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Conference name: 12th International Conference on Quality, Reliability, Risk, Maintenance, and Safety Engineering, QR2MSE 2022; Conference date: 27 July 2022 through 30 July 2022; Conference code: 189505&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 12th International Conference on Quality, Reliability, Risk, Maintenance, and Safety Engineering (QR2MSE 2022)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 12th International Conference on Quality, Reliability, Risk, Maintenance, and Safety Engineering, QR2MSE 2022, July 27, 2022 - July 30, 2022&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IET. Conf. Proc.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 12th International Conference on Quality, Reliability, Risk, Maintenance, and Safety Engineering, QR2MSE 2022, July 27, 2022 - July 30, 2022</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85164297770&amp;doi=10.1049%2ficp.2022.3152&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=8b5fcb3304ec163b06c0c20b262d2dad</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1049/icp.2022.3152</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Emeishan, China</custom1><custom3>12th International Conference on Quality, Reliability, Risk, Maintenance, and Safety Engineering, QR2MSE 2022, July 27, 2022 - July 30, 2022</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>H. Guo</author><author>T. Liu</author><author>K. -S. Lui</author><author>C. Danilov</author><author>K. Nahrstedt</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Secure Broadcast Protocol for Unmanned Aerial Vehicle Swarms</title><secondary-title>2020 29th International Conference on Computer Communications and Networks (ICCCN)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2020 29th International Conference on Computer Communications and Networks (ICCCN)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-9</pages><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>3-6 Aug. 2020</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2637-9430</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICCCN49398.2020.9209739</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The technology advancement has made Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) swarm a promising method to achieve complicated missions that a single UAV cannot support. Leader-followers formation is a widely used swarm management scenario where a leader drone frequently broadcasts controlling messages to all follower drones to achieve collaboratively a common mission. However, managing such a UAV swarm, especially when the member drones dynamically join and leave the swarm, introduces significant security challenges and performance overhead.In this work, we propose a Swarm Broadcast Protocol (SBP) to facilitate the security protection of leader-followers formation based UAV swarms. SBP contains a security key management scheme that manages a broadcast key among the swarm for leader to broadcast encrypted messages to followers. When swarm membership changes, the broadcast key will be updated and synchronized among the swarm to maintain both backward and forward secrecy. The overhead of SBP is small that only constant computational overhead is needed for both swarm leader and followers to achieve key synchronization when a new drone joins regardless of the current swarm size. This feature would highly reduce the overhead when there are many individual drone joining events. Through experiments on network emulator, we show that SBP achieves lowest bandwidth overhead and CPU utilization to handle multiple swarm membership changing events, comparing with two public-key-based swarm management protocol baselines.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 29th International Conference on Computer Communications and Networks (ICCCN)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 29th International Conference on Computer Communications and Networks (ICCCN)</research-notes><custom3>2020 29th International Conference on Computer Communications and Networks (ICCCN)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>R. Yeniçeri</author><author>E. Saldıran</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Design and Development of An Avionics Architecture for Autonomous UAV Fleets</title><secondary-title>2021 12th International Conference on Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, ICMAE 2021</secondary-title><tertiary-title>2021 12th International Conference on Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, ICMAE 2021</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>12th International Conference on Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, ICMAE 2021, July 16, 2021 - July 19, 2021</full-title></periodical><pages>365-372</pages><keywords><keyword>Software testing</keyword><keyword>Open source software</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Fixed wings</keyword><keyword>Aircraft detection</keyword><keyword>Flight simulators</keyword><keyword>Cost effectiveness</keyword><keyword>Embedded systems</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>unmanned aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword><keyword>Economic and social effects</keyword><keyword>Avionics</keyword><keyword>Computer operating systems</keyword><keyword>Fault tolerance</keyword><keyword>Memory architecture</keyword><keyword>Multiple UAVs</keyword><keyword>Swarm</keyword><keyword>Cameras</keyword><keyword>Redundancy</keyword><keyword>MATLAB</keyword><keyword>Autonomous UAV</keyword><keyword>Autonomous UAVs</keyword><keyword>swarm</keyword><keyword>Software radio</keyword><keyword>avionics</keyword><keyword>Bandwidth</keyword><keyword>Design and Development</keyword><keyword>Computer hardware</keyword><keyword>Design</keyword><keyword>Design and development process</keyword><keyword>Flight management computers</keyword><keyword>Micro UAVs</keyword><keyword>Micro-UAV</keyword><keyword>Signal dynamics</keyword><keyword>Slot antennas</keyword><keyword>Reconfigurable architectures</keyword><keyword>SYSTEM</keyword><keyword>Microstrip antennas</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>16-19 July 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-166543321-1 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICMAE52228.2021.9522365</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In this work we present the design and development process of an avionics architecture for missions that require highly coordinated flight of a fleet of autonomous fixed-wing micro UAVs. Applications such as signal tracking or dynamic object tracking with multiple UAVs allow a cost-effective and minimum-risk alternative to missions which have been historically handled with manned aircraft. As such, for these specific applications, we have developed a micro-avionics architecture structured around an in-house customized open-source autopilot and an indigenous Linux based single board payload/flight management computer. The essential 5-km range telemetry and control link radio is backed up by high-power long-range IEEE 802.11n (WiFi) radio device. The redundancy of communication not only improves the reliability of the avionics architecture, but also enables the trade-off between bandwidth and power efficiency. The architecture is capable of transmitting data at rates above 200 kbps up to 4 km away from its ground station equipped with the developed miniature patch antenna tracker. The payload/flight management computer is ready to run a CSI/USB connected day-light or low-illumination infra-red camera, a USB connected software defined radio and different types of sensor payloads such as radar/lidar range sensors and RGBD cameras. Tied to this architecture, we have designed a Software-in-the-Loop (SIL) and Hardware-in-the-Loop (HIL) testing system with MAVlink communication protocol interlinking hardware to Matlab based UAV dynamic models and tracking algorithms. This system allows comprehensive simulation and testing of designed control and guidance algorithms before flight tests while minimizing cost and crash risk. We have successfully used the avionics architecture in flight tests that involve (a) system identification of flight vehicles and (b) tracking and identification of signal sources using multiple UAVs.  © 2021 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Conference name: 12th International Conference on Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, ICMAE 2021; Conference date: 16 July 2021 through 19 July 2021; Conference code: 171531&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 12th International Conference on Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, ICMAE 2021, July 16, 2021 - July 19, 2021&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 12th International Conference on Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering (ICMAE)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 12TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON MECHANICAL AND AEROSPACE ENGINEERING (ICMAE)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Int. Conf. Mech. Aerosp. Eng., ICMAE&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 12th International Conference on Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, ICMAE 2021, July 16, 2021 - July 19, 2021</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85115364557&amp;doi=10.1109%2fICMAE52228.2021.9522365&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=dbb875b00677cfd96259c82e0d2938e1</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICMAE52228.2021.9522365</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Virtual, Athens, Greece</custom1><custom3>12th International Conference on Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, ICMAE 2021, July 16, 2021 - July 19, 2021</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Z. Wang</author><author>C. Chen</author><author>Y. Zhang</author><author>K. Zhang</author><author>C. Guo</author><author>Y. Yuan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An Interaction Framework for Multi-domain Unmanned Systems Collaboration Based on Interoperability Messages</title><secondary-title>2022 IEEE 5th International Conference on Electronic Information and Communication Technology (ICEICT)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2022 IEEE 5th International Conference on Electronic Information and Communication Technology (ICEICT)</full-title></periodical><pages>152-155</pages><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>21-23 Aug. 2022</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICEICT55736.2022.9908941</electronic-resource-num><abstract>To improve the interoperability of unmanned system and enhance the multi-domain unmanned system collaborative capacity, we propose an interaction framework based on interoperability messages, which consists of a set of message standard and the correlated interaction protocol. Combines the common information interaction requirements of unmanned system and the different specificity of unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV), unmanned surface vehicles (USV), unmanned ground vehicles (UGV), unmanned underwater vehicles (UUV) and the corresponding payloads carried by the unmanned systems, the message standard set can be divided into three main categories, each category contains several kinds of message. The interaction protocol of a message varies according to the message's type and meaning. The interaction framework will help human operator make it easier to control different kinds of multi-domain unmanned systems and make autonomous cooperative between unmanned systems possible.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 IEEE 5th International Conference on Electronic Information and Communication Technology (ICEICT)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 IEEE 5th International Conference on Electronic Information and Communication Technology (ICEICT)</research-notes><custom3>2022 IEEE 5th International Conference on Electronic Information and Communication Technology (ICEICT)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>J. Boubin</author><author>C. Burley</author><author>P. Han</author><author>B. Li</author><author>B. Porter</author><author>C. Stewart</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>MARbLE: Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning at the Edge for Digital Agriculture</title><secondary-title>2022 IEEE/ACM 7th Symposium on Edge Computing (SEC)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2022 IEEE/ACM 7th Symposium on Edge Computing (SEC)</full-title></periodical><pages>68-81</pages><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>5-8 Dec. 2022</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/SEC54971.2022.00013</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Digital agriculture, hailed as the fourth great agricultural revolution, employs software-driven autonomous agents for in-field crop management. Edge computing resources deployed near crop fields support autonomous agents with substantial computational needs for tasks such as AI inference. In large fields, using multiple autonomous agents, called swarms, can speed up crop management tasks if sufficient edge resources are provisioned. However, to use swarms today, farmers and software developers craft their own standalone solutions that are either simple and ineffective or complicated and hard-to-reproduce. We present MARbLE, a platform for developing and managing swarms. MARbLE provides an easy-to-use programming paradigm that helps users build swarm workloads using multi-agent reinforcement learning. Developers supply just two functions Map() and Eval(). The platform automatically compiles and deploys swarms and continuously updates the reinforcement learning models that govern their actions. Developers can experiment with multiple swarm and edge resource configurations both in simulation and with actual in-field runs. We studied real UAV swarms conducting digital agriculture missions. We observe that swarms demanded edge computing resources in bursts; the ratio of average to peak demand was 2.9X. MARbLE uses energy-saving load balancing policies to duty cycle machines during workload demand troughs, leveraging workload patterns to save edge energy. Using MARbLE, we found that four-agent swarms with load balancing techniques sped up missions by 2.1X and reduced edge energy usage by up to 2X compared to state of the art autonomous swarms.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 IEEE/ACM 7th Symposium on Edge Computing (SEC)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 IEEE/ACM 7th Symposium on Edge Computing (SEC)</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49789/J. Boubin et al. - 2022 - MARbLE Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning at the .pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><custom3>2022 IEEE/ACM 7th Symposium on Edge Computing (SEC)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>A. Balasubramanian</author><author>N. Mahalingam</author><author>R. Pragada</author><author>P. Pietraski</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Group Feedback Protocols for UAV Swarming Applications</title><secondary-title>2018 IEEE Globecom Workshops (GC Wkshps)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2018 IEEE Globecom Workshops (GC Wkshps)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-7</pages><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>9-13 Dec. 2018</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/GLOCOMW.2018.8644393</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper presents group feedback protocols (group NACK (gNACK)/group ACK (gACK)), whereby a swarm of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAV) cooperate through their Sidelinks (D2D links) to determine the lost packets, among a group of packets received by them in the downlink interface (interface from the base station to the UAV). We bring to bear the notion of group feedback (gNACK/gACK) for broadcast/multicast transmissions, where an ACK/NACK is determined not on a peruser, or per-packet basis, but instead, based on multiple users, and multiple packets. We formulate this problem as a submodular optimization problem to obtain optimal solutions, and algorithms in minimizing the sum-rate for determining the gNACK (gACK) under the assumption that each user in the swarm is aware of the error rates of all other users. We then extend the structure of the optimal algorithm to devise distributed group feedback protocols, where a user operates solely on its own error rates, and does not possess information on error rates of other users. We show that the proposed distributed group feedback protocol is ≈ 1.5% away from the optimal solution. PHY/MAC system design aspects of the group feedback protocols regarding cellular systems are outlined. Simulation results assessing the performance of the proposed protocols are provided. With the goal of embracing the evolving perspective of UAVs to swarming use cases, where a network of UAVs cooperate to accomplish a mission are envisioned, this study becomes important as it enables spectrally efficient feedback, and local packet loss recovery schemes, without invoking the base station.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2018 IEEE Globecom Workshops (GC Wkshps)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2018 IEEE Globecom Workshops (GC Wkshps)</research-notes><custom3>2018 IEEE Globecom Workshops (GC Wkshps)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>M. A. Khan</author><author>I. M. Qureshi</author><author>I. U. Khan</author><author>A. Nasim</author><author>U. Javed</author><author>W. Khan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>On the Performance of Flying Ad-hoc Networks (FANETs) with Directional Antennas</title><secondary-title>2018 5th International Multi-Topic ICT Conference (IMTIC)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2018 5th International Multi-Topic ICT Conference (IMTIC)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-8</pages><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>25-27 April 2018</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/IMTIC.2018.8467274</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The Flying Ad-hoc Networks (FANETs) is relatively a new research area that governs the autonomous movement of multiple and small-sized unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs). Compared to the traditional ad-hoc networks, FANETs are more efficient in completing their task in catastrophic situations to deliver data communication services from the height. However, type of the mission and sensitivity of the application requires an adaptive, efficient, and scalable communication network for data transmission among the UAVs. Such network are challenged by the high mobility and frequent topology changes, resulting connectivity loss problem. In this context, the UAVs in FANETs have been deployed with omnidirectional antennas, which leads to restrict the overall performance of the network. Alternately, directional antennas have the potential to enhance the transmission range, spatial reuse, and capacity of the network effectively. Nevertheless, these benefits also bring some unique challenges, particularly for the MAC layer. In order to overcome such constraints, we propose a new directional antennas based medium access control (MAC) protocol to adapt the FANETs architecture. The idea is to use multiple directional antennas on a single UAV with IEEE 802.11 protocol. The design goal is to improve the overall performance of the network and to provide solutions to some of the unique challenges of using directional antennas. The integrated solution is modeled in OPNET and evaluated for throughput, end-to-end delay, and retransmission attempts. The simulation results authenticate that the proposed IEEE 802.11-based directional antennas protocol could significantly increase the performance of FANETs as compared to omnidirectional antennas.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2018 5th International Multi-Topic ICT Conference (IMTIC)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2018 5th International Multi-Topic ICT Conference (IMTIC)</research-notes><custom3>2018 5th International Multi-Topic ICT Conference (IMTIC)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>J. Peng</author><author>H. Gao</author><author>L. Liu</author><author>N. Li</author><author>X. Xu</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>TBM: An Efficient Trajectory-Based Multicast Routing Protocol for Sparse UAV networks</title><secondary-title>Proceedings - 2020 IEEE 22nd International Conference on High Performance Computing and Communications, IEEE 18th International Conference on Smart City and IEEE 6th International Conference on Data Science and Systems, HPCC-SmartCity-DSS 2020</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2020 IEEE 22nd International Conference on High Performance Computing and Communications; IEEE 18th International Conference on Smart City; IEEE 6th International Conference on Data Science and Systems (HPCC/SmartCity/DSS)</full-title></periodical><pages>867-872</pages><keywords><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Trajectories</keyword><keyword>Information dissemination</keyword><keyword>UAV networks</keyword><keyword>Internet protocols</keyword><keyword>Multicasting</keyword><keyword>Routing protocols</keyword><keyword>Extensive simulations</keyword><keyword>Data communication systems</keyword><keyword>Network routing</keyword><keyword>Smart city</keyword><keyword>Multicast routing protocol</keyword><keyword>Effectiveness and efficiencies</keyword><keyword>routing protocol</keyword><keyword>Data Science</keyword><keyword>Mobile wireless network</keyword><keyword>multicast</keyword><keyword>Multiple destinations</keyword><keyword>Positioning technologies</keyword><keyword>Sparse distribution</keyword><keyword>trajectory</keyword><keyword>Trajectory information</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>14-16 Dec. 2020</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-172817649-9 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/HPCC-SmartCity-DSS50907.2020.00115</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Multicast is an essential operation for Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) networks, which supports important functions such as information dissemination and swarm coordination. However, most existing routing protocols for UAV networks aim at unicast routing, and there are few multicast protocols dedicated to UAV networks. Furthermore, most existing multicast protocols for mobile wireless networks usually maintain a forwarding structure, and they are inefficient in UAV networks due to the unique characteristics of UAVs, such as high-speed movement and sparse distribution. For many UAV applications, the trajectories of UAVs are pre-planned in advance through mission planning and trajectory planning, and the location and motion information of UAVs can be obtained through positioning technology and inertial sensors. In this paper, we propose an efficient Trajectory-Based Multicast (TBM) routing protocol for UAV networks. TBM utilizes the trajectory information to compute the encounters between UAVs, then a priority metric that characterizes the ability of a UAV to forward a message to multiple destination nodes is calculated. Based on the priority metric, TBM constructs a priority encounter graph, which considers the timeliness and stability of message forwarding, thus finding a multicast forwarding sequence with low delay and high delivery ratio. Through extensive simulations, we demonstrate the effectiveness and efficiency of TBM. © 2020 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 7; Conference name: 22nd IEEE International Conference on High Performance Computing and Communications, 18th IEEE International Conference on Smart City and 6th IEEE International Conference on Data Science and Systems, HPCC-SmartCity-DSS 2020; Conference date: 14 December 2020 through 16 December 2020; Conference code: 168653&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 IEEE 22nd International Conference on High Performance Computing and Communications; IEEE 18th International Conference on Smart City; IEEE 6th International Conference on Data Science and Systems (HPCC/SmartCity/DSS)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proc. - IEEE Int. Conf. High Perform. Comput. Commun., IEEE Int. Conf. Smart City IEEE Int. Conf. Data Sci. Syst., HPCC-SmartCity-DSS&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 IEEE 22nd International Conference on High Performance Computing and Communications; IEEE 18th International Conference on Smart City; IEEE 6th International Conference on Data Science and Systems (HPCC/SmartCity/DSS)</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85105352068&amp;doi=10.1109%2fHPCC-SmartCity-DSS50907.2020.00115&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=8820d233a0c58738edde5a399da04940</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>2020 IEEE 22nd International Conference on High Performance Computing and Communications; IEEE 18th International Conference on Smart City; IEEE 6th International Conference on Data Science and Systems (HPCC/SmartCity/DSS)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>W. -S. Jung</author><author>J. Yim</author><author>Y. -B. Ko</author><author>S. Singh</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>ACODS: adaptive computation offloading for drone surveillance system</title><secondary-title>2017 16th Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2017 16th Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-6</pages><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>28-30 June 2017</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/MedHocNet.2017.8001647</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) surveillance systems allow for highly advanced and safe surveillance of hazardous locations. Further, multi-purpose drones can be widely deployed for not only gathering information but also analyzing the situation from sensed data. However, mobile drone systems have limited computing resources and battery power which makes it a challenge to use these systems for long periods of time or in fully autonomous modes. In this paper, we propose an Adaptive Computation Offloading Drone System (ACODS) architecture with reliable communication for increasing drone operating time. We design not only the response time prediction module for mission critical task offloading decision but also task offloading management module via the Multipath TCP (MPTCP). Through performance evaluation via our prototype implementation, we show that the proposed algorithm achieves significant increase in drone operation time and significantly reduces the response time.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 16th Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 16th Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)</research-notes><custom3>2017 16th Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Z. Xinqing</author><author>L. Na</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Content Driven Routing Protocol of the Software-defined Information-Centric Airborne Tactical Network</title><secondary-title>Proceedings of 2019 IEEE International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Computer Applications, ICAICA 2019</secondary-title><tertiary-title>Proceedings of 2019 IEEE International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Computer Applications, ICAICA 2019</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2019 IEEE International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Computer Applications, ICAICA 2019, March 29, 2019 - March 31, 2019</full-title></periodical><pages>198-204</pages><keywords><keyword>Artificial intelligence</keyword><keyword>Network architecture</keyword><keyword>Communication service</keyword><keyword>Proposed architectures</keyword><keyword>Software defined networking</keyword><keyword>Closed loop control systems</keyword><keyword>Internet protocols</keyword><keyword>Routing protocols</keyword><keyword>Computer software</keyword><keyword>Software defined networking (SDN)</keyword><keyword>Network routing</keyword><keyword>Information-centric networkings</keyword><keyword>Tactical network</keyword><keyword>Airborne tactical network</keyword><keyword>Aviation swarms</keyword><keyword>Content-driven routing protocol</keyword><keyword>Information contents</keyword><keyword>Information-centric networking</keyword><keyword>Information-centric networkings (ICN)</keyword><keyword>Operational platforms</keyword><keyword>Software-definition networking</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2019</year><pub-dates><date>29-31 March 2019</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-172811222-0 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICAICA.2019.8873524</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The traditional airborne tactical network (ATN) is tightly coupled to combat applications and does not take into account the information content itself, the routing protocols of current ATNs cannot provide differentiated communication services for different information content, leading to the difficulty of meeting the communication requirements of the diverse operational platforms and various operational missions of the aviation swarm. This paper integrates the concept of software-defined networking (SDN) and the concept of information-centric networking (ICN) into the ATN, and proposes the software-defined information-centric airborne tactical network (SDIC-ATN) architecture. Based on the proposed architecture, a content-driven routing protocol is further designed to provide efficient and coping transmission services for different information content. © 2019 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Conference name: 2019 IEEE International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Computer Applications, ICAICA 2019; Conference date: 29 March 2019 through 31 March 2019; Conference code: 152847&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 IEEE International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Computer Applications (ICAICA)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 IEEE International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Computer Applications, ICAICA 2019, March 29, 2019 - March 31, 2019&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proc. IEEE Int. Conf. Artif. Intell. Comput. Appl., ICAICA&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 IEEE International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Computer Applications, ICAICA 2019, March 29, 2019 - March 31, 2019</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85074443493&amp;doi=10.1109%2fICAICA.2019.8873524&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=d2db1cd62a7068fae069ffb84e0c8c61</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICAICA.2019.8873524</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Dalian, China</custom1><custom3>2019 IEEE International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Computer Applications, ICAICA 2019, March 29, 2019 - March 31, 2019</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>H. Yu</author><author>H. Huang</author><author>X. Jia</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Clustering-based Communication Backbone for Large Scale UAV Networks</title><secondary-title>2018 14th International Conference on Mobile Ad-Hoc and Sensor Networks (MSN)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2018 14th International Conference on Mobile Ad-Hoc and Sensor Networks (MSN)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-6</pages><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>6-8 Dec. 2018</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/MSN.2018.00007</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Single micro UAV is limited by its endurance and suffers the problem of single point failure. An autonomous fleet of cooperating UAVs can render more efficient and robust ability to complete the missions. In order to make multiple UAVs fly cooperatively in an autonomous way without control from the ground station, one of the key techniques is communication network technology. In this paper, we propose a distributed algorithm to construct a clustered-backbone to support both broadcast and unicast communications for UAV networks. In our algorithm, UAVs clustering and virtual backbone construction only need the information exchange among adjacent UAVs. We also propose a strategy to dynamically maintain this clustered-backbone network. We test our scheme using four commercial UAVs enhanced by an ARM-based embedded computer to demonstrate the distributed control and dynamic maintenance features of the algorithm.</abstract><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;More algorithm, less architecture&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2018 14th International Conference on Mobile Ad-Hoc and Sensor Networks (MSN)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2018 14th International Conference on Mobile Ad-Hoc and Sensor Networks (MSN)</research-notes><custom3>2018 14th International Conference on Mobile Ad-Hoc and Sensor Networks (MSN)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>C. Manderino</author><author>A. Gillette</author><author>P. Gauvin</author><author>A. D. George</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Resilient Networking Framework for Mission Operations and Resource Sharing in Multi-Agent Systems</title><secondary-title>2018 IEEE/AIAA 37th Digital Avionics Systems Conference (DASC)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2018 IEEE/AIAA 37th Digital Avionics Systems Conference (DASC)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-7</pages><volume>2018-September</volume><keywords><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Multi agent systems</keyword><keyword>Middleware</keyword><keyword>NASA</keyword><keyword>Fault tolerance</keyword><keyword>UTM</keyword><keyword>Life cycle</keyword><keyword>Distributed computer systems</keyword><keyword>Vehicles</keyword><keyword>Satellites</keyword><keyword>Small satellites</keyword><keyword>Digital avionics</keyword><keyword>Advanced traffic management systems</keyword><keyword>CubeSats</keyword><keyword>Distributed systems</keyword><keyword>Fault tolerant computer systems</keyword><keyword>Resilient operations</keyword><keyword>Space</keyword><keyword>Unmanned</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>23-27 Sept. 2018</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>21557195 (ISSN); 978-153864112-5 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/DASC.2018.8569889</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Multi-agent systems call for dependable communication and maintainable infrastructure to conduct distributed operations. Effectively networking services across distributed systems (e.g., drone formations) allows nodes to contribute their collective resources toward achieving mission objectives. Automating unit coordination and node management, within a reusable middleware framework, aligns with goals envisioned in NASA's Unmanned Aerial System (UAS) Traffic Management (UTM) and the National Research Council's Space Studies Board recommendations for CubeSat swarms and constellations for advanced aerospace missions. To provide reliable system management, software services should possess automaticity and fault-tolerance. Additionally, networking services for aerospace platforms should be robust, portable, and reusable for many mission life cycles. Researchers at the National Science Foundation (NSF) Center for Space, High-performance, and Resilient Computing (SHREC) have developed a system architecture that can be deployed as a reusable middleware for distributed systems in hazardous aerospace environments. © 2018 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Conference name: 37th IEEE/AIAA International Digital Avionics Systems Conference, DASC 2018; Conference date: 23 September 2018 through 27 September 2018; Conference code: 143574; CODEN: ADACF&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2018 IEEE/AIAA 37th Digital Avionics Systems Conference (DASC)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: AIAA IEEE Dig Avionics Syst Conf Proc&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2018 IEEE/AIAA 37th Digital Avionics Systems Conference (DASC)</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85060613131&amp;doi=10.1109%2fDASC.2018.8569889&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=405d23200d8e3f481ace443f389f3d1b</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>2018 IEEE/AIAA 37th Digital Avionics Systems Conference (DASC)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>L. Ciarletta</author><author>A. Guenard</author><author>Y. Presse</author><author>V. Galtier</author><author>Y. -Q. Song</author><author>J. -C. Ponsart</author><author>S. Aberkane</author><author>D. Theilliol</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Simulation and platform tools to develop safe flock of UAVs: a CPS application-driven research</title><secondary-title>2014 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2014 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)</full-title></periodical><pages>95-102</pages><dates><year>2014</year><pub-dates><date>27-30 May 2014</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICUAS.2014.6842244</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Autonomous formation flying (flocking) of UAVs requires coordination of efforts and solutions in multiple research fields (robotics, wireless sensor networks to name a few). The Airborne Embedded auTonomOUs Robust Network of Objects and Sensors (AETOURNOS) project is designed as a federative, fueling platform and global evaluation tool. It has spawned another collaborative project bridging the gap between Computer Science and Automation: 6PO (Cyber-Physical Systems and Cooperative Control of a Fleet of UAVs). We want to investigate new flocking strategies, mobility-aware communication protocols (and reciprocally: movements influenced by network QoS), and to ease the cooperation between experts, we need co-simulation solutions, and “universal” control interfaces. This article presents our first contribution to this grand scheme: a stand-alone simulation of an autonomous flocking strategy taking into account both the dynamics of the UAVs and their communications, which has allowed us to examine the relation between network unreliability and control computation. To better study the influence of the communication network, we present an architecture coupling a dedicated network simulator with the UAVs simulator, as well as with a real drone piloting interface. The lessons learned help us build a research and action plan for the years to come.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2014 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2014 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)</research-notes><custom3>2014 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>M. Alharthi</author><author>A. -E. M. Taha</author><author>H. S. Hassanein</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Dynamic Controller Placement in Software Defined Drone Networks</title><secondary-title>2019 IEEE Global Communications Conference (GLOBECOM)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2019 IEEE Global Communications Conference (GLOBECOM)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-6</pages><dates><year>2019</year><pub-dates><date>9-13 Dec. 2019</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2576-6813</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/GLOBECOM38437.2019.9013799</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Controller placement is one of the most important aspects in Software Defined Networking (SDN) as it is critical in determining the performance of the network. While SDN is mainly applied in wired networks, we attempt to utilize it in a futuristic drone-based network architecture to capitalize on the programmability and flexibility offered by SDN. Such drone network comprises a multi-hop network of drones as the nodes of the network which also act as programmable network nodes and forwarding elements. In such a dynamic and mobile network, maintaining SDN controller connectivity becomes a challenge, especially when the drone network requires operating independently from a ground infrastructure for some deployment scenarios. In this work, we attempt to address this challenge by implementing a dynamic scheme for controller placement that deploys a minimum number of drones that operate as SDN controllers and adjust their locations dynamically as the controlled nodes adjust their locations to meet changing mission requirements.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 IEEE Global Communications Conference (GLOBECOM)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 IEEE Global Communications Conference (GLOBECOM)</research-notes><custom3>2019 IEEE Global Communications Conference (GLOBECOM)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>M. Kaur</author><author>R. Amin</author><author>J. Martin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The Design and Validation of ICN-Enabled Hybrid Unmanned Aerial System</title><secondary-title>MILCOM 2021 - 2021 IEEE Military Communications Conference (MILCOM)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>MILCOM 2021 - 2021 IEEE Military Communications Conference (MILCOM)</full-title></periodical><pages>169-174</pages><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>29 Nov.-2 Dec. 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2155-7586</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/MILCOM52596.2021.9653062</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This work presents a measurement study that evaluates a novel Information Centric Networking (ICN)-enabled Hybrid Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) System called IH-UAS. IH-UAS leverages ICN along with an innovative system model integrating broker-based publish-subscribe message dissemination with a decentralized architecture to form an ad hoc (infrastructure-less) UAS to carry out military missions. The overarching research goal that drives this study is to design a system that pushes decision-making to the UAV swarm on the battlefield such that mission tasks are completed more reliably and in less time than traditional centralized UAV-based missions. We use theoretical and measurement-based analysis to validate the system. Through experiments conducted using a simplified variant of a Coordinated Search and Tracking (CSAT) application in IH-UAS, we demonstrate that IH-UAS performs better than the same application operating in a traditional centralized solution. We also show that the broker placement and the number of brokers are critical to application performance.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: MILCOM 2021 - 2021 IEEE Military Communications Conference (MILCOM)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: MILCOM 2021 - 2021 IEEE Military Communications Conference (MILCOM)</research-notes><custom3>MILCOM 2021 - 2021 IEEE Military Communications Conference (MILCOM)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>I. Cardei</author><author>M. Cardei</author><author>R. Papa</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>UAV-enabled Data Gathering in Wireless Sensor Networks</title><secondary-title>2018 IEEE 37th International Performance Computing and Communications Conference (IPCCC)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2018 IEEE 37th International Performance Computing and Communications Conference (IPCCC)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-8</pages><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>17-19 Nov. 2018</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2374-9628</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/PCCC.2018.8711145</electronic-resource-num><abstract>A critical aspect of wireless sensor networks is network lifetime. Power-constrained wireless sensor networks are usable as long as they can communicate sensed data to the base station. Multi-hop data gathering consumes increased energy, especially for data-intensive applications. In this paper we propose a UAV-enabled data gathering mechanism for wireless sensor networks which prolongs network lifetime compared to a traditional data gathering mechanism. Some of the aspects that we address are UAV path planning, scheduled and opportunistic data gathering, and integration of the data gathering with a node scheduling mechanism. Simulations using ns3 show that our algorithm is more efficient in terms of energy consumed and packet delivery ratio compared to traditional data gathering.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2018 IEEE 37th International Performance Computing and Communications Conference (IPCCC)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2018 IEEE 37th International Performance Computing and Communications Conference (IPCCC)</research-notes><custom3>2018 IEEE 37th International Performance Computing and Communications Conference (IPCCC)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>J. Sandino</author><author>J. Galvez–Serna</author><author>N. Mandel</author><author>F. Vanegas</author><author>F. Gonzalez</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Autonomous Mapping of Desiccation Cracks via a Probabilistic-based Motion Planner Onboard UAVs</title><secondary-title>2022 IEEE Aerospace Conference (AERO)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2022 IEEE Aerospace Conference (AERO)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-14</pages><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>5-12 March 2022</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1095-323X</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/AERO53065.2022.9843299</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Studies of past life forms on other planets are possible through the identification and localisation of desiccation cracks in ancient water bodies such as lakes, rivers and seas. Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) are increasingly being used as a viable remote sensing solution for planetary exploration, as desiccation cracks are difficult to identify with the naked eye and are normally located in complex and unreachable environments. However, most UAVs have a strong reliance on human operators through their communication systems, as UAVs have limited onboard decision-making capabilities for autonomous navigation in such environments. UAV navigation in real-world scenarios is also challenging as data captured from their sensors is imperfect, and outputs from computer vision systems are, sometimes, inaccurate. These sensory and onboard vision limitations cause partial observability of the state of surveyed environments, inducing uncertainty in optimal path planning. This paper proposes a UAV system for autonomous onboard navigation, identification, and mapping of desiccation cracks for planetary exploration. The navigation problem is mathematically formulated as a partially observable Markov decision process (POMDP), where a motion strategy can be obtained by solving the POMDP in real time using the augmented belief tree (ABT) solver. The framework discussed in this work is validated with real flight tests using two desiccation crack patterns distributed across the surveyed area. Real-time segmentation from streamed camera frames of desiccation cracks is achieved through inference onboard the aircraft using a ResNet18 Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) model, and an OpenCV AI Kit (OAK)-D camera. Results from real flight tests indicate that the system can reduce levels of object detection uncertainty to locate and map desiccation cracks in environments under partial observability. The system design allows further adaptation for similar time-critical applications requiring increased levels of UAV autonomy in unstructured environments under uncertainty and partial observability, such as humanitarian relief, wildlife monitoring, and surveillance.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 IEEE Aerospace Conference (AERO)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 IEEE Aerospace Conference (AERO)</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49790/J. Sandino et al. - 2022 - Autonomous Mapping of Desiccation Cracks via a Pro.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><custom3>2022 IEEE Aerospace Conference (AERO)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>M. Borowczak</author><author>G. Purdy</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>S-CHIRP: Secure communication for heterogeneous IoTs with round-robin protection</title><secondary-title>2018 IEEE International Conference on Consumer Electronics (ICCE)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2018 IEEE International Conference on Consumer Electronics (ICCE)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-6</pages><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>12-14 Jan. 2018</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2158-4001</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICCE.2018.8326301</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This work introduces CHIRP - an algorithm for communication between ultra-portable heterogeneous IoT devices with a type of round-robin protection mechanism. This algorithm is presented both in its basic form as well as in a secured form in order to secure and maintain trust boundaries and communication within specific groups of heterogeneous devices. The specific target application scenarios includes resource constrained environments where a co-located swarm of devices (adversarial in mission or objective) is also present. CHIRP, and its secured version (S-CHIRP), enables complete peer-to-peer communication of a n-agent network of devices in as few as n rounds. In addition to the n-round cycle length, the proposed communication mechanism has the following major properties: nodes communication is entirely decentralized, communication is resilient to the loss of nodes, and finally communication is resilient to the (re)-entry of nodes. Theoretical models show that even the secure implementation of this mechanism is capable of scaling to IoT swarms in the million device range with memory constraints in the &lt;; 10 MB range.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2018 IEEE International Conference on Consumer Electronics (ICCE)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2018 IEEE International Conference on Consumer Electronics (ICCE)</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49792/M. Borowczak and G. Purdy - 2018 - S-CHIRP Secure communication for heterogeneous Io.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><custom3>2018 IEEE International Conference on Consumer Electronics (ICCE)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>S. Basu</author><author>S. Banerjee</author><author>T. Halder</author><author>A. K. Das</author><author>S. Sarkar</author><author>A. Basak</author><author>A. M. Ray</author><author>D. Chakravarty</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Comparative Study on Propagation Models for Routing Protocols in FANETs</title><secondary-title>2021 IEEE International India Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium (InGARSS)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2021 IEEE International India Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium (InGARSS)</full-title></periodical><pages>528-531</pages><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>6-10 Dec. 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/InGARSS51564.2021.9792118</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Rapid growth of technology and sudden high demand of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) has significantly influenced the design and development of efficient and robust UAV network architecture, propagation models, routing techniques, etc. Resultantly, in recent years, the usage of UAVs in forms of flying Ad Hoc Networks (FANETs), especially drone swarms, in disaster recovery, military applications, forest surveillance, critical missions, emergency services, etc. are becoming more popular and powerful. However, selection of propagation models in FANETs is always a challenge due to its wireless shared links, individual drone’s mobility, limited power, etc. Hence, in this paper, we study propagation models for performance comparison of routing protocols in FANETs. Specifically, we study and present simulation results of Lutz and ITU Recommendation series to compare Ad hoc On demand Distance Vector Routing (AODV) and Destination Sequenced Distance Vector Routing (DSDV), two widely used routing protocols in FANETs considering rain attenuation. Finally, a plot of the Cramer-Rao Lower Bound has also been presented in order to provide better clarity for depicting the performances of FANETs’ routing protocols.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 IEEE International India Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium (InGARSS)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 IEEE International India Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium (InGARSS)</research-notes><custom3>2021 IEEE International India Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium (InGARSS)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Jun Peng</author><author>Min Wu</author><author>Xiaoyong Zhang</author><author>Ya Xie</author><author>Fu Jiang</author><author>Ya Liu</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Collaborative Multi-Agent Model with Knowledge-Based Communication for the RoboCupRescue Simulation</title><secondary-title>Proceedings of the 2006 International Symposium on Collaborative Technologies and Systems, CTS 2006</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Symposium on Collaborative Technologies and Systems (CTS'06)</full-title></periodical><pages>341-348</pages><volume>2006</volume><keywords><keyword>Decision making</keyword><keyword>Multi agent systems</keyword><keyword>Cooperation</keyword><keyword>Multi-agent system</keyword><keyword>Intelligent agents</keyword><keyword>Knowledge based systems</keyword><keyword>Algorithms</keyword><keyword>Computer simulation</keyword><keyword>Knowledge communication</keyword><keyword>Particle swarm optimal (PSO)</keyword><keyword>RoboCupRescue</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2006</year><pub-dates><date>14-17 May 2006</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>0978569903 (ISBN); 978-097856990-7 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/CTS.2006.2</electronic-resource-num><abstract>An effective cooperation model in a Multi-Agent system is required to enable agents to interact and achieve their task proficiently. To address this problem, we propose a collaborative hierarchical Multi-Agent model based on two layers (Administrant layer and Autonomous layer), which makes use of the knowledge-based communication to actualize interaction in this model. Task planning and allocation are implemented in the administrant layer by using U-Tree algorithm, where reward function and evaluation value are introduced to control selection factors. Agents are allowed to work together using architectures like swarm and information update value in the autonomous layer, so that centralized and decentralized control can be integrated effectively. Moreover, this collaboration model has been applied successfully in CSU_Yunlu RoboCupRescue simulation team to show its advantages over other approaches, which will be about to participate in international RoboCupRescue 2006 in June. © 2006 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 5; Correspondence Address: P. Jun; School of Information Science and Engineering, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan 410075, China; email: pengj@mail.csu.edu.cn; Conference name: 2006 International Symposium on Collaborative Technologies and Systems, CTS 2006; Conference date: 14 May 2006 through 17 May 2006; Conference code: 68801&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: International Symposium on Collaborative Technologies and Systems (CTS'06)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proc. Int. Symp. Collabor. Technol. Syst.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: International Symposium on Collaborative Technologies and Systems (CTS'06)</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-33845587725&amp;doi=10.1109%2fCTS.2006.2&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=ee581ea82379178d607965dff8882551</url></web-urls></urls><custom3>International Symposium on Collaborative Technologies and Systems (CTS'06)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>T. D. Khanh</author><author>I. Komarov</author><author>L. D. Don</author><author>R. Iureva</author><author>S. Chuprov</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>TRA: Effective Authentication Mechanism for Swarms Of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles</title><secondary-title>2020 IEEE Symposium Series on Computational Intelligence, SSCI 2020</secondary-title><tertiary-title>2020 IEEE Symposium Series on Computational Intelligence, SSCI 2020</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2020 IEEE Symposium Series on Computational Intelligence, SSCI 2020, December 1, 2020 - December 4, 2020</full-title></periodical><pages>1852-1858</pages><keywords><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Military vehicles</keyword><keyword>Dynamic environments</keyword><keyword>unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Rock mechanics</keyword><keyword>Maneuverability</keyword><keyword>Mission requirements</keyword><keyword>Authentication</keyword><keyword>security</keyword><keyword>swarm</keyword><keyword>Ground control stations</keyword><keyword>Intelligent computing</keyword><keyword>authentication</keyword><keyword>SCHEME</keyword><keyword>Authentication mechanisms</keyword><keyword>Communication environments</keyword><keyword>Computing performance</keyword><keyword>decentralized approach</keyword><keyword>Direct communications</keyword><keyword>Simulation and results</keyword><keyword>KEY AGREEMENT PROTOCOL</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>1-4 Dec. 2020</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-172812547-3 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/SSCI47803.2020.9308140</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The swarm of the unmanned aerial vehicles is researched to meet the special mission requirements given both in the military and civilian sectors such as fire detection, sky reconnaissance, and other areas of human activities. These swarms can directly contact via ground control station or direct communication. However, when communicating remotely via wireless and fine maneuverability of the unmanned aerial vehicle, many mechanisms face several security gaps, such as the authentication mechanism in enemy attacks. In this study, we propose safe and effective authentication mechanism appropriate for the dynamic environment of the unmanned aerial vehicle. In the frames of this approach, a new operating mechanism in the proposed protocol is described. The protocol provides authentication security for swarms of the unmanned aerial vehicle. Our scheme allows good communication and computing performance as well as storage cost. Finally, simulation and results in the communication environment between drones are presented. © 2020 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 6; Conference name: 2020 IEEE Symposium Series on Computational Intelligence, SSCI 2020; Conference date: 1 December 2020 through 4 December 2020; Conference code: 166370&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 IEEE Symposium Series on Computational Intelligence (SSCI)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 IEEE Symposium Series on Computational Intelligence, SSCI 2020, December 1, 2020 - December 4, 2020&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 IEEE SYMPOSIUM SERIES ON COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE (SSCI)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Symp. Ser. Comput. Intell., SSCI&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 IEEE Symposium Series on Computational Intelligence, SSCI 2020, December 1, 2020 - December 4, 2020</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85099693868&amp;doi=10.1109%2fSSCI47803.2020.9308140&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=1f6e36b2e8665de1c90babd2bce7ab40</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/SSCI47803.2020.9308140</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Virtual, Canberra, ACT, Australia</custom1><custom3>2020 IEEE Symposium Series on Computational Intelligence, SSCI 2020, December 1, 2020 - December 4, 2020</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>M. Suresh</author><author>D. Ghose</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Group coordination and path replan tactics in GPS denied environments</title><secondary-title>2016 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2016 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)</full-title></periodical><pages>31-39</pages><dates><year>2016</year><pub-dates><date>7-10 June 2016</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICUAS.2016.7502646</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Success of a cooperative mission entirely depends on precise navigation information of each UAV. Though present day UAVs are equipped with GPS, the UAVs have to rely only on navigation information obtained from inertial navigation system while operating in GPS denied environments. This research work, addresses the problem of establishing a GPS protected wireless MAV network (WIMAN) using three classes of navigation system, one equipped only with GPS, an other equipped only with high accuracy inertial navigation system and the third equipped with relatively low accuracy inertial navigation system, to enable missions in GPS denied environments. NP hardness in establishing GPS protected WIMAN architecture is discussed and a heuristic algorithm is proposed. Group coordination and tactical replan procedures, that enable WIMAN to maintain its configuration, reconfiguration to adapt to various phases of cooperative threat reconnaissance mission, is demonstrated through simulation results.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2016 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2016 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)</research-notes><custom3>2016 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>R. Grodi</author><author>D. B. Rawat</author><author>C. Bajracharya</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Performance evaluation of Unmanned Aerial Vehicle ad hoc networks</title><secondary-title>SoutheastCon 2015</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SoutheastCon 2015</full-title></periodical><pages>1-4</pages><dates><year>2015</year><pub-dates><date>9-12 April 2015</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1558-058X</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/SECON.2015.7133020</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) can form an ad-hoc network to communicate and cooperate with each other via wireless links. UAV ad hoc networks have the potential to provide reliable and real-time services using single-hop or multi-hop communications. However, the network topology of a UAV ad-hoc network is highly dynamic because of the fast flying UAVs that result in short lived communication links between UAVs. In mission critical applications, small delays could result in catastrophic outcomes. Thus it is required for UAVs to exchange their information as quickly as possible (with shortest possible delay). In this paper, we evaluate the performance of UAV ad hoc networks by considering the effect of network size on throughput, energy consumption and effective transmission range (total coverage range). Numerical results obtained from simulations are presented to evaluate the performance of UAV ad hoc networks. Our results show that when network size (the number of UAVs) increases, the throughput per UAV and energy consumption decrease while the total network transmission range (effective coverage range) increases.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: SoutheastCon 2015&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: SoutheastCon 2015</research-notes><custom3>SoutheastCon 2015</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>N. Virbora</author><author>U. Sokoeun</author><author>M. Saran</author><author>S. Sovicheyratana</author><author>S. Channareth</author><author>S. Saravuth</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Implementation of Matrix Drone Show Using Automatic Path Generator with DJI Tello Drones</title><secondary-title>8th International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies, ICEET 2022</secondary-title><tertiary-title>8th International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies, ICEET 2022</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>8th International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies, ICEET 2022, October 27, 2022 - October 28, 2022</full-title></periodical><pages>1-5</pages><keywords><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>IEEE Standards</keyword><keyword>Swarm drone</keyword><keyword>Wireless local area networks (WLAN)</keyword><keyword>Wi-Fi</keyword><keyword>Medium access control</keyword><keyword>High level languages</keyword><keyword>Python</keyword><keyword>11n</keyword><keyword>Automatic drone path generator</keyword><keyword>Automatic Drone Path Generator</keyword><keyword>DJI tello EDU</keyword><keyword>DJI Tello EDU</keyword><keyword>Four-group</keyword><keyword>matrix</keyword><keyword>Matrix drone</keyword><keyword>Matrix Drone</keyword><keyword>Path generators</keyword><keyword>Swarm Drone</keyword><keyword>Wi-fi 802.</keyword><keyword>Wi-Fi 802. 11N</keyword><keyword>Wireless access points</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>27-28 Oct. 2022</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-166549106-8 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICEET56468.2022.10007090</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In this paper described the process of designing and applying 100 DJI Tello EDU drones to display various characters following from A to Z and 0 to 9 as letters and words. The drones are divided into four groups, each of 25 drones. Each drone is connected to a wireless access point where the mission control center operates the command to each drone individually in parallel to display the expected letter or words. Python is the programming language used for commanding and controlling the operation. The communication between drones and the mission control computer is done wirelessly with Wi-FiS02.11N technology running at a 2. 4GHz frequency. Each drone is assigned to a specific IP address as an ID based on the unique Media Access Control (MAC) address. To communicate with the drones, the User Diagram Protocol (UDP) protocol is used for the communication. As a result, the matrix drone can perform different flights showing different characters and words including various custom 3D shapes.  © 2022 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 2; Correspondence Address: N. Virbora; Faculty of Electronics, National Polytechnic Institute of Cambodia, Phnom Penh, Cambodia; email: nyvirakbora@gmail.com; Conference name: 8th International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies, ICEET 2022; Conference date: 27 October 2022 through 28 October 2022; Conference code: 185970&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 8th International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies, ICEET 2022, October 27, 2022 - October 28, 2022&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2022 International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies (ICEET)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Int. Conf. Eng. Emerg. Technol., ICEET&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 8th International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies, ICEET 2022, October 27, 2022 - October 28, 2022</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85146876470&amp;doi=10.1109%2fICEET56468.2022.10007090&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=1db0373a6201b6271aed81c6905faee8</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICEET56468.2022.10007090</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia</custom1><custom3>8th International Conference on Engineering and Emerging Technologies, ICEET 2022, October 27, 2022 - October 28, 2022</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>L. E. Caraballo</author><author>J. M. Díaz-Báñez</author><author>R. Fabila-Monroy</author><author>C. Hidalgo-Toscano</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Patrolling a terrain with cooperrative UAVs using Random Walks</title><secondary-title>2019 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2019 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)</full-title></periodical><pages>828-837</pages><dates><year>2019</year><pub-dates><date>11-14 June 2019</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2575-7296</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICUAS.2019.8797915</electronic-resource-num><abstract>A group of UAVs can be used to efficiently patrol a terrain, in which each robot flies around an assigned area and shares information with the neighbors periodically in order to protect or supervise it. To ensure robustness, previous works propose sending a robot to the neighboring area in case it detects a failure. In order to add unpredictability and to improve on the efficiency in the deterministic patrolling scheme, this paper presents random strategies to cover the areas distributed among the agents. We evaluate these strategies using three metrics: the idle-time, the isolation-time and the broadcast-time. The idle-time is the expected time between two consecutive observations of any point of the terrain. The isolation-time is the expected time that a robot is isolated (that is, without communication with any other robot). The broadcast-time is the expected time elapsed from the moment a robot emits a message until it is received by all the other robots of the team. Simulations show that the random strategies outperform the results obtained with the deterministic protocol.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)</research-notes><custom3>2019 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>A. T. Erman</author><author>P. Havinga</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Data dissemination of emergency messages in mobile multi-sink wireless sensor networks</title><secondary-title>2010 The 9th IFIP Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2010 The 9th IFIP Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-8</pages><dates><year>2010</year><pub-dates><date>23-25 June 2010</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/MEDHOCNET.2010.5546870</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In wireless sensor networks (WSNs), data dissemination is generally performed from sensor nodes to a static sink. If the data under consideration is an emergency message such as a fire alarm, it must be transmitted as fast and reliably as possible towards the sink of WSN. In such mission critical applications, it may not be enough to have one static sink but there will be multiple and mobile sinks. Sinks can be associated to first responders such as firefighters, but also to unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs). The existing approaches have a high communication cost and a high delivery latency, which makes them less suitable for emergency situations. As an alternative to existing protocols, we present Honeycomb Architecture and Hexagonal Tiling-Based Data Dissemination (HexDD) protocol for emergency message transmission in mobile multi-sink WSNs. Simulation results show that HexDD has a high data delivery ratio and a very low data delivery latency, which are major requirements for disaster management scenarios.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2010 The 9th IFIP Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2010 The 9th IFIP Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)&#xD;&#xD;UAVs are only tackled on the side&#xD;&#xD;</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49786/A. T. Erman and P. Havinga - 2010 - Data dissemination of emergency messages in mobile.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><custom3>2010 The 9th IFIP Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Y. Chen</author><author>H. Liu</author><author>J. Guo</author><author>Y. Wang</author><author>F. Liu</author><author>S. Ding</author><author>R. Chen</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Cooperative Networking Strategy of UAV Cluster for Large-Scale WSNs</title><secondary-title>IEEE Sensors Journal</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Sensors Journal</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Sensors Journal</abbr-1></periodical><pages>22276-22290</pages><volume>22</volume><number>22</number><issue>22</issue><keywords><keyword>Optimization</keyword><keyword>Data collection</keyword><keyword>Aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Flight simulators</keyword><keyword>Optimisations</keyword><keyword>Data acquisition</keyword><keyword>Swarm intelligence</keyword><keyword>Motion planning</keyword><keyword>Genetic algorithms</keyword><keyword>Energy utilization</keyword><keyword>unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Heuristic algorithms</keyword><keyword>Heuristics algorithm</keyword><keyword>Wireless sensor networks</keyword><keyword>Autonomous aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>data collection</keyword><keyword>Autonomous vehicles</keyword><keyword>Sensor nodes</keyword><keyword>Clustering algorithms</keyword><keyword>Collaborative perception</keyword><keyword>Energy-consumption</keyword><keyword>Life cycle</keyword><keyword>Network energy consumption</keyword><keyword>swarm intelligence algorithm</keyword><keyword>Swarm intelligence algorithms</keyword><keyword>wireless sensor networks (WSNs)</keyword><keyword>Sensors</keyword><keyword>Energy consumption</keyword><keyword>ENERGY</keyword><keyword>WIRELESS SENSOR NETWORKS</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>15 Nov.15, 2022</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1530-437X, 1558-1748</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/JSEN.2022.3212785</electronic-resource-num><abstract>To solve the shortcomings of wireless sensor networks (WSNs) in data collection in a wide range, long distance, and other complex environments, such as high networking cost, short network life cycle, and difficult data collection, a data collection strategy based on the unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) cluster collaborative networking is proposed. First, the node structure and deployment application of WSNs are analyzed, and the architecture of UAV collaborative data collection is designed. Second, the related models of communication energy consumption between WSNs' network and UAV cluster, UAV cluster task allocation, and path planning are established successively. Then, a simple but efficient task planning strategy considering UAV forward and return distances is proposed. Finally, for the problem of model solving, the solution strategy of the heuristic swarm intelligence algorithm is proposed. The simulation results verify that the strategy reduces the overall network energy consumption by 42.16% and the total range of UAV by 9.7% and realizes the relative minimization of WSNs energy consumption and UAV flight cost on the premise of ensuring the full coverage of WSNs' nodes.  © 2001-2012 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 6; Correspondence Address: H. Liu; Nanjing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics, State Key Laboratory of Mechanics and Control of Mechanical Structures, Nanjing, 210016, China; email: rtlhxx@nuaa.edu.cn</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://ieeexplore-ieee-org.proxy1-bib.sdu.dk/document/9918630</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSEN.2022.3212785</url></text-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>G. Grieco</author><author>G. Iacovelli</author><author>P. Boccadoro</author><author>L. A. Grieco</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>On the Design of the Drone Control Layer</title><secondary-title>European Wireless 2021; 26th European Wireless Conference</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>European Wireless 2021; 26th European Wireless Conference</full-title></periodical><pages>1-7</pages><keywords><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>Middleware</keyword><keyword>Complex mission</keyword><keyword>Networking architecture</keyword><keyword>Control layers</keyword><keyword>Mission design</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>10-12 Nov. 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><abstract>The Internet of Drones (IoD) is a networking architecture born to leverage the huge potential of Internet-connected drones. A key challenge for the IoD is represented by the technological fragmentation of its components. To this end, a middleware solution, namely Drone Control Layer (DCL), is proposed hereby, which enables complex mission design when heterogeneous swarms are considered. The DCL is made of four interfaces which abstract underlying drivers and hardware, provide a set of common primitives to applications, enable communications between drones, and other logical entities. To illustrate its applicability, relevant scenarios of interest are analyzed in details.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 1; Conference name: 26th European Wireless Conference, EW 2021; Conference date: 10 November 2021 through 12 November 2021; Conference code: 176877&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Eur. Wirel. Conf., EW&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Eur. Wirel. Conf., EW&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: European Wireless 2021; 26th European Wireless Conference&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: European Wireless 2021; 26th European Wireless Conference</research-notes><custom3>European Wireless 2021; 26th European Wireless Conference</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Han, K.</author><author>Nuaimi, E. A.</author><author>Blooshi, S. A.</author><author>Psiakis, R.</author><author>Yeun, C. Y.</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Su C</author><author>Gritzalis D</author><author>Piuri V</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>A New Scalable Mutual Authentication in Fog-Edge Drone Swarm Environment</title><secondary-title>Lecture Notes in Computer Science (including subseries Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence and Lecture Notes in Bioinformatics)</secondary-title><tertiary-title>Lecture Notes in Computer Science (including subseries Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence and Lecture Notes in Bioinformatics)</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>17th International Conference on Information Security Practice and Experience, ISPEC 2022, November 23, 2022 - November 25, 2022</full-title></periodical><pages>179-196</pages><volume>13620 LNCS</volume><keywords><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>UAV</keyword><keyword>Drone swarm</keyword><keyword>Authentication</keyword><keyword>Fog</keyword><keyword>Cryptography</keyword><keyword>Large-scales</keyword><keyword>Ground stations</keyword><keyword>PROTOCOL</keyword><keyword>Authentication protocols</keyword><keyword>Drone Swarm</keyword><keyword>Efficient authentication</keyword><keyword>Fog-edge</keyword><keyword>Fog-Edge</keyword><keyword>Key compromise</keyword><keyword>Mutual authentication</keyword><keyword>PUF</keyword><keyword>Scalable authentication</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>2022</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Springer Science and Business Media Deutschland GmbH</publisher><isbn>03029743 (ISSN); 978-303121279-6 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/978-3-031-21280-2_10</electronic-resource-num><abstract>A drone swarm is a preferable way in deploying drones for large-scale missions. In establishing drone swarms, secure communication between a fog drone and several edge drones is essential to mutually authenticate each other. Although many research works proposed the designs of mutual authentications, none of them meets the adequate security for the drone swarm environments, requiring either involvement of the ground station during the authentication process or expensive PKI-based crypto operations. Only a few works proposed more lightweight authentication, however, they are still vulnerable to key compromises in addition to the limited flexibility and scalability. In this work, we propose an efficient and scalable authentication protocol for fog-edge drone swarm environments, enabling mutual authentication between fog and edges without involving the ground station. We also show the design can leverage various hardware-assisted security functions. Protocol evaluations show security requirements satisfaction while achieving 14–20 times less computation overhead as compared to PKI-based models. © 2022, Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 3; Correspondence Address: K. Han; Technology Innovation Institute, Adu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; email: kyusuk.han@tii.ae; Conference name: 17th International Conference on Information Security Practice and Experience, ISPEC 2022; Conference date: 23 November 2022 through 25 November 2022; Conference code: 287289&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 17th International Conference on Information Security Practice and Experience, ISPEC 2022, November 23, 2022 - November 25, 2022&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: INFORMATION SECURITY PRACTICE AND EXPERIENCE, ISPEC 2022&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Lect. Notes Comput. Sci.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 17th International Conference on Information Security Practice and Experience, ISPEC 2022, November 23, 2022 - November 25, 2022</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85145200697&amp;doi=10.1007%2f978-3-031-21280-2_10&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=388b5c7e4c154f7afd469dd9658a9e9d</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-21280-2_10</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Taipei, Taiwan</custom1><custom3>17th International Conference on Information Security Practice and Experience, ISPEC 2022, November 23, 2022 - November 25, 2022</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Aydln, E. E.</author><author>Kara, O.</author><author>Cakir, F.</author><author>Cansiz, B. S.</author><author>Secinti, G.</author><author>Canberk, B.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Enabling Self-Organizing TDMA Scheduling for Aerial Swarms</title><secondary-title>DroNet 2022 - Proceedings of the 2022 8th Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications, Part of MobiSys 2022</secondary-title><tertiary-title>DroNet 2022 - Proceedings of the 2022 8th Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications, Part of MobiSys 2022</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>8th Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications, DroNet 2022 - Part of MobiSys 2022, July 1, 2022</full-title></periodical><pages>13-18</pages><keywords><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Military operations</keyword><keyword>Ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Ad-hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Cost effectiveness</keyword><keyword>Self-organising</keyword><keyword>Reliable communication</keyword><keyword>Internet protocols</keyword><keyword>Protocol design</keyword><keyword>ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Time division multiple access</keyword><keyword>Aerial swarm</keyword><keyword>aerial swarms</keyword><keyword>Applications domains</keyword><keyword>contention</keyword><keyword>Contention</keyword><keyword>protocol design</keyword><keyword>Self-organizing time division multiple access</keyword><keyword>self-organizing time division multiple access (STDMA)</keyword><keyword>TDMA scheduling</keyword><keyword>Time-division multiple access</keyword><keyword>contention, ad hoc networks, self-organizing time division multiple access (STDMA), protocol design, aerial swarms</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>2022</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery, Inc</publisher><isbn>978-145039405-5 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3539493.3539584</electronic-resource-num><abstract>With the proliferation of affordable VTOL drones, application domain of aerial swarms expands everyday, spanning from public drone art to offensive military operations. Orchestrating these systems towards a successful mission, especially in contested environments, requires strict synchronization and reliable communication among network entities. Although using a ground controller with a long range link provides a cost-effective solution, it is extremely vulnerable to single-point of failure and/or jamming attacks. Thus, in contested environments, adapting ad-hoc policies is one of the most promising approaches, mitigating these vulnerabilities. However, existing ad-hoc approaches fail to sustain multi-hop connections, suffering from frequent topology changes and intermittent links due to dynamic environment. In this paper, we propose self-organizing TDMA (STDMA) protocol for aerial swarms in order to ensure reliable communication through efficient network management. We also partially implement our protocol on a small-scale test-bed and show that how drones are able to self-configure upon joining the network without any prior information. Our proposed STDMA protocol improves the overall channel utilization up to 55 percent with less control traffic overhead compared to the existing studies.  © 2022 ACM.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: E.E. Aydln; Istanbul Technical University, Istanbul, Turkey; email: aydinesi16@itu.edu.tr; Conference name: 8th Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications, DroNet 2022 - Part of MobiSys 2022; Conference code: 180584&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 8th Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications, DroNet 2022 - Part of MobiSys 2022, July 1, 2022&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: DroNet - Proc. Workshop Micro Aer. Veh. Netw., Syst., AppL., Part MobiSys&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 8th Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications, DroNet 2022 - Part of MobiSys 2022, July 1, 2022</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85135403396&amp;doi=10.1145%2f3539493.3539584&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=082d8afd2145dd62a9a9c86ad7b3d263</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3539493.3539584</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Portland, OR, United states</custom1><custom3>8th Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications, DroNet 2022 - Part of MobiSys 2022, July 1, 2022</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Areias, B.</author><author>Martins, A.</author><author>Paula, N.</author><author>Reis, A. B.</author><author>Sargento, S.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A control and communications platform for procedural mission planning with multiple aerial drones</title><secondary-title>Personal and Ubiquitous Computing</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Personal and Ubiquitous Computing</full-title><abbr-1>Pers. Ubiquitous Comp.</abbr-1></periodical><pages>1105-1115</pages><volume>26</volume><number>4</number><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Mission planning</keyword><keyword>Aircraft control</keyword><keyword>Autonomous flight</keyword><keyword>Ground communications</keyword><keyword>Loosely coupled</keyword><keyword>Automated sensing</keyword><keyword>Aerial drones</keyword><keyword>Drone networks</keyword><keyword>Communications platform</keyword><keyword>Message handling</keyword><keyword>Modular solution</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>2022</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>16174909 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/s00779-020-01378-3</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Leveraging recent advances in autonomous flight capabilities of commercially available drone equipment, we report on the development of a modular solution for multi-drone control that implements the functionality required for planning, execution, and monitoring of procedural, multi-step missions with optional drone cooperation. The platform consists of loosely coupled components interacting via message brokers, which we evaluate through a pair of real-life experiments that emulate reference use-cases. We then look into the performance of drone-to-ground communications, with a particular focus on latency. We implement a dedicated, low-resource communications module with efficient serialization protocols and asynchronous message handling, to compare against the built-in message broker approach. Our data shows the importance of low-level prioritization of drone control requests and indicates that message broker approaches may not be suitable for drone swarms. © 2020, Springer-Verlag London Ltd., part of Springer Nature.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 0; Correspondence Address: S. Sargento; Instituto de Telecomunicações, University of Aveiro, Aveiro, Portugal; email: susana@ua.pt</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85081747115&amp;doi=10.1007%2fs00779-020-01378-3&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=7a84bf9faa97496970642351f893495d</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ulku, E. E.</author><author>Dogan, B.</author><author>Demir, O.</author><author>Bekmezci, I.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Sharing location information in multi-UAV systems by common channel multi-token circulation method in FANETs</title><secondary-title>Elektronika ir Elektrotechnika</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Elektronika ir Elektrotechnika</full-title><abbr-1>Elektron. Elektrotech.</abbr-1></periodical><pages>66-71</pages><volume>25</volume><number>1</number><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Flying Ad Hoc networks (FANET)</keyword><keyword>Mobile Ad Hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Multi-token circulation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2019</year><pub-dates><date>2019</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>13921215 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.5755/j01.eie.25.1.22738</electronic-resource-num><abstract>—Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) technology is being used increasingly for military and civilian purposes. The primary reason for this increase is that UAVs eliminate the risk to human life in difficult and dangerous missions, are cost effective, and easily are deployed. Developments in UAV technology and decreasing costs have increased UAV usage. However, when multiple UAVs are deployed, inter UAV communication becomes complicated. For this reason, communication in multi-UAV systems is the most important problem that needs to be solved. To enable communication among UAVs without infrastructure support, a Flying Ad Hoc Network (FANET) is used. A FANET provides UAVs to fly in tandem without colliding. To ensure coordinated flight, UAVs require the location information of other UAVs. In this study, we developed a common channel multi-token circulation protocol to share location information in multi-UAV systems that communicate using a FANET. The proposed method ensures that UAVs in multi-UAV systems know each other's coordinate information with minimum error. © 2019 Kauno Technologijos Universitetas. All Rights Reserved.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 5; Correspondence Address: E.E. Ulku; Department of Computer Engineering, Marmara University Faculty of Technology, Goztepe Campus, Kadikoy – Istanbul, 34722, Turkey; email: emre.ulku@marmara.edu.tr</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85061599884&amp;doi=10.5755%2fj01.eie.25.1.22738&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=3e2f09cf2ba6ee4bc25b163c7a9b186f</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49781/Ulku et al. - 2019 - Sharing location information in multi-UAV systems .pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wedaj, S.</author><author>Paul, K.</author><author>Ribeiro, V. J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>DADS: Decentralized attestation for device swarms</title><secondary-title>ACM Transactions on Privacy and Security</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Transactions on Privacy and Security</full-title><abbr-1>ACM Transactions on Privacy and Security</abbr-1></periodical><pages>Article 19</pages><volume>22</volume><number>3</number><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Security</keyword><keyword>Embedded systems</keyword><keyword>security</keyword><keyword>Cyber Physical System</keyword><keyword>Dynamic network</keyword><keyword>SECURITY</keyword><keyword>INTERNET</keyword><keyword>WIRELESS</keyword><keyword>THINGS</keyword><keyword>Decentralized attestation</keyword><keyword>Dynamic networks</keyword><keyword>Remote attestation</keyword><keyword>Swarm attestation</keyword><keyword>decentralized attestation</keyword><keyword>dynamic networks</keyword><keyword>SOFTWARE-BASED ATTESTATION</keyword><keyword>swarm attestation</keyword><keyword>dynamic networks, decentralized attestation, Remote attestation, security, swarm attestation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2019</year><pub-dates><date>JUL 2019</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2471-2566, 2471-2574</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3325822</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We present a novel scheme called Decentralized Attestation for Device Swarms (DADS), which is, to the best of our knowledge, the first to accomplish decentralized attestation in device swarms. Device swarms are smart, mobile, and interconnected devices that operate in large numbers and are likely to be part of emerging applications in Cyber-Physical Systems (CPS) and Industrial Internet of Things (IIoTs). Swarm devices process and exchange safety, privacy, and mission-critical information. Thus, it is important to have a good code verification technique that scales to device swarms and establishes trust among collaborating devices. DADS has several advantages over current state-of-the-art swarm attestation techniques: It is decentralized, has no single point of failure, and can handle changing topologies after nodes are compromised. DADS assures system resilience to node compromise/failure while guaranteeing only devices that execute genuine code remain part of the group. We conduct performance measurements of communication, computation, memory, and energy using the TrustLite embedded systems architecture in OMNeT++ simulation environment. We show that the proposed approach can significantly reduce communication cost and is very efficient in terms of computation, memory, and energy requirements. We also analyze security and show that DADS is very effective and robust against various attacks. © 2019 Association for Computing Machinery.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 9</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://dl-acm-org.proxy1-bib.sdu.dk/doi/pdf/10.1145/3325822</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3325822</url></text-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Touati, Haifa</author><author>Chriki, Amira</author><author>Snoussi, Hichem</author><author>Kamoun, Farouk</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Cognitive Radio and Dynamic TDMA for efficient UAVs swarm communications</title><secondary-title>Computer Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Computer Networks</full-title><abbr-1>Computer Networks</abbr-1></periodical><pages>108264</pages><volume>196</volume><keywords><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Military applications</keyword><keyword>Military vehicles</keyword><keyword>Rock mechanics</keyword><keyword>Software radio</keyword><keyword>Bandwidth</keyword><keyword>Military communications</keyword><keyword>MAC</keyword><keyword>Communication</keyword><keyword>Cognitive radio</keyword><keyword>Time division multiple access</keyword><keyword>VEHICLES</keyword><keyword>MOBILITY</keyword><keyword>SENSOR</keyword><keyword>SCHEME</keyword><keyword>Cognitive Radio</keyword><keyword>Spectrum sharing</keyword><keyword>TDMA</keyword><keyword>Unmanned Aerial Vehicles Swarm</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>SEP 4 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1389-1286, 1872-7069</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.comnet.2021.108264</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In the last decades, under technological progress in electronic and avionics systems, Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) have known an increasing use in several military and civilian missions. Multiple UAVs can cooperatively carry out dangerous applications for human operators or missions where human intervention is not needed, such as surveillance and monitoring of areas of interest and physical infrastructures. Due to the lack of proper communication rules and standards, communication remains one of the most crucial design issues for UAVs swarm. Furthermore, UAVs generally operate in frequency bands shared with other users. Hence, these spectral bands become overcrowded and UAVs may face a spectrum scarcity issue. To address the above challenges, it is essential to define a reliable communication architecture for multiple UAVs coordination and efficient bandwidth sharing. A promising technology that can satisfy the spectrum requirements of the emerging UAVs Networks is Cognitive Radio Network (CRN). The goal is to opportunistically use spectral bands with minimum interference to other users or applications, i.e., primary users. In this paper, we consider the problem of spectrum scarcity encountered by UAVs. We present a centralized CRN-based communication approach for UAVs-Ground Control Station (GCS) communication. The GCS is used as a central coordinator to handle bandwidth usage for the UAVs swarm in its coverage zone. It selects, allocates, and shares available frequencies using CRN and Software Defined Radio (SDR). To share the available CRN-frequency between the different UAVs in its scope, the GCS uses dynamic Time Division Multiple Access (TDMA) technique. The performance of the proposed communication approach is evaluated in a surveillance context in terms of the total time required to transfer UAVs data, the total number of packets sent, and the achieved throughput.  2021 Elsevier B.V.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.comnet.2021.108264</url></text-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wang, Shuo</author><author>Shi, DongMei</author><author>Dong, Yu</author><author>Huang, Kai</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Research on distributed task allocation of loitering munition swarm</title><tertiary-title>Proceedings - 2020 International Conference on Information Science, Parallel and Distributed Systems, ISPDS 2020</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2020 International Conference on Engineering Management of Communication and Technology, EMCTECH 2020, October 20, 2020 - October 22, 2020</full-title></periodical><pages>162-166</pages><keywords><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Ammunition</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>2020</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ISPDS51347.2020.00041</electronic-resource-num><abstract>With the continuous development of unmanned systems swarm technology, the loitering munition swarm technology has gained wide attention from various countries for its unique combat advantages, and the task allocation technology is the key guarantee for its completion of combat missions. With regard to this technology, the first and second part of this article introduced the current development, the classification standards and system architecture of task allocation. The third part analyzed the typical distinctions between loitering munition swarm and unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) swarm, conducted multiconstraint analysis, summed up the dynamic burst states, established the modeling of distributed task allocation and the performance evaluation function, and also summarized the advantages and disadvantages of typical algorithms. The fourth part prospected the development direction and research focus, and the last part is the conclusion.  2020 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 International Conference on Engineering Management of Communication and Technology, EMCTECH 2020, October 20, 2020 - October 22, 2020&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 International Conference on Engineering Management of Communication and Technology, EMCTECH 2020, October 20, 2020 - October 22, 2020</research-notes><urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ISPDS51347.2020.00041</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Vienna, Austria</custom1><custom3>2020 International Conference on Engineering Management of Communication and Technology, EMCTECH 2020, October 20, 2020 - October 22, 2020</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sanjay Sarma, O. V.</author><author>Vishwanath Lohit, T.</author><author>Pugazhenthi, S.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Development and testing of a foraging strategy for low cost Swarm Robots</title><tertiary-title>CARE 2013 - 2013 IEEE International Conference on Control, Automation, Robotics and Embedded Systems, Proceedings</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2013 IEEE International Conference on Control, Automation, Robotics and Embedded Systems, CARE 2013, December 16, 2013 - December 18, 2013</full-title></periodical><pages>IEEE</pages><keywords><keyword>Costs</keyword><keyword>Planning</keyword><keyword>Swarm intelligence</keyword><keyword>Robots</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>2013</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/CARE.2013.6733742</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This article presents a strategy and development of low cost Swarm Robots for foraging with combined collective exploration for target and aggregation strategies. The robots in the swarm communicate with each other by a predefined message protocol of assigning priorities. The communication strategy developed is simulated on a self-developed simulator applying real time constrains. The communication between robots is established by generating message matrices during simulation in 2D and 3D detail. This article further details the development of hardware for low cost swarm robots and testing at micro level.  2013 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2013 IEEE International Conference on Control, Automation, Robotics and Embedded Systems, CARE 2013, December 16, 2013 - December 18, 2013&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2013 IEEE International Conference on Control, Automation, Robotics and Embedded Systems, CARE 2013, December 16, 2013 - December 18, 2013</research-notes><urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/CARE.2013.6733742</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Jabalpur, India</custom1><custom3>2013 IEEE International Conference on Control, Automation, Robotics and Embedded Systems, CARE 2013, December 16, 2013 - December 18, 2013</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Shim, Sangwoo</author><author>Kim, Taehun</author><author>Hyun, Soon J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Control Integrated Query Processing System for Coordination of Multiple UAVs</title><secondary-title>14th IEEE Annual Consumer Communications and Networking Conference (CCNC)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2017 14TH IEEE ANNUAL CONSUMER COMMUNICATIONS &amp; NETWORKING CONFERENCE (CCNC)</full-title></periodical><pages>528-533</pages><keywords><keyword>Multi-UAV system</keyword><keyword>Automation system</keyword><keyword>Query Processor</keyword><keyword>Testbed implemenation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>2017</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>IEEE</publisher><isbn>978-1-5090-6196-9</isbn><abstract>Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) are gaining more popularity thanks to their versatility, miniaturization, and inexpensiveness. Beyond the limits of single UAV system, multi-UAV systems which can perform complex mission-oriented tasks better have been recently introduced. However, previous systems are less automated in the way that human intervention is still required to execute missions, and they were implemented for the only purpose of carrying out specific scenarios. In this paper, in order to automate the required procedures in the system and increase system flexibility, we propose a control integrated query processing system for coordination of multiple UAVs. We devise a high level query language to express a user command for a variety of UAVs' tasks by integrating the ways of controlling movements and actions of multiple UAVs and collecting data from them. We present the overall architecture of the query processing system and experimental results on testbed using real UAVs.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 14TH IEEE ANNUAL CONSUMER COMMUNICATIONS &amp; NETWORKING CONFERENCE (CCNC)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 14TH IEEE ANNUAL CONSUMER COMMUNICATIONS &amp; NETWORKING CONFERENCE (CCNC)</research-notes><language>English</language><custom1>New York</custom1><custom3>2017 14TH IEEE ANNUAL CONSUMER COMMUNICATIONS &amp; NETWORKING CONFERENCE (CCNC)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ribeiro, Laura Michaella Batista</author><author>Muller, Ivan</author><author>Buss Becker, Leandro</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Communication Interface Manager for Improving Performance of Heterogeneous UAV Networks</title><secondary-title>SENSORS</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SENSORS</full-title><abbr-1>Sensors</abbr-1></periodical><pages>4255</pages><volume>21</volume><number>13</number><issue>13</issue><keywords><keyword>UAV</keyword><keyword>mobility</keyword><keyword>wireless networks</keyword><keyword>FANETS</keyword><keyword>SYSTEMS</keyword><keyword>ARCHITECTURE</keyword><keyword>802.11P</keyword><keyword>connection stability</keyword><keyword>IEEE standards</keyword><keyword>message reliability</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>JUL 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1424-8220</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.3390/s21134255</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Exchanging messages with stable connections in missions composed of multiple unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV) remains a challenge. The variations in UAV distances from each other, considering their individual trajectories, and the medium dynamic factors are important points to be addressed.In this context, to increase the stability of UAV-to-UAV (U2U) communication with link quality, this paper presents an interface manager (IM) that is capable of improving communication in multi-UAV networks.Given a predefined set of available individual wireless interfaces, the proposed IM dynamically defines the best interface for sending messages based on on-flight conditions sensed and calculated dynamically from the wireless medium. Different simulation scenarios are generated using a complex and realistic experimental setup composed of traditional simulators such as NS-3, Gazebo, and GzUAV. IEEE 802.11n 2.4 GHz and 802.11p 5 GHz interfaces are used for the IM selection. The IM performance is evaluated in terms of metrics from the medium-access-control (MAC) and physical layers, which aim to improve and maintain the connectivity between the UAVs during the mission, and from the application layer, which targets the reliability in the delivery of messages. The obtained results show that compared with the cases where a single interface is used, the proposed IM is able to increase the network throughput and presents the best proportion of transmitted and received packets, reception power (-60 dBm to -75 dBm), and loss (-80 dB to -85 dB), resulting in a more efficient and stable network connections.</abstract><language>English</language><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49779/Ribeiro et al. - 2021 - Communication Interface Manager for Improving Perf.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Han, Bo</author><author>Hu, Chaofang</author><author>Zhou, Yimin</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Fu, M.</author><author>Sun, J.</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>The Ground Station Design for Swarm Unmanned Aerial Vehicle Control</title><secondary-title>38th Chinese Control Conference (CCC)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>PROCEEDINGS OF THE 38TH CHINESE CONTROL CONFERENCE (CCC)</full-title></periodical><pages>8248-8253</pages><keywords><keyword>Software</keyword><keyword>Unmanned Aerial Vehicle</keyword><keyword>Communication Protocol</keyword><keyword>Ground Station Control</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2019</year><pub-dates><date>2019</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>IEEE</publisher><isbn>978-988-15639-7-2</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.23919/chicc.2019.8865734</electronic-resource-num><abstract>With the development of Science and technology and reform in military field, unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) plays more and more key role in the current world. Along with the fast exploration of UAVs, the ground control station (GCS) as the link between people and UAVs is particularly important. In this paper, the UAV based GCS is studied and programmed for software achievement. The involved technologies include multi-thread mechanism, Windows message transmission mechanism and serial port communication technology. AS for the GCS, it can be divided into Main frame interface, link communication, control instruction and map navigation such modules. After the basic function achievement of the GCS. the simulation tests and practical experiments are performed to verify the control performance. Experimental results can demonstrate that the GCS can send the remote control commands to the UAVs accurately in real-time.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: PROCEEDINGS OF THE 38TH CHINESE CONTROL CONFERENCE (CCC)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: PROCEEDINGS OF THE 38TH CHINESE CONTROL CONFERENCE (CCC)</research-notes><language>English</language><custom1>New York</custom1><custom3>PROCEEDINGS OF THE 38TH CHINESE CONTROL CONFERENCE (CCC)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Yang, Qin</author><author>Parasuraman, Ramviyas</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Hierarchical Needs Based Self-Adaptive Framework For Cooperative Multi-Robot System</title><secondary-title>IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics (SMC)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2020 IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON SYSTEMS, MAN, AND CYBERNETICS (SMC)</full-title></periodical><pages>2991-2998</pages><keywords><keyword>ARCHITECTURE</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>2020</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>IEEE</publisher><isbn>978-1-72818-526-2</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/smc42975.2020.9283249</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Research in multi-robot and swarm systems has seen significant interest in cooperation of agents in complex and dynamic environments. To effectively adapt to unknown environments and maximize the utility of the group, robots need to cooperate, share information, and make a suitable plan according to the specific scenario. Inspired by Maslow's hierarchy of human needs and systems theory, we introduce Robot's Need Hierarchy and propose a new solution called Self-Adaptive Swarm System (SASS). It combines multi-robot perception, communication, planning, and execution with the cooperative management of conflicts through a distributed Negotiation-Agreement Mechanism that prioritizes robot's needs. We also decompose the complex tasks into simple executable behaviors through several Atomic Operations, such as selection, formation, and routing. We evaluate SASS through simulating static and dynamic tasks and comparing them with the state-of-the-art collision-aware task assignment method integrated into our framework.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON SYSTEMS, MAN, AND CYBERNETICS (SMC)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON SYSTEMS, MAN, AND CYBERNETICS (SMC)</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49784/Yang and Parasuraman - 2020 - Hierarchical Needs Based Self-Adaptive Framework F.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><custom1>New York</custom1><custom3>2020 IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON SYSTEMS, MAN, AND CYBERNETICS (SMC)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hong, Chen</author><author>Shi, Dianxi</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Cloud-based Control System Architecture for Multi-UAV</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Robotics, Control and Automation</full-title></periodical><pages>25–30</pages><keywords><keyword>Control system architecture, SITL simulator, Unmanned aerial vehicle, Cloud platform</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>2018</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-6530-7</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3265639.3265652</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Robotics, Control and Automation&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Robotics, Control and Automation</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3265639.3265652</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>Chengdu, China</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Robotics, Control and Automation</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Xu, Li</author><author>Liu, Juan</author><author>Xie, Lingfu</author><author>He, Xiaofan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Multi-UAV Navigation and Recharging for Fair and Sustainable Coverage in Wireless Networks</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Advanced Information Science and System</full-title></periodical><pages>Article 76</pages><keywords><keyword>Fairness index, UAV, Deep Reinforcement Learning, Coverage, PPO</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>2022</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-8586-2</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3503047.3503129</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Advanced Information Science and System&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Advanced Information Science and System</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3503047.3503129</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>Sanya, China</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Advanced Information Science and System</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Liu, Xiong</author><author>Yin, Dong</author><author>Zhou, Yongbin</author><author>Liu, Zhihong</author><author>Wang, Yueke</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Dispatching and management methods for communication of UAV swarm</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on High Performance Compilation, Computing and Communications</full-title></periodical><pages>61–67</pages><keywords><keyword>UAV swarm communication, management architecture, ROS</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>2018</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-6337-2</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3195612.3195622</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on High Performance Compilation, Computing and Communications&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on High Performance Compilation, Computing and Communications</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3195612.3195622</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>Hong Kong, Hong Kong</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on High Performance Compilation, Computing and Communications</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zucchi, Artur Carvalho</author><author>Silveira, Regina Melo</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Performance Analysis of Routing Protocol for Ad Hoc UAV Network</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 10th Latin America Networking Conference</full-title></periodical><pages>73–80</pages><keywords><keyword>Routing, UAV, FANET, OLSR, AODV, DSDV</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>2018</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-5922-1</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3277103.3277127</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 10th Latin America Networking Conference&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 10th Latin America Networking Conference</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3277103.3277127</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>São Paulo, Brazil</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 10th Latin America Networking Conference</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hu, Huanfeng</author><author>Shu, Jian</author><author>Liu, Linlan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Performance Analysis of Routing Protocols in UAV Ad Hoc Networks</title></titles><periodical><full-title>2021 International Conference on Mechanical, Aerospace and Automotive Engineering</full-title></periodical><pages>57–63</pages><keywords><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicle, Performance analysis, Ad hoc network, Routing protocol</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>2022</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-8520-6</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3518781.3519205</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 International Conference on Mechanical, Aerospace and Automotive Engineering&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 International Conference on Mechanical, Aerospace and Automotive Engineering</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3518781.3519205</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>Changsha, China</custom1><custom3>2021 International Conference on Mechanical, Aerospace and Automotive Engineering</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kara, Mostefa</author><author>Laouid, Abdelkader</author><author>Bounceur, Ahcene</author><author>Hammoudeh, Mohammad</author><author>Alshaikh, Muath</author><author>Kebache, Romaissa</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Semi-Decentralized Model for Drone Collaboration on Secure Measurement of Positions</title></titles><periodical><full-title>The 5th International Conference on Future Networks &amp;amp; Distributed Systems</full-title></periodical><pages>64–69</pages><keywords><keyword>Consensus, UAV, Secure communication, Drone, Data Collection.</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>2022</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-8734-7</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3508072.3508083</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: The 5th International Conference on Future Networks &amp;amp; Distributed Systems&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: The 5th International Conference on Future Networks &amp;amp; Distributed Systems</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3508072.3508083</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>Dubai, United Arab Emirates</custom1><custom3>The 5th International Conference on Future Networks &amp;amp; Distributed Systems</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Vishnevsky, Vladimir</author><author>Larionov, Andrey</author><author>Zvyagin, Maxim</author><author>Dinh, Truong Duy</author><author>Ovchinnikov, Anton</author><author>Kirichek, Ruslan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Software development for controlling a group of UAVs</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Future Networks and Distributed Systems</full-title></periodical><pages>Article 21</pages><keywords><keyword>Mavlink, flying network, ground positioning, UAV, Ardupilot, swarm, desktop application</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>2021</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-8886-3</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3440749.3442614</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Future Networks and Distributed Systems&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Future Networks and Distributed Systems</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3440749.3442614</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>St.Petersburg, Russian Federation</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Future Networks and Distributed Systems</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Li, Jun</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Throughput-aware Flying Communication Relay Network for Disaster Area Search and Rescue</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 2019 8th International Conference on Networks, Communication and Computing</full-title></periodical><pages>138–141</pages><keywords><keyword>Flying ad hoc networks, throughput aware virtual force, search and rescue, unmanned aerial vehicles</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>2020</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-7702-7</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3375998.3376038</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 2019 8th International Conference on Networks, Communication and Computing&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 2019 8th International Conference on Networks, Communication and Computing</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3375998.3376038</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>Luoyang, China</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 2019 8th International Conference on Networks, Communication and Computing</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>St-Onge, David</author><author>Varadharajan, Vivek-Shankar</author><author>Beltrame, Giovanni</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Tangible Robotic Fleet Control</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 18th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and MultiAgent Systems</full-title></periodical><pages>2387–2389</pages><keywords><keyword>aerial swarm systems, swarm interaction, tangible interface</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2019</year><pub-dates><date>2019</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>International Foundation for Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-6309-9</isbn><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 18th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and MultiAgent Systems&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 18th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and MultiAgent Systems</research-notes><custom1>Montreal QC, Canada</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 18th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and MultiAgent Systems</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>McCune, Ryan</author><author>Madey, Greg</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Decentralized K-means clustering with MANET swarms</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 2014 Symposium on Agent Directed Simulation</full-title></periodical><pages>Article 6</pages><keywords><keyword>agent-based modeling, emergent behavior, DDDAS, clustering, swarm intelligence</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year><pub-dates><date>2014</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Society for Computer Simulation International</publisher><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 2014 Symposium on Agent Directed Simulation&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 2014 Symposium on Agent Directed Simulation</research-notes><custom1>Tampa, Florida</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 2014 Symposium on Agent Directed Simulation</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Khan, Muhammad Asghar</author><author>Khan, Inam Ullah</author><author>Qureshi, Ijaz Mansoor</author><author>Alam, Muhammad Kashif</author><author>Shah, Syed Bilal Hussain</author><author>Shafiq, Muhammad</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Deployment of reliable, simple, and cost-effective medium access control protocols for multi-layer flying ad-hoc networks</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Future Networks and Distributed Systems</full-title></periodical><pages>Article 49</pages><keywords><keyword>ad-hoc network, MAC, IEEE 802.15.1, UAVs, FANETs</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>2018</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-6428-7</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3231053.3231115</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Future Networks and Distributed Systems&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Future Networks and Distributed Systems</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3231053.3231115</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>Amman, Jordan</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Future Networks and Distributed Systems</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wiedner, Florian</author><author>Andre, Jonas</author><author>Mendes, Paulo</author><author>Carle, Georg</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Policy-based routing for Flying Adhoc Networks</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications</full-title></periodical><pages>25–30</pages><keywords><keyword>Routing, Policies, Network Mobility, FANET</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>2022</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-9405-5</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3539493.3539578</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3539493.3539578</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>Portland, OR, USA</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ahmed, Ahmed Abdelmoamen</author><author>Olumide, Abel</author><author>Akinwa, Adeoluwa</author><author>Chouikha, Mohamed</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Constructing 3d maps for dynamic environments using autonomous UAVs</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 16th EAI International Conference on Mobile and Ubiquitous Systems: Computing, Networking and Services</full-title></periodical><pages>504–513</pages><keywords><keyword>autonomous, simulation, UAV, LIDAR, ROS, 3d maps, navigation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>2020</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-7283-1</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3360774.3368200</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;Only a single drone involved&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 16th EAI International Conference on Mobile and Ubiquitous Systems: Computing, Networking and Services&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 16th EAI International Conference on Mobile and Ubiquitous Systems: Computing, Networking and Services</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3360774.3368200</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>Houston, Texas, USA</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 16th EAI International Conference on Mobile and Ubiquitous Systems: Computing, Networking and Services</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bannis, Adeola</author><author>Noh, Hae Young</author><author>Zhang, Pei</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Bleep: motor-enabled audio side-channel for constrained UAVs</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 26th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking</full-title></periodical><pages>Article 26</pages><keywords><keyword>side-channel, motor sound, UAV</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>2020</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-7085-1</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3372224.3419183</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;Not really a communication architecture, but moreover a communication mechanism&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 26th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 26th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3372224.3419183</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>London, United Kingdom</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 26th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking</custom3></record></records></xml>