<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><records><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>A. Kapitonov</author><author>S. Lonshakov</author><author>A. Krupenkin</author><author>I. Berman</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Blockchain-based protocol of autonomous business activity for multi-agent systems consisting of UAVs</title><secondary-title>2017 Workshop on Research, Education and Development of Unmanned Aerial Systems (RED-UAS)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2017 Workshop on Research, Education and Development of Unmanned Aerial Systems (RED-UAS)</full-title></periodical><pages>84-89</pages><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>3-5 Oct. 2017</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/RED-UAS.2017.8101648</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This article describes a method of organizing the communication protocol, which allows agents of the multiagent system (MAS) to make decisions about their actions. Plan activities and interact with each other to perform tasks of modern industrial and business processes based on cyber-physical systems. The main attention is paid to those multi-agent systems, where autonomous agents - robots or smart things - participate in business processes among people, and their activities are organized in an unreliable and unknown environment. The article shows, how to organize a communication system between agents in a peer-to-peer network using the decentralized Ethereum Blochchain technology and smart contracts. The architecture of protocol of autonomous business activity, based on this communication method is given. As a result, the experience of implementation an autonomous economic system with unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV) is described.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 Workshop on Research, Education and Development of Unmanned Aerial Systems (RED-UAS)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 Workshop on Research, Education and Development of Unmanned Aerial Systems (RED-UAS)&#xD;&#xD;UAVs are only an example in this paper to verify the created blockchain architecture. Also, it is not really about drone swarms&#xD;&#xD;</research-notes><custom3>2017 Workshop on Research, Education and Development of Unmanned Aerial Systems (RED-UAS)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Y. Cheriguene</author><author>S. Djellikh</author><author>F. Z. Bousbaa</author><author>N. Lagraa</author><author>A. Lakas</author><author>C. A. Kerrache</author><author>A. E. Karim Tahari</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>SEMRP: an Energy-efficient Multicast Routing Protocol for UAV Swarms</title><secondary-title>Proceedings of the 2020 IEEE/ACM 24th International Symposium on Distributed Simulation and Real Time Applications, DS-RT 2020</secondary-title><tertiary-title>Proceedings of the 2020 IEEE/ACM 24th International Symposium on Distributed Simulation and Real Time Applications, DS-RT 2020</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>24th IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Distributed Simulation and Real Time Applications, DS-RT 2020, September 14, 2020 - September 16, 2020</full-title></periodical><pages>ACM SIGSIM; IEEE Computer Society</pages><keywords><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Energy efficiency</keyword><keyword>Quality of service</keyword><keyword>UAVs</keyword><keyword>Vehicular ad hoc networks</keyword><keyword>Multicasting</keyword><keyword>Power management (telecommunication)</keyword><keyword>Routing protocols</keyword><keyword>Network routing</keyword><keyword>Real time requirement</keyword><keyword>Information delivery</keyword><keyword>Multicast routing protocol</keyword><keyword>Multicast Routing Protocol</keyword><keyword>Network throughput</keyword><keyword>Networking protocols</keyword><keyword>Packet delivery ratio</keyword><keyword>Packet networks</keyword><keyword>Quality of Service parameters</keyword><keyword>SEMRP</keyword><keyword>Service performance</keyword><keyword>Swarm of UAVs</keyword><keyword>AD HOC NETWORKS</keyword><keyword>swarm of UAVs, SEMRP, UAVs, multicast routing protocol</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>14-16 Sept. 2020</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-172817343-6 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/DS-RT50469.2020.9213700</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The deployment of a swarm of cooperative UAVs applications for the execution of distributed tasks has increased attention from both academia and industry researchers. The use of a group of UAVs instead of one single UAV offers many advantages like extending the mission coverage, providing a reliable ad-hoc networks services, and enhancing the service performance, to name a few. However, due to the highly dynamic nature of the swarm topology, the coordination of a large number of UAVs poses new challenges to traditional inter-UAV communication protocols. Therefore, there is a need for the design of new networking protocols that can efficiently support the fast-pace and real-time requirements of a coordinated swarm navigation in various environments. In this paper, we propose SEMRP a Swarm energy-efficient multicast routing protocol for UAVs flying in group formations. The main purpose of SEMRP is to facilitate the control and information delivery between UAVs while minimizing inter-UAV packet loss, packet re-transmission, and end-to-end delay. In this study we show how SEMRP achieves these objectives by taking into account various Quality-of-Service parameters like the network throughput, the UAVs mobility, and energy efficiency to ensure a timely and accurate information delivery to all members of a UAV swarm. The results of the conducted simulation using NS-2 advocate for the efficiency of our proposal through its to two presented versions (SEMRP-v1 and SEMRP-v2) in term of reducing the total emission energy (at least by 10 dBm), optimizing the End-to-End Delay by 44%, and increasing the packet delivery ratio by more than to 22% compared to SP-GMRF protocol.  © 2020 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 17; Conference name: 24th IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Distributed Simulation and Real Time Applications, DS-RT 2020; Conference date: 14 September 2020 through 16 September 2020; Conference code: 163757&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 24th IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Distributed Simulation and Real Time Applications, DS-RT 2020, September 14, 2020 - September 16, 2020&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2020 IEEE/ACM 24th International Symposium on Distributed Simulation and Real Time Applications (DS-RT)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proc. IEEE/ACM Int. Symp. Distrib. Simul. Real Time Appl., DS-RT&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: PROCEEDINGS OF THE 2020 IEEE/ACM 24TH INTERNATIONAL SYMPOSIUM ON DISTRIBUTED SIMULATION AND REAL TIME APPLICATIONS (DS-RT)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the IEEE/ACM 24th International Symposium on Distributed Simulation and Real Time Applications&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 24th IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Distributed Simulation and Real Time Applications, DS-RT 2020, September 14, 2020 - September 16, 2020</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85094813992&amp;doi=10.1109%2fDS-RT50469.2020.9213700&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=1b5e43d3a51deece772e60ce0fcdf7f3</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/DS-RT50469.2020.9213700</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Prague, Czech republic</custom1><custom3>24th IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Distributed Simulation and Real Time Applications, DS-RT 2020, September 14, 2020 - September 16, 2020</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>F. G. Tinetti</author><author>O. C. V. Riveros</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Combining Technologies for Aiding Search Missions with Drones</title><secondary-title>2021 International Conference on Computational Science and Computational Intelligence (CSCI)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2021 International Conference on Computational Science and Computational Intelligence (CSCI)</full-title></periodical><pages>1617-1622</pages><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>15-17 Dec. 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/CSCI54926.2021.00013</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper presents the combination of technologies in an application for aiding search missions. Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV), wireless communications, and image processing and classification technologies are combined for generating warnings to an operator in a search mission. Thus, the UAV would be used to cover a specific ground area communicating images the system should be able to classify. In case a positive image is classified (i.e., one with the object/s being searched for), an operator is warned so that the final decision is made by an expert. In this way, the mostly bored task of looking at images without object being looked for is avoided, and the expert attention could be focused on images with a high probability of having the object/s being looked for. A cloud service is used for image classification (IBM Watson) along with a previously proposed UAV system architecture and a low-cost drone SDK. A proof of concept is described, giving implementation details, and preliminary results. Obtained results show that the general system is a viable solution and set a starting point for enhancing several subsystems for better performance.</abstract><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;Not really architecture&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 International Conference on Computational Science and Computational Intelligence (CSCI)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2021 International Conference on Computational Science and Computational Intelligence (CSCI)</research-notes><custom3>2021 International Conference on Computational Science and Computational Intelligence (CSCI)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>F. Fabra</author><author>W. Zamora</author><author>P. Reyes</author><author>J. A. Sanguesa</author><author>C. T. Calafate</author><author>J. -C. Cano</author><author>P. Manzoni</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>MUSCOP: Mission-Based UAV Swarm Coordination Protocol</title><secondary-title>IEEE Access</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Access</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Access</abbr-1></periodical><pages>72498-72511</pages><volume>8</volume><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>2020</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2169-3536</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2987983</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Nowadays, Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) have become the preferred, and sometimes the only support tool when facing critical scenarios such as earthquakes, search and rescue missions, and border surveillance. In these scenarios, deploying a UAV swarm instead of a single UAV can provide additional benefits when, for example, cargo carrying requirements exceed the lifting power of a single UAV, or when the deployment of several UAVs simultaneously can accelerate the accomplishment of the mission, and broaden the covered area. To this aim, in this paper we present MUSCOP, a protocol that allows multiple UAVs to perfectly coordinate their flight when performing planned missions. Experimental results show that the proposed protocol is able to achieve a high degree of swarm cohesion independently of the swarm formation adopted, and even in the presence of very lossy channels, achieving minimal synchronization delays and very low position offsets with regard to the ideal case.</abstract><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49777/F. Fabra et al. - 2020 - MUSCOP Mission-Based UAV Swarm Coordination Proto.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>F. Fabra</author><author>W. Zamora</author><author>P. Reyes</author><author>C. T. Calafate</author><author>J. -C. Cano</author><author>P. Manzoni</author><author>E. Hernandez-Orallo</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An UAV Swarm Coordination Protocol Supporting Planned Missions</title><secondary-title>2019 28th International Conference on Computer Communication and Networks (ICCCN)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2019 28th International Conference on Computer Communication and Networks (ICCCN)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-9</pages><keywords><keyword>UAV</keyword><keyword>swarm</keyword><keyword>UNMANNED AERIAL VEHICLES</keyword><keyword>ArduSim</keyword><keyword>flight coordination</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2019</year><pub-dates><date>29 July-1 Aug. 2019</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>IEEE</publisher><isbn>978-1-72811-856-7</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICCCN.2019.8847043</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) are being widely used as a valuable tool in critical situations, especially when the access to the target area is difficult or hazardous. In these situations, a swarm of UAVs can provide additional benefits by covering larger areas, thereby speeding up the fulfillment of a mission, or by carrying heavier loads that a single UAV would not support. In this paper we present MUSCOP, a protocol that allows a set of UAVs to properly synchronize their flight in the fulfillment of planned missions. The results obtained show that MUSCOP achieves a high degree of swarm cohesion even in the presence of channel losses, introducing minimum synchronization delays and low position offset errors compared to an ideal scenario.</abstract><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;Duplicate of DOI: 10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2987983&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 28th International Conference on Computer Communication and Networks (ICCCN)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 28th International Conference on Computer Communication and Networks (ICCCN)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 28TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMPUTER COMMUNICATION AND NETWORKS (ICCCN)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 28TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMPUTER COMMUNICATION AND NETWORKS (ICCCN)</research-notes><language>English</language><custom1>New York</custom1><custom3>2019 28th International Conference on Computer Communication and Networks (ICCCN)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>A. Chriki</author><author>H. Touati</author><author>H. Snoussi</author><author>F. Kamoun</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>UAV-GCS Centralized Data-Oriented Communication Architecture for Crowd Surveillance Applications</title><secondary-title>15th IEEE International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing Conference (IEEE IWCMC)</secondary-title><tertiary-title>2019 15th International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing Conference, IWCMC 2019</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>15th IEEE International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing Conference, IWCMC 2019, June 24, 2019 - June 28, 2019</full-title></periodical><pages>2064-2069</pages><keywords><keyword>Information management</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Military vehicles</keyword><keyword>Network architecture</keyword><keyword>Rock mechanics</keyword><keyword>Aircraft control</keyword><keyword>Monitoring</keyword><keyword>Vehicle to vehicle communications</keyword><keyword>Quality of service</keyword><keyword>Unmanned ariel vehicles</keyword><keyword>Vehicle transmissions</keyword><keyword>Bandwidth</keyword><keyword>Crowd surveillance</keyword><keyword>Data communication systems</keyword><keyword>Ground control stations</keyword><keyword>Mobile computing</keyword><keyword>Centralized architecture</keyword><keyword>Critical current density (superconductivity)</keyword><keyword>Crowd Surveillance Applications</keyword><keyword>Data-Oriented communication</keyword><keyword>Ground Control Station (GCS)</keyword><keyword>QoS management</keyword><keyword>QOS management</keyword><keyword>Unmanned Ariel Vehicles(UAV)</keyword><keyword>Wave transmission</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2019</year><pub-dates><date>24-28 June 2019</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-153867747-6 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/IWCMC.2019.8766641</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In recent years, a large number of researchers investigate the conception of systems that use a unique Unmanned Ariel Vehicles (UAV) or multiple independent UAVs to conduct civil or military missions, with minimal human intervention. In this paper we focus on using multiple UAVs to cooperatively monitor a crowded area. Communication in such UAVs network is an ongoing project. Due to the lack of proper communication standards and rules, designing a reliable communication model is essential for: (i) multi-UAV coordination, (ii) efficient bandwidth sharing according to data priority and urgency and (iii) avoiding useless transmission of the same data by multiple UAVs. To address the above challenges, we propose a centralized data-oriented communication architecture for crowd surveillance allocations using an UAV fleet. The Ground Control Station (GCS) is used as a central coordinator to manage bandwidth usage for the UAV fleet in its coverage area. To allow UAVs to send priority messages urgently to the GCS, we define two classes of urgent messages: critical state and important result. The class of the data as well as other relevant information about the detected event will be used by the GCS to authorize or not UAV data transmission and hence to optimize the bandwidth usage efficiency. © 2019 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 22; Conference name: 15th IEEE International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing Conference, IWCMC 2019; Conference date: 24 June 2019 through 28 June 2019; Conference code: 149875&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 15th IEEE International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing Conference, IWCMC 2019, June 24, 2019 - June 28, 2019&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 15th International Wireless Communications &amp; Mobile Computing Conference (IWCMC)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 15TH INTERNATIONAL WIRELESS COMMUNICATIONS &amp; MOBILE COMPUTING CONFERENCE (IWCMC)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Int. Wirel. Commun. Mob. Comput. Conf., IWCMC&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 15th IEEE International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing Conference, IWCMC 2019, June 24, 2019 - June 28, 2019</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85073884955&amp;doi=10.1109%2fIWCMC.2019.8766641&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=ea33daa21eca5108e19699ef38d0bfd5</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/IWCMC.2019.8766641</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Tangier, Morocco</custom1><custom3>15th IEEE International Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing Conference, IWCMC 2019, June 24, 2019 - June 28, 2019</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>S. -C. Choi</author><author>I. -Y. Ahn</author><author>J. -H. Park</author><author>J. Kim</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Towards Real-Time Data Delivery in oneM2M Platform for UAV Management System</title><secondary-title>18th Annual International Conference on Electronics, Information, and Communication (ICEIC)</secondary-title><tertiary-title>ICEIC 2019 - International Conference on Electronics, Information, and Communication</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>18th International Conference on Electronics, Information, and Communication, ICEIC 2019, January 22, 2019 - January 25, 2019</full-title></periodical><pages>516-518</pages><keywords><keyword>Information management</keyword><keyword>Drones</keyword><keyword>Remote sensing</keyword><keyword>UAV</keyword><keyword>drone swarm</keyword><keyword>Command and control systems</keyword><keyword>UAV management system</keyword><keyword>oneM2M standard</keyword><keyword>real-time data delivery</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2019</year><pub-dates><date>22-25 Jan. 2019</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>978-89-950044-4-9</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.23919/ELINFOCOM.2019.8706417</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper presents oneM2M standard platform architecture design and its implementation which supports real-time data delivery for UAV management system. Recently, a UAV swarm service is getting a lot of attention since compared to the single UAV, a UAV swarm can reduce time of executing various mission activities such as remote sensing, surveillance, search and rescue. However, to support those UAV swarm service scenarios, UAV management system should be involved and moreover, the system requires a real-time data delivery feature due to the high cruise speed of the UAVs and the low-latency constraints of the command and control message. Considering oneM2M message flows, we have designed the procedure which enables real-time data delivery in oneM2M platform and experimental results show that our system improves end-to-end delay performance in various network environments.  2019 Institute of Electronics and Information Engineers (IEIE).</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 18th International Conference on Electronics, Information, and Communication, ICEIC 2019, January 22, 2019 - January 25, 2019&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 International Conference on Electronics, Information, and Communication (ICEIC)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2019 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ELECTRONICS, INFORMATION, AND COMMUNICATION (ICEIC)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 18th International Conference on Electronics, Information, and Communication, ICEIC 2019, January 22, 2019 - January 25, 2019</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.23919/ELINFOCOM.2019.8706417</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Auckland, New zealand</custom1><custom3>18th International Conference on Electronics, Information, and Communication, ICEIC 2019, January 22, 2019 - January 25, 2019</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>A. Zolich</author><author>A. Sœgrov</author><author>E. Vågsholm</author><author>V. Hovstein</author><author>T. A. Johansen</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Coordinated maritime missions of unmanned vehicles — Network architecture and performance analysis</title><secondary-title>2017 IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2017 IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-7</pages><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>21-25 May 2017</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1938-1883</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICC.2017.7996481</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Multi-vehicle operations using various types of unmanned vehicles (UVs) can increase efficiency of marine data acquisition, reduce the crew risk and lower mission costs. These types of missions are very complex and often involve systems that are not interoperable. From an operational perspective however, some level of integration is necessary. Typically, a common network system architecture and Situation Awareness (SA) platform are required. The architecture allows operators to transfer data between vehicles and their operators, while the SA platform allows to monitor mission progress and react to changes. This paper presents a network system architecture used during an experiment realized in Spring 2016 in Norway. 8 departments from 5 institutions worked together to combine operation of 4 UVs (aerial, surface, underwater), a support vessel and on-shore team. The description is followed by a backbone network performance analysis. Several cases are presented, with focus on a transmission between manned vessel and Unmanned Surface Vehicle (USV), including direct connection, and data-relay mechanism via Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV).</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC)</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49787/A. Zolich et al. - 2017 - Coordinated maritime missions of unmanned vehicles.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><custom3>2017 IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Z. Liu</author><author>X. Wang</author><author>L. Shen</author><author>S. Zhao</author><author>Y. Cong</author><author>J. Li</author><author>D. Yin</author><author>S. Jia</author><author>X. Xiang</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Mission-Oriented Miniature Fixed-Wing UAV Swarms: A Multilayered and Distributed Architecture</title><secondary-title>IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics: Systems</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics: Systems</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics: Systems</abbr-1></periodical><pages>1588-1602</pages><volume>52</volume><number>3</number><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Computer architecture</keyword><keyword>Decision making</keyword><keyword>Planning</keyword><keyword>Resource management</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Fixed wings</keyword><keyword>Aircraft detection</keyword><keyword>Architecture</keyword><keyword>Aircraft control</keyword><keyword>Task analysis</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>Attitude control</keyword><keyword>Control allocation</keyword><keyword>unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs)</keyword><keyword>Proposed architectures</keyword><keyword>Communication layers</keyword><keyword>Decision making procedure</keyword><keyword>Distributed architecture</keyword><keyword>fixed wing</keyword><keyword>Human interactions</keyword><keyword>Integrated architecture</keyword><keyword>Level control</keyword><keyword>swarms</keyword><keyword>Target recognition</keyword><keyword>Scalability</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>March 2022</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2168-2216, 2168-2232</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/TSMC.2020.3033935</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In this article, a multilayered and distributed architecture for mission-oriented miniature fixed-wing UAV swarms is presented. Based on the concept of modularity, the proposed architecture divides the overall system into five layers: 1) low-level control layer; 2) high-level control layer; 3) coordination layer; 4) communication layer; and 5) human interaction layer, and many modules that can be viewed as black boxes with interfaces of inputs and outputs. In this way, not only the complexity of developing a large system can be reduced but also the versatility of supporting diversified missions can be ensured. Furthermore, the proposed architecture is fully distributed that each UAV performs the decision-making procedure autonomously so as to achieve better scalability. Moreover, different kinds of aerial platforms can be feasibly extended by using the control allocation matrices and the integrated hardware box. A prototype swarm system based on the proposed architecture is built and the proposed architecture is evaluated through field experiments with a scale of 21 fixed-wing UAVs. Particularly, to the best of our knowledge, this article is the first work which successfully demonstrates formation flight, target recognition, and tracking missions within an integrated architecture for fixed-wing UAV swarms through field experiments.  © 2013 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 21; Correspondence Address: X. Wang; College of Intelligence and Technology, National University of Defense Technology, Changsha, China; email: xkwang@nudt.edu.cn</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85096849383&amp;doi=10.1109%2fTSMC.2020.3033935&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=eae653c6da571182e9cd59c39fb5b975</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49798/Z. Liu et al. - 2022 - Mission-Oriented Miniature Fixed-Wing UAV Swarms .pdf</url></pdf-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TSMC.2020.3033935</url></text-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>B. Fei</author><author>W. Bao</author><author>X. Zhu</author><author>D. Liu</author><author>T. Men</author><author>Z. Xiao</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Autonomous Cooperative Search Model for Multi-UAV With Limited Communication Network</title><secondary-title>IEEE Internet of Things Journal</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Internet of Things Journal</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Internet of Things Journal</abbr-1></periodical><pages>19346-19361</pages><volume>9</volume><number>19</number><issue>19</issue><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>1 Oct.1, 2022</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2327-4662</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/JIOT.2022.3165278</electronic-resource-num><abstract>With the rapid development of artificial intelligence technology, the multi-UAV cooperative search has wide applications in the field of Internet of Things, such as resource exploration, emergency rescue, intelligent transportation, etc. However, the communication network in an unknown environment may be inaccessible, and the real-time information sharing among UAVs cannot be guaranteed, resulting in the failure of cooperative search. Aiming at this issue, this article is devoted to the design of the multi-UAV flight strategy to improve the cooperative search capability in an uncertain communication environment. Specifically, a new cooperative architecture oriented to a local communication network is devised to control the observation locations of multiple UAVs in the search process, and some local communication networks are established based on the distance among UAVs to meet the requirements of the search task. On this foundation, we develop a multi-UAV cooperative search model (MCSM) with communication cost and formation benefit as an optimization function to ensure the effectiveness of multi-UAV search. Moreover, in the process of model solving, an improved sparrow search algorithm (ISSA) is presented with some different search strategies to enhance the optimization capability. To verify the superiority of the proposed method, we designed several groups of simulation experiments to analyze the performance of MCSM. Experimental results illustrate that our method can not only maintain high cooperative search accuracy but also has high stability and convergence speed.</abstract><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;More about an algorithm than an architecture&#xD;&#xD;</research-notes></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>R. L. Lidowski</author><author>B. E. Mullins</author><author>R. O. Baldwin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A novel communications protocol using geographic routing for swarming UAVs performing a Search Mission</title><secondary-title>7th Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, PerCom 2009</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2009 IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications</full-title></periodical><pages>1-7</pages><keywords><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>Communications protocols</keyword><keyword>Autonomous swarms</keyword><keyword>Routing protocols</keyword><keyword>Remotely operated vehicles</keyword><keyword>Communication</keyword><keyword>Communications</keyword><keyword>Computer science</keyword><keyword>Dimensional grids</keyword><keyword>Direction change</keyword><keyword>Geographic routing</keyword><keyword>OPNET Modeler</keyword><keyword>Search efficiency</keyword><keyword>Search protocols</keyword><keyword>Stateless routing</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2009</year><pub-dates><date>9-13 March 2009</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>978-142443304-9 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/PERCOM.2009.4912764</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper develops a novel communications protocol for autonomous swarms of unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV5) searching a 2-dimensional grid. The search protocol, the UAV Search Mission Protocol (USMP), combines inter-UAV communication with geographic routing to improve search efficiency in terms of total searches, distance traveled by UAVs, and the minimization of UAV direction changes. By determining where search state updates impact search decisions, messages are geographically routed to improve search efficiency. USMP and the geographic greedy perimeter stateless routing (GPSR) protocol are studied via simulation using OPNET Modeler 12.0. Geographic routing degrades performance by at least 20% in total searches and distance traveled, but improves direction changes by 6.7%. Overall, USMP improves performance by as much as 188% compared to scenarios without inter-UAV communication. © 2009 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 30; Conference name: 7th Annual IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications, PerCom 2009; Conference date: 9 March 2009 through 13 March 2009; Conference code: 77122&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2009 IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Annu. IEEE Int. Conf. Pervasive Comput. Commun., PerCom&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2009 IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-70349329598&amp;doi=10.1109%2fPERCOM.2009.4912764&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=76a7960a059d0099463852c51cee7ee3</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49794/R. L. Lidowski et al. - 2009 - A novel communications protocol using geographic r.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><custom3>2009 IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>B. J. Olivieri de Souza</author><author>M. Endler</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Coordinating movement within swarms of UAVs through mobile networks</title><secondary-title>2015 IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communication Workshops (PerCom Workshops)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2015 IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communication Workshops (PerCom Workshops)</full-title></periodical><pages>154-159</pages><dates><year>2015</year><pub-dates><date>23-27 March 2015</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/PERCOMW.2015.7134011</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAV) have several uses in civilians and military applications, such as search and rescue missions, cartography and terrain exploration, industrial plant control, surveillance, public security, firefight, and others. Swarms of UAVs may further increase the effectiveness of these tasks, since they enable larger coverage, more accurate or redundant sensed data, fault tolerance, etc. Swarms of aerial robots require real-time coordination, which is just a specific case of M2M collaboration. But one of the biggest challenges of UAV swarming is that this real-time coordination has to happen in a wide-area setting where it is expensive, or even impossible, to set up a dedicated wireless infrastructure for this purpose. Instead, one has to resort to conventional 3G/4G wireless networks, where communication latencies are in the range of 50-150 ms. In this paper we tackle the problem of UAV swarm formation and maintenance in areas covered by such mobile network, and propose a bandwidth-efficient multi-robot coordination algorithm for these settings. The coordination algorithm was implemented on the top of our mobile middleware SDDL, uses its group-cast communication capability, and was tested with simulated UAVs.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2015 IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communication Workshops (PerCom Workshops)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2015 IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communication Workshops (PerCom Workshops)</research-notes><custom3>2015 IEEE International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communication Workshops (PerCom Workshops)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>F. Zhang</author><author>H. Lu</author><author>J. Wu</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A reconfigurable mission management system based on modular framework for micro UAVs</title><secondary-title>Proceedings of 2014 IEEE Chinese Guidance, Navigation and Control Conference</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of 2014 IEEE Chinese Guidance, Navigation and Control Conference</full-title></periodical><pages>2510-2514</pages><dates><year>2014</year><pub-dates><date>8-10 Aug. 2014</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/CGNCC.2014.7007562</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In this paper, we present the architecture of the reconfigurable mission management system for micro UAVs. The system consists of two subsystems: the onboard system and the ground control station. They all base on the modular framework. All modules are independent to each other. The entire system can reconfigure depending on the requirements of different missions. The method of multi-thread is introduced to realize them. Each thread performs one specific task, such as communication, path planning, control, mission management, health monitor and data logging. Meanwhile, the ground control station provides a friendly interface displaying the real-time status of UAVs. Especially for the onboard system, we mainly detail the mission management computer, which includes a mission management module. Petri net is used to model the vehicle behaviors during the mission.</abstract><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;Not accessible&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of 2014 IEEE Chinese Guidance, Navigation and Control Conference&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of 2014 IEEE Chinese Guidance, Navigation and Control Conference</research-notes><custom3>Proceedings of 2014 IEEE Chinese Guidance, Navigation and Control Conference</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>A. Kopeikin</author><author>S. S. Ponda</author><author>L. B. Johnson</author><author>J. P. How</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Multi-UAV network control through dynamic task allocation: Ensuring data-rate and bit-error-rate support</title><secondary-title>2012 IEEE Globecom Workshops</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2012 IEEE Globecom Workshops</full-title></periodical><pages>1579-1584</pages><dates><year>2012</year><pub-dates><date>3-7 Dec. 2012</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2166-0077</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/GLOCOMW.2012.6477821</electronic-resource-num><abstract>A multi-UAV system relies on communications to operate. Failure to communicate remotely sensed mission data to the base may render the system ineffective, and the inability to exchange command and control messages can lead to system failures. This paper describes a unique method to control communications through distributed task allocation to engage under-utilized UAVs to serve as communication relays and to ensure that the network supports mission tasks. The distributed algorithm uses task assignment information, including task location and proposed execution time, to predict the network topology and plan support using relays. By explicitly coupling task assignment and relay creation processes the team is able to optimize the use of agents to address the needs of dynamic complex missions. The framework is designed to consider realistic network communication dynamics including path loss, stochastic fading, and information routing. The planning strategy is shown to ensure that agents support both datarate and interconnectivity bit-error-rate requirements during task execution. System performance is characterized through experiments both in simulation and in outdoor flight testing with a team of three UAVs.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2012 IEEE Globecom Workshops&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2012 IEEE Globecom Workshops</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49785/A. Kopeikin et al. - 2012 - Multi-UAV network control through dynamic task all.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><custom3>2012 IEEE Globecom Workshops</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>N. Toorchi</author><author>F. Hu</author><author>E. S. Bentley</author><author>S. Kumar</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Skeleton-Based Swarm Routing (SSR): Intelligent Smooth Routing for Dynamic UAV Networks</title><secondary-title>IEEE Access</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Access</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Access</abbr-1></periodical><pages>1286-1303</pages><volume>9</volume><keywords><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Swarm intelligence</keyword><keyword>Learning algorithms</keyword><keyword>Vehicle transmissions</keyword><keyword>reinforcement learning</keyword><keyword>Resource Constraint</keyword><keyword>Mobile telecommunication systems</keyword><keyword>Routing protocols</keyword><keyword>Ad hoc on demand distance vector</keyword><keyword>Adaptive routing protocols</keyword><keyword>Computational resources</keyword><keyword>Critical challenges</keyword><keyword>Geometric routing</keyword><keyword>Musculoskeletal system</keyword><keyword>Network routing</keyword><keyword>Online learning algorithms</keyword><keyword>Optimized Link State Routing</keyword><keyword>quality of service</keyword><keyword>Single-path routing</keyword><keyword>stochastic dynamic programming</keyword><keyword>swarm networks</keyword><keyword>UAV communication</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>2021</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>21693536 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3043672</electronic-resource-num><abstract>A swarm of unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) requires the transmission of mission-related data across the network. The resource constraints and dynamic nature of the swarm bring critical challenges to the design of UAV routing protocols. Most of the conventional ad hoc routing schemes are not intelligent and cannot adapt to the dynamic nature of UAV swarming networks. On the other hand, some artificial intelligence (AI)-based routing schemes may consume significant computational resources in the UAVs. In this article, a low-cost, adaptive routing protocol, namely skeleton-based swarm routing (SSR), is proposed, which exploits an intelligent online learning algorithm and the topology features of the mission-driven UAV swarm to distribute the traffic over optimal routes. Here, the skeleton represents the most stable parts of the swarm formation. SSR architecture consists of three modules: 1) A geometric addressing module, which assigns geometric coordinates to each node based on the swarm skeleton structure; 2) A leaf-like routing pipe which allows the selection of multiple candidate routes around the shortest path; 3) An intelligent low-complexity learning model which determines how to distribute the packets inside the routing pipe to achieve load-balanced, high-throughput transmissions. The proposed skeleton-based scheme can also facilitate the UAV formation construction and morphing. The simulation results show that the proposed SSR protocol can noticeably improve the network performance (up to 100% throughput improvement) compared to the single path routing schemes, such as the ad-hoc on-demand distance vector (AODV) and link-quality and traffic-load aware optimized link state routing (LTA-OLSR) protocols. © 2013 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 12; Correspondence Address: F. Hu; Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, The University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa, United States; email: fei@eng.ua.edu</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85097953660&amp;doi=10.1109%2fACCESS.2020.3043672&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=696ac7e2ffb23be228d6bf8e27ec7bbf</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49778/N. Toorchi et al. - 2021 - Skeleton-Based Swarm Routing (SSR) Intelligent Sm.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>X. Hou</author><author>Z. Ren</author><author>J. Wang</author><author>S. Zheng</author><author>W. Cheng</author><author>H. Zhang</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Distributed Fog Computing for Latency and Reliability Guaranteed Swarm of Drones</title><secondary-title>IEEE Access</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Access</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Access</abbr-1></periodical><pages>7117-7130</pages><volume>8</volume><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>2020</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2169-3536</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2964073</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Swarm of drones, as an intensely significant category of swarm robots, is widely used in various fields, e.g., search and rescue, detection missions, military, etc. Because of the limitation of computing resource of drones, dealing with computation-intensive tasks locally is difficult. Hence, the cloud-based computation offloading is widely adopted, nevertheless, for some latency-sensitive tasks, e.g., object recognition, path planning, etc., the cloud-based manner is inappropriate due to the excessive delay. Even in some harsh environments, e.g., disaster area, battlefield, etc., there is no wireless infrastructure existed to combine the drones and cloud center. Thus, to solve the problem encountered by cloud-based computation offloading, in this paper, Fog Computing aided Swarm of Drones (FCSD) architecture is proposed. Considering the uncertainty factors in harsh environments which may threaten the success of FCSD processing tasks, not only the latency model, but also the reliability model of FCSD is constructed to guarantee the high reliability of task completion. Moreover, in view of the limited battery life of the drone, we formulated the problem as the task allocation problem which minimized the energy consumption of FCSD under the constraints of latency and reliability. Furthermore, to speed up the process of the optimization problem solving to improve the practicality, relying on the recent advances in distributed convex optimization, we develop a fast Proximal Jacobi Alternating Direction Method of Multipliers (ADMM) based distributed algorithm. Finally, simulation results validate the effectiveness of our proposed scheme.</abstract><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49797/X. Hou et al. - 2020 - Distributed Fog Computing for Latency and Reliabil.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>T. Zahariadis</author><author>A. Voulkidis</author><author>P. Karkazis</author><author>P. Trakadas</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Preventive maintenance of critical infrastructures using 5G networks &amp; drones</title><secondary-title>2017 14th IEEE International Conference on Advanced Video and Signal Based Surveillance (AVSS)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2017 14th IEEE International Conference on Advanced Video and Signal Based Surveillance (AVSS)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-4</pages><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>29 Aug.-1 Sept. 2017</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/AVSS.2017.8078465</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The massive deployment of IoT devices, broadband and mission critical services are paving the way for 5G communication networks, which will enable massive capacity, zero delay, elasticity and optimal deployment, enhanced security, privacy by design and connectivity to billions of devices with less predictable traffic patterns. This paper targets a very important and demanding application the Preventive Maintenance as a Service in Critical Infrastructures and more precisely in the energy (electricity and gas) transmission and distribution network that combines the 5G technology with secure IoT and drones flight control. In more details, it addresses the 5G advances at the edge network and proposes a number of VNFs to support surveillance using swarms of drones.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 14th IEEE International Conference on Advanced Video and Signal Based Surveillance (AVSS)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 14th IEEE International Conference on Advanced Video and Signal Based Surveillance (AVSS)</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49795/T. Zahariadis et al. - 2017 - Preventive maintenance of critical infrastructures.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><custom3>2017 14th IEEE International Conference on Advanced Video and Signal Based Surveillance (AVSS)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>H. Yu</author><author>H. Huang</author><author>X. Jia</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Clustering-based Communication Backbone for Large Scale UAV Networks</title><secondary-title>2018 14th International Conference on Mobile Ad-Hoc and Sensor Networks (MSN)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2018 14th International Conference on Mobile Ad-Hoc and Sensor Networks (MSN)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-6</pages><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>6-8 Dec. 2018</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/MSN.2018.00007</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Single micro UAV is limited by its endurance and suffers the problem of single point failure. An autonomous fleet of cooperating UAVs can render more efficient and robust ability to complete the missions. In order to make multiple UAVs fly cooperatively in an autonomous way without control from the ground station, one of the key techniques is communication network technology. In this paper, we propose a distributed algorithm to construct a clustered-backbone to support both broadcast and unicast communications for UAV networks. In our algorithm, UAVs clustering and virtual backbone construction only need the information exchange among adjacent UAVs. We also propose a strategy to dynamically maintain this clustered-backbone network. We test our scheme using four commercial UAVs enhanced by an ARM-based embedded computer to demonstrate the distributed control and dynamic maintenance features of the algorithm.</abstract><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;More algorithm, less architecture&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2018 14th International Conference on Mobile Ad-Hoc and Sensor Networks (MSN)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2018 14th International Conference on Mobile Ad-Hoc and Sensor Networks (MSN)</research-notes><custom3>2018 14th International Conference on Mobile Ad-Hoc and Sensor Networks (MSN)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>N. Lin</author><author>L. Fu</author><author>L. Zhao</author><author>G. Min</author><author>A. Al-Dubai</author><author>H. Gacanin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Novel Multimodal Collaborative Drone-Assisted VANET Networking Model</title><secondary-title>IEEE Transactions on Wireless Communications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Transactions on Wireless Communications</full-title><abbr-1>IEEE Transactions on Wireless Communications</abbr-1></periodical><pages>4919-4933</pages><volume>19</volume><number>7</number><issue>7</issue><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>July 2020</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1558-2248</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/TWC.2020.2988363</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Drones can be used for many assistance roles in complex communication scenarios and play as the aerial relays to support terrestrial communications. Although a great deal of emphasis has been placed on the drone-assisted networks, existing work focuses on routing protocols without fully exploiting the drones superiority and flexibility. To fill this gap, this paper proposes a collaborative communication scheme for multiple drones to assist the urban vehicular ad-hoc networks (VANETs). In this scheme, drones are distributed regarding the predicted terrestrial traffic condition in order to efficiently alleviate the inevitable problems of conventional VANETs, such as building obstacle, isolated vehicles, and uneven traffic loading. To effectively coordinate multiple drones, this issue is modeled as a multimodal optimization problem to improve the global performance on a certain space. To this end, a succinct swarm-based optimization algorithm, namely Multimodal Nomad Algorithm (MNA) is presented. This algorithm is inspired by the migratory behavior of the nomadic tribes on Mongolia grassland. Based on the floating car data of Chengdu China, extensive experiments are conducted to examine the performance of the MNA-optimized drone-assisted VANET. The results demonstrate that our scheme outperforms its counterparts in terms of hop number, packet delivery ratio, and throughput.</abstract><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49793/N. Lin et al. - 2020 - A Novel Multimodal Collaborative Drone-Assisted VA.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>K. Daniel</author><author>B. Dusza</author><author>A. Lewandowski</author><author>C. Wietfeld</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>AirShield: A system-of-systems MUAV remote sensing architecture for disaster response</title><secondary-title>2009 IEEE International Systems Conference Proceedings</secondary-title><tertiary-title>2009 IEEE International Systems Conference Proceedings</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2009 IEEE International Systems Conference, March 23, 2009 - March 26, 2009</full-title></periodical><pages>196-200</pages><keywords><keyword>Communication systems</keyword><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Remote sensing</keyword><keyword>Wireless networks</keyword><keyword>Sensor networks</keyword><keyword>Cognitive systems</keyword><keyword>System of systems</keyword><keyword>Wireless sensor networks</keyword><keyword>Remotely operated vehicles</keyword><keyword>Disaster response</keyword><keyword>Mission control centers</keyword><keyword>Contaminated areas</keyword><keyword>Gaseous contaminants</keyword><keyword>Liquids</keyword><keyword>Measurement device</keyword><keyword>Mesh network</keyword><keyword>Mobile sensor systems</keyword><keyword>Nuclear weapons</keyword><keyword>System-of-Systems</keyword><keyword>Toxic gas</keyword><keyword>Uncontrolled emissions</keyword><keyword>Wireless connection</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2009</year><pub-dates><date>23-26 March 2009</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher><isbn>978-142443463-3 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/SYSTEMS.2009.4815797</electronic-resource-num><abstract>For clarification, containment and combat of large danger areas, fast and flexible survey of potentially contaminated areas is an emerging challenge. In this paper we present a project that focuses on incidents, that are caused by uncontrolled emissions of liquid or gaseous contaminants (e.g. explosive or toxic gases or liquids, biological, chemical or nuclear weapons). Instead of sending specially equipped forces with expensive transport and measurement devices into the contaminated area, our proposed system makes use of an autonomous, wireless connected swarm of Micro Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (MUAV), often simply known as drones, that are featured with lightweight mobile sensor systems. In this paper we will be particularly focusing on the complex communication system, which on the one hand has to organize the on-board-communication between the control systems of the MUAV and the sensors and on the other hand has to establish wireless connections to the mission control center on the ground as well as to neighboring MUAVs in the air via a mesh network. © 2009 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 107; Correspondence Address: K. Daniel; Communication Networks Institute (CNI), Dortmund University of Technology, 44227 Dortmund, Germany; email: Kai.Daniel@tu-dortmund.de; Conference name: 2009 IEEE International Systems Conference; Conference date: 23 March 2009 through 26 March 2009; Conference code: 76413&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2009 3rd Annual IEEE Systems Conference&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2009 IEEE International Systems Conference, March 23, 2009 - March 26, 2009&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2009 IEEE INTERNATIONAL SYSTEMS CONFERENCE, PROCEEDINGS&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: IEEE Int. Syst. Conf. Proc.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2009 IEEE International Systems Conference, March 23, 2009 - March 26, 2009</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-67650141552&amp;doi=10.1109%2fSYSTEMS.2009.4815797&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=b3157e0c877b11e7ef7c7ad50d7f0f96</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/SYSTEMS.2009.4815797</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Vancouver, BC, Canada</custom1><custom3>2009 IEEE International Systems Conference, March 23, 2009 - March 26, 2009</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>A. T. Erman</author><author>P. Havinga</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Data dissemination of emergency messages in mobile multi-sink wireless sensor networks</title><secondary-title>2010 The 9th IFIP Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2010 The 9th IFIP Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-8</pages><dates><year>2010</year><pub-dates><date>23-25 June 2010</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/MEDHOCNET.2010.5546870</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In wireless sensor networks (WSNs), data dissemination is generally performed from sensor nodes to a static sink. If the data under consideration is an emergency message such as a fire alarm, it must be transmitted as fast and reliably as possible towards the sink of WSN. In such mission critical applications, it may not be enough to have one static sink but there will be multiple and mobile sinks. Sinks can be associated to first responders such as firefighters, but also to unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs). The existing approaches have a high communication cost and a high delivery latency, which makes them less suitable for emergency situations. As an alternative to existing protocols, we present Honeycomb Architecture and Hexagonal Tiling-Based Data Dissemination (HexDD) protocol for emergency message transmission in mobile multi-sink WSNs. Simulation results show that HexDD has a high data delivery ratio and a very low data delivery latency, which are major requirements for disaster management scenarios.</abstract><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2010 The 9th IFIP Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2010 The 9th IFIP Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)&#xD;&#xD;UAVs are only tackled on the side&#xD;&#xD;</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49786/A. T. Erman and P. Havinga - 2010 - Data dissemination of emergency messages in mobile.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><custom3>2010 The 9th IFIP Annual Mediterranean Ad Hoc Networking Workshop (Med-Hoc-Net)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>J. A. Preiss</author><author>W. Honig</author><author>G. S. Sukhatme</author><author>N. Ayanian</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Crazyswarm: A large nano-quadcopter swarm</title><secondary-title>Proceedings - IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation</secondary-title><tertiary-title>Proceedings - IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2017 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation, ICRA 2017, May 29, 2017 - June 3, 2017</full-title></periodical><pages>3299-3304</pages><volume>0</volume><keywords><keyword>Vehicle to vehicle communications</keyword><keyword>Trajectory Planning</keyword><keyword>Robotics</keyword><keyword>System architectures</keyword><keyword>Vehicles</keyword><keyword>Communication infrastructure</keyword><keyword>Position errors</keyword><keyword>Tracking performance</keyword><keyword>Motion capture</keyword><keyword>Number of vehicles</keyword><keyword>State estimation</keyword><keyword>Accurate tracking</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>29 May-3 June 2017</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher><isbn>10504729 (ISSN); 978-150904633-1 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICRA.2017.7989376</electronic-resource-num><abstract>We define a system architecture for a large swarm of miniature quadcopters flying in dense formation indoors. The large number of small vehicles motivates novel design choices for state estimation and communication. For state estimation, we develop a method to reliably track many small rigid bodies with identical motion-capture marker arrangements. Our communication infrastructure uses compressed one-way data flow and supports a large number of vehicles per radio. We achieve reliable flight with accurate tracking (&lt; 2 cm mean position error) by implementing the majority of computation onboard, including sensor fusion, control, and some trajectory planning. We provide various examples and empirically determine latency and tracking performance for swarms with up to 49 vehicles. © 2017 IEEE.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 219; Conference name: 2017 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation, ICRA 2017; Conference date: 29 May 2017 through 3 June 2017; Conference code: 129533; CODEN: PIIAE&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation, ICRA 2017, May 29, 2017 - June 3, 2017&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proc IEEE Int Conf Rob Autom&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 2017 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation, ICRA 2017, May 29, 2017 - June 3, 2017</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85027964932&amp;doi=10.1109%2fICRA.2017.7989376&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=e193894989f47bf83524b931eba9eb66</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICRA.2017.7989376</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Singapore, Singapore</custom1><custom3>2017 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation, ICRA 2017, May 29, 2017 - June 3, 2017</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Qin, B.</author><author>Zhang, D.</author><author>Tang, S.</author><author>Wang, M.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Distributed Grouping Cooperative Dynamic Task Assignment Method of UAV Swarm</title><secondary-title>Applied Sciences (Switzerland)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Applied Sciences (Switzerland)</full-title><abbr-1>Appl. Sci.-Basel</abbr-1></periodical><pages>2865</pages><volume>12</volume><number>6</number><issue>6</issue><keywords><keyword>task assignment</keyword><keyword>Task assignment</keyword><keyword>Distributed swarm</keyword><keyword>Dynamic task planning</keyword><keyword>Event-trigger</keyword><keyword>Swarm control</keyword><keyword>distributed swarm</keyword><keyword>dynamic task planning</keyword><keyword>event-trigger</keyword><keyword>swarm control</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>MAR 2022</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>20763417 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.3390/app12062865</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Aiming at the problem of UAV swarms with distributed subsets performing cooperative reconnaissance-and-attack tasks on multi-targets in complex and uncertain combat scenarios, a distributed grouping cooperative dynamic task assignment method is proposed based on extended contract network protocol. The dynamic task assignment model for the UAV swarm with the topology of distributed subsets is established considering multiple constraints such as task cooperation, performing sequence, dynamic environment, communication topology, payload model, and UAV capability. According to the characteristics of multi-participants and multi-tasks in the process of UAV swarm executing tasks, the determination mechanism on cooperators and the selection mechanism of sequential tasks are proposed, and then the contract network protocol is extended. On the basis of the above, an event-triggered task assignment strategy for dynamic tasks is designed. The simulated results show that the proposed method can achieve the cooperative dynamic assignment of the UAV swarm to perform reconnaissance-and-attack tasks to multi-targets in complex and uncertain combat scenarios, improve the adaptiveness of the swarm under the sudden circumstance, and realize the optimization for task execution efficiency of the UAV swarm. © 2022 by the authors. Licensee MDPI, Basel, Switzerland.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 16; Correspondence Address: D. Zhang; School of Astronautics, Northwestern Polytechnical University, Xi’an, 710072, China; email: zhangdong@nwpu.edu.cn</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85126270583&amp;doi=10.3390%2fapp12062865&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=86a1f080cf644be6b6f4e27b491ba2fa</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49780/Qin et al. - 2022 - Distributed Grouping Cooperative Dynamic Task Assi.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Scherer, J.</author><author>Yahyanejad, S.</author><author>Hayat, S.</author><author>Yanmaz, E.</author><author>Vukadinovic, V.</author><author>Andre, T.</author><author>Bettstetter, C.</author><author>Rinner, B.</author><author>Khan, A.</author><author>Hellwagner, H.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An autonomous multi-UAV system for search and rescue</title><secondary-title>DroNet 2015 - Proceedings of the 2015 Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications for Civilian Use</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications for Civilian Use</full-title></periodical><pages>33-38</pages><keywords><keyword>Computer architecture</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Network architecture</keyword><keyword>Disaster prevention</keyword><keyword>Distributed parameter control systems</keyword><keyword>Autonomous unmanned aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>UAV</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles</keyword><keyword>Search and rescue</keyword><keyword>Wireless communications</keyword><keyword>System architectures</keyword><keyword>Micro air vehicle (MAV)</keyword><keyword>Vehicles</keyword><keyword>Closed loop control systems</keyword><keyword>Robot operating systems (ROS)</keyword><keyword>Proof of concept</keyword><keyword>System architecture</keyword><keyword>Wireless telecommunication systems</keyword><keyword>Modular architectures</keyword><keyword>Video streaming</keyword><keyword>Aerial communication</keyword><keyword>Real-time video streams</keyword><keyword>aerial communication, search and rescue, system architecture, uav, unmanned aerial vehicles, video streaming</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year><pub-dates><date>2015</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery, Inc</publisher><isbn>978-145033501-0 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2750675.2750683</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper proposes and evaluates a modular architecture of an autonomous unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) system for search and rescue missions. Multiple multicopters are coordinated using a distributed control system. The system is implemented in the Robot Operating System (ROS) and is capable of providing a real-time video stream from a UAV to one or more base stations using a wireless communications infrastructure. The system supports a heterogeneous set of UAVs and camera sensors. If necessary, an operator can interfere and reduce the autonomy. The system has been tested in an outdoor mission serving as a proof of concept. Some insights from these tests are described in the paper. © Copyright 2015 ACM.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 206; Conference name: 1st ACM Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications for Civilian Use, DroNet 2015; Conference code: 117690&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: DroNet - Proc. Workshop Micro Aer. Veh. Netw., Syst., Appl. Civ. Use&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the First Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications for Civilian Use&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the First Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications for Civilian Use</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-84959503077&amp;doi=10.1145%2f2750675.2750683&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=76030a538eaa43ee55acd0e9a800770d</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>Florence, Italy</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the First Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications for Civilian Use</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Xu, C.</author><author>Zhang, K.</author><author>Jiang, Y.</author><author>Niu, S.</author><author>Yang, T.</author><author>Song, H.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Communication aware uav swarm surveillance based on hierarchical architecture</title><secondary-title>Drones</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Drones</full-title><abbr-1>Drones-Basel</abbr-1></periodical><pages>33</pages><volume>5</volume><number>2</number><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>Communication aware UAV formation</keyword><keyword>Dynamical object tracking</keyword><keyword>Hierarchical architecture of UAV teaming</keyword><keyword>Intercommunication quality</keyword><keyword>Persistent surveillance</keyword><keyword>persistent surveillance</keyword><keyword>OPTIMIZATION</keyword><keyword>ALLOCATION</keyword><keyword>communication aware UAV formation</keyword><keyword>dynamical object tracking</keyword><keyword>hierarchical architecture of UAV teaming</keyword><keyword>intercommunication quality</keyword><keyword>SIMULATION</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>JUN 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2504446X (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.3390/drones5020033</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Multi-agent unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) teaming becomes an essential part in science mission, modern warfare surveillance, and disaster rescuing. This paper proposes a decentralized UAV swarm persistent monitoring strategy in realizing continuous sensing coverage and network service. A two-layer (high altitude and low altitude) UAV teaming hierarchical structure is adopted in realizing the accurate object tracking in the area of interest (AOI). By introducing the UAV communication channel model in its path planning, both centralized and decentralized control schemes would be evaluated in the waypoint tracking simulation. The UAV swarm network service and object tracking are measured by metrics of communication link quality and waypoints tracking accuracy. UAV swarm network connectivity are evaluated over different aspects, such as stability and volatility. The comparison of proposed algorithms is presented with simulations. The result shows that the decentralized scheme outperforms the centralized scheme in the mission of persistent surveillance, especially on maintaining the stability of inner UAV swarm network while tracking moving objects. © 2021 by the authors. Licensee MDPI, Basel, Switzerland.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 23; Correspondence Address: H. Song; Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University, Daytona Beach, 32114, United States; email: songh4@erau.edu</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-85106611660&amp;doi=10.3390%2fdrones5020033&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=d496b7bc7f4c5b70b26a8d7e106aeebe</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49782/Xu et al. - 2021 - Communication aware uav swarm surveillance based o.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mehra, R. K.</author><author>Bošković, J. D.</author><author>Knoebel, N.</author><author>Moshtagh, N.</author><author>Amin, J.</author><author>Larson, G. L.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Collaborative Mission Planning &amp; Autonomous Control Technologies (COMPACT) for complex UAV missions</title><secondary-title>AUVSI Unmanned Systems North America Conference 2009</secondary-title><tertiary-title>AUVSI Unmanned Systems North America Conference 2009</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>AUVSI Unmanned Systems North America Conference 2009, August 10, 2009 - August 13, 2009</full-title></periodical><pages>716-734</pages><volume>2</volume><keywords><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Military operations</keyword><keyword>Navigation</keyword><keyword>Mission planning</keyword><keyword>Hierarchical architectures</keyword><keyword>Motion planning</keyword><keyword>Swarm behavior</keyword><keyword>Moving targets</keyword><keyword>Autonomous control</keyword><keyword>Evolutionary algorithms</keyword><keyword>Memory architecture</keyword><keyword>MATLAB</keyword><keyword>Complex mission</keyword><keyword>Autonomous agents</keyword><keyword>Task executions</keyword><keyword>Communication delays</keyword><keyword>UAV missions</keyword><keyword>Remotely operated vehicles</keyword><keyword>Reconnaissance aircraft</keyword><keyword>Coordination reactions</keyword><keyword>Uncertain dynamic environment</keyword><keyword>Real-time missions</keyword><keyword>Computer simulation</keyword><keyword>Re-planning</keyword><keyword>Intelligence , surveillance , and reconnaissances</keyword><keyword>Close air support</keyword><keyword>Compact system</keyword><keyword>Dynamic agents</keyword><keyword>Dynamic changes</keyword><keyword>Hybrid automatons</keyword><keyword>Matlab simulations</keyword><keyword>Powders</keyword><keyword>Reactive motions</keyword><keyword>Simple model</keyword><keyword>Targets</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2009</year><pub-dates><date>2009</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Unmanned Vehicle Systems International</publisher><isbn>978-161567580-7 (ISBN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.2514/6.2009-5653</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In this paper an autonomous hierarchical architecture for controlling swarms of unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV) is investigated. Its purpose is to carry out complex missions involving Intelligence, Surveillance, and Reconnaissance (ISR), Suppression of Enemy Aerial Defenses (SEAD), Destruction of Enemy Aerial Defenses (DEAD), Close Air Support (CAS), and other functions in an environment characterized by large uncertainty and vehicle loss or failures. Our approach is referred to as the Collaborative Mission Planning &amp; Autonomous Control Technology (CoMPACT) encompassing tasks and objectives from the mission planning stage to the UAV task execution level. The main advantage of the CoMPACT system is that it effectively combines mission planning using evolutionary algorithms, hybrid automata-based task execution, and biologically-inspired emergent swarm behaviors. Judicious combination and coordination of these capabilities results in a system that is scalable to architectures involving a very large number of autonomous agents in which mission-relevant objectives are accomplished in highly uncertain dynamic environments through real-time mission re-planning, dynamic agent-to-task assignment, and reactive motion planning. Through simulation and experiment, the CoMPACT approach is shown to be robust to intermittent loss of communications and communication delays, and to dynamic changes in the environment such as moving targets, unknown targets and obstacles, pop-up threats, vehicular failures and loss of agents. The CoMPACT system has been extensively tested on a Matlab simulation of a realistic mission scenario involving ISR, SEAD and DEAD functions, and simple models of UAV dynamics operating in a dynamic threat and target-rich environment. The CoMPACT system has also been implemented and field tested for maritime applications in a companion AUVSI paper [42].</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 1; Correspondence Address: R. K. Mehra; Scientific Systems Company, Inc., United States; email: rkm@ssci.com; Conference name: AUVSI Unmanned Systems North America Conference 2009; Conference date: 10 August 2009 through 13 August 2009; Conference code: 79395&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: AUVSI Unmanned Syst. North Am. Conf.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: AUVSI Unmanned Systems North America Conference 2009, August 10, 2009 - August 13, 2009&#xD;&#xD;Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 32; Correspondence Address: J. D. Bošković; Scientific Systems Company, Inc., United States; email: jovan@ssci.com; Conference name: AIAA Guidance, Navigation, and Control Conference and Exhibit; Conference date: 10 August 2009 through 13 August 2009; Conference code: 81960&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: AIAA Guid., Navig., Control Conf. Exhib.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: AIAA Guidance, Navigation, and Control Conference and Exhibit&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: AIAA Guidance, Navigation, and Control Conference and Exhibit&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: AUVSI Unmanned Systems North America Conference 2009, August 10, 2009 - August 13, 2009</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Jovan-Boskovic/publication/268557497_Collaborative_Mission_Planning_Autonomous_Control_Technology_CoMPACT_system_employing_swarms_of_UAVs/links/5681929708ae1975838f8d92/Collaborative-Mission-Planning-Autonomous-Control-Technology-CoMPACT-system-employing-swarms-of-UAVs.pdf</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://49783/Mehra et al. - 2009 - Collaborative Mission Planning &amp; Autonomous Contro.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><custom1>Washington, DC, United states</custom1><custom3>AUVSI Unmanned Systems North America Conference 2009, August 10, 2009 - August 13, 2009</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bryson, M.</author><author>Sukkarieh, S.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Architectures for cooperative airborne simultaneous localisation and mapping</title><secondary-title>Journal of Intelligent and Robotic Systems: Theory and Applications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Intelligent and Robotic Systems: Theory and Applications</full-title><abbr-1>J Intell Rob Syst Theor Appl</abbr-1></periodical><pages>267-297</pages><volume>55</volume><number>4-5</number><issue>4-5</issue><keywords><keyword>Planning</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Global positioning system</keyword><keyword>Sensor networks</keyword><keyword>UAVs</keyword><keyword>Mapping</keyword><keyword>Information dissemination</keyword><keyword>Architectural design</keyword><keyword>Computational complexity</keyword><keyword>Sensors</keyword><keyword>Vehicles</keyword><keyword>SLAM</keyword><keyword>Remotely operated vehicles</keyword><keyword>Sensor data fusion</keyword><keyword>Cooperative control</keyword><keyword>Active SLAM</keyword><keyword>Information</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2009</year><pub-dates><date>2009</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>15730409 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/s10846-008-9303-9</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper develops active Simultaneous Localisation And Mapping (SLAM) trajectory control strategies for multiple cooperating Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) for tasks such as surveillance and picture compilation in Global Positioning System (GPS)-denied environments. Each UAV in the team uses inertial sensor and terrain sensor information to simultaneously localise the UAV while building a point feature map of the surrounding terrain, where map information is shared between vehicles over a data fusion network. Multi-vehicle active SLAM control architectures are proposed that actively plan the trajectories and motions of each of the vehicles in the team based on maximising information in the localisation and mapping estimates. We demonstrate and compare an ideal, centralised architecture, where a central planning node chooses optimal actions for each UAV, and a coordinated, decentralised architecture, where UAVs make their own control decisions based on common shared map information. The different architectures involve varying degrees of complexity and optimality through differing communications and computational requirements. Results are presented using a three-UAV team in a six-degree of freedom multi-UAV simulator. © 2009 Springer Science+Business Media B.V.</abstract><research-notes>Export Date: 22 November 2023; Cited By: 33; Correspondence Address: M. Bryson; ARC Centre of Excellence in Autonomous Systems, Australian Centre for Field Robotics, University of Sydney, NSW 2006, Australia; email: m.bryson@acfr.usyd.edu.au; CODEN: JIRSE</research-notes><language>English</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.uri?eid=2-s2.0-68149120542&amp;doi=10.1007%2fs10846-008-9303-9&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=2b3e854343b568355fd458420719732f</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Aljehani, Maher</author><author>Inoue, Masahiro</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Communication and autonomous control of multi-UAV system in disaster response tasks</title><tertiary-title>Smart Innovation, Systems and Technologies</tertiary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>11th KES International Conference on Agent and Multi-Agent Systems—Technologies and Applications, KES-AMSTA 2017, June 21, 2017 - June 23, 2017</full-title></periodical><pages>123-132</pages><volume>74</volume><keywords><keyword>Antennas</keyword><keyword>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Aircraft detection</keyword><keyword>Rock mechanics</keyword><keyword>Aircraft control</keyword><keyword>Internet of things</keyword><keyword>Transmission control protocol</keyword><keyword>Aerial photography</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>2018</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Springer Science and Business Media Deutschland GmbH</publisher><isbn>21903018</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/978-3-319-59394-4_12</electronic-resource-num><abstract>After disasters occurrence, advanced technologies always play significant contributions to various disaster response tasks. For instance, utilization of Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) for aerial imagery data helps to get a real-time monitoring system of the stricken areas. Recently, UAV is becoming a ubiquitous system and valuable technology in many civil applications, motivating researchers to endeavor to develop UAVs systems. Moreover, Internet of Things (IoT) has been employed to several study cases of disaster response. Using IoT to communicate, manage and control multiple UAVs after disaster occurrence is a real practical approach. However, this kind of integration wasnt clearly presented especially in the technical sides like communication and autonomous control. Consequently, this paper aims to reveal the scientific scenes of communications and controls between multiple UAVs and Ground Control Stations (GCSs). Due to an unexpected failure within a single UAV system, this study presents a multi-UAV system for scanning and tracking missions. Authors turned UAV to an IoT device by using embedded LTE dongle on the UAV control board. In the beginning of the paper, authors raised the issues of existing systems. Then, presented the design and process of the proposed system. Lastly, they demonstrated some results through experiments.  Springer International Publishing AG 2018.</abstract><research-notes>Compilation and indexing terms, Copyright 2023 Elsevier Inc.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 11th KES International Conference on Agent and Multi-Agent Systems—Technologies and Applications, KES-AMSTA 2017, June 21, 2017 - June 23, 2017&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: 11th KES International Conference on Agent and Multi-Agent Systems—Technologies and Applications, KES-AMSTA 2017, June 21, 2017 - June 23, 2017</research-notes><urls><text-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-59394-4_12</url></text-urls></urls><custom1>Vilamoura, [city] Algarve, Portugal</custom1><custom3>11th KES International Conference on Agent and Multi-Agent Systems—Technologies and Applications, KES-AMSTA 2017, June 21, 2017 - June 23, 2017</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wang, Lizhi</author><author>Zhao, Xuejiao</author><author>Zhang, Yuan</author><author>Wang, Xiaohong</author><author>Ma, Tielin</author><author>Gao, Xia</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Unmanned aerial vehicle swarm mission reliability modeling and evaluation method oriented to systematic and networked mission</title><secondary-title>CHINESE JOURNAL OF AERONAUTICS</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>CHINESE JOURNAL OF AERONAUTICS</full-title><abbr-1>Chin. J. Aeronaut.</abbr-1></periodical><pages>466-478</pages><volume>34</volume><number>2</number><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>Complex networks</keyword><keyword>Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAV)</keyword><keyword>Vulnerability</keyword><keyword>Connectivity</keyword><keyword>ARCHITECTURE</keyword><keyword>COMPLEX NETWORKS</keyword><keyword>Mission reliability</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>FEB 2021</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1000-9361, 2588-9230</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.cja.2020.02.026</electronic-resource-num><abstract>With the development of Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) system autonomy, network communication technology and group intelligence theory, mission execution in the form of a UAV swarm will be an important realization of future applications. Traditional single-UAV mission reliability modeling methods have been unable to meet the requirements of UAV swarm mission reliability modeling. Therefore, the UAV swarm mission reliability modeling and evaluation method is proposed. First, aimed at the interdependence among the multiple layers, a multi-layer network model of a UAV swarm is established. At the same time, based on the system having the following characteristics?using a mission chain to complete the mission and applying the connectivity of the mission network?the mission network model of a UAV swarm is established. Second, vulnerability and connectivity are selected as two indicators to reflect the reliability of the mission, and aimed at random attack and deliberate attack, vulnerability and connectivity evaluation methods are proposed. Finally, the validity and accuracy of the constructed model are verified through simulations,and the model and selected indicators can meet the reliability requirements of the UAV swarm mis-sion. In this way, this study provides quantitative reference for UAV-swarm-related decision -making work and supports the development of UAV-swarm-related work. (c) 2020 Chinese Society of Aeronautics and Astronautics. Production and hosting by Elsevier Ltd. This is an open access article under the CC BY-NC-ND license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/).</abstract><language>English</language></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Nogales, Borja</author><author>Sanchez-Aguero, Victor</author><author>Vidal, Ivan</author><author>Valera, Francisco</author><author>Garcia-Reinoso, Jaime</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A NFV system to support configurable and automated multi-UAV service deployments</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 4th ACM Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications</full-title></periodical><pages>39–44</pages><keywords><keyword>NFV, Virtualization, MANO, SUAV</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>2018</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-5839-2</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3213526.3213534</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;Less mission-related communication, but more focused on drone deployment.&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 4th ACM Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 4th ACM Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3213526.3213534</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>Munich, Germany</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 4th ACM Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Moradi, Mehrdad</author><author>Sundaresan, Karthikeyan</author><author>Chai, Eugene</author><author>Rangarajan, Sampath</author><author>Mao, Z. Morley</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>SkyCore: Moving Core to the Edge for Untethered and Reliable UAV-based LTE Networks</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 24th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking</full-title></periodical><pages>35–49</pages><keywords><keyword>mobility management, edge epc, lte, uav, sdn, drone, epc, 5g, uav-based lte networks, resource-challenged</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>2018</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-5903-0</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3241539.3241549</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 24th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 24th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3241539.3241549</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>New Delhi, India</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 24th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Madey, Alexander G.</author><author>Madey, Gregory R.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Design and evaluation of UAV swarm command and control strategies</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the Agent-Directed Simulation Symposium</full-title></periodical><pages>Article 7</pages><keywords><keyword>NetLogo, swarming, UAVs, command and control, emergent behavior</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year><pub-dates><date>2013</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Society for Computer Simulation International</publisher><isbn>978-1-62748-029-1</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.5555/2499592.2499599</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the Agent-Directed Simulation Symposium&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the Agent-Directed Simulation Symposium</research-notes><custom1>San Diego, California</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the Agent-Directed Simulation Symposium</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Petrolo, Riccardo</author><author>Lin, Yingyan</author><author>Knightly, Edward</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>ASTRO: Autonomous, Sensing, and Tetherless netwoRked drOnes</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 4th ACM Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications</full-title></periodical><pages>1–6</pages><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>2018</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-5839-2</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3213526.3213527</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 4th ACM Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 4th ACM Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3213526.3213527</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>Munich, Germany</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 4th ACM Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bagnato, Alessandra</author><author>Bíró, Regina Krisztina</author><author>Bonino, Dario</author><author>Pastrone, Claudio</author><author>Elmenreich, Wilfried</author><author>Reiners, René</author><author>Schranz, Melanie</author><author>Arnautovic, Edin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Designing Swarms of Cyber-Physical Systems: the H2020 CPSwarm Project: Invited Paper</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the Computing Frontiers Conference</full-title></periodical><pages>305–312</pages><keywords><keyword>evolutionary algorithms, CPS integration, development tools, cyber-physical systems, swarm computing, emergent behaviour, model based design, cyber-physical system of systems, deployment tools</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>2017</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-4487-6</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3075564.3077628</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;How design a CPS swarm, but not really how to design its communication (architecture).&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the Computing Frontiers Conference&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the Computing Frontiers Conference</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3075564.3077628</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>Siena, Italy</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the Computing Frontiers Conference</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ahmed, Ahmed Abdelmoamen</author><author>Olumide, Abel</author><author>Akinwa, Adeoluwa</author><author>Chouikha, Mohamed</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Constructing 3d maps for dynamic environments using autonomous UAVs</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 16th EAI International Conference on Mobile and Ubiquitous Systems: Computing, Networking and Services</full-title></periodical><pages>504–513</pages><keywords><keyword>autonomous, simulation, UAV, LIDAR, ROS, 3d maps, navigation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>2020</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-7283-1</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3360774.3368200</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;Only a single drone involved&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 16th EAI International Conference on Mobile and Ubiquitous Systems: Computing, Networking and Services&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 16th EAI International Conference on Mobile and Ubiquitous Systems: Computing, Networking and Services</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3360774.3368200</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>Houston, Texas, USA</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 16th EAI International Conference on Mobile and Ubiquitous Systems: Computing, Networking and Services</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bannis, Adeola</author><author>Noh, Hae Young</author><author>Zhang, Pei</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Bleep: motor-enabled audio side-channel for constrained UAVs</title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 26th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking</full-title></periodical><pages>Article 26</pages><keywords><keyword>side-channel, motor sound, UAV</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>2020</date></pub-dates></dates><publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher><isbn>978-1-4503-7085-1</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3372224.3419183</electronic-resource-num><research-notes>&#xD;&#xD;Not really a communication architecture, but moreover a communication mechanism&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 26th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking&#xD;&#xD;The following values have no corresponding Zotero field:&#xD;periodical: Proceedings of the 26th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1145/3372224.3419183</url></web-urls></urls><custom1>London, United Kingdom</custom1><custom3>Proceedings of the 26th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking</custom3></record></records></xml>